<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Search Engine Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/search-engine-marketing-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 07:39:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Search Engine Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How Google Ads Can Boost Your SEO Results (Really!)</title>
		<link>/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google has said over and over again that SEO is not a paid activity. This means that advertising with Google Ads will not have an impact on your organic search rankings. This article does not dispute the above. We definitely believe that using Google Ads alone is not enough for your site to see a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/">How Google Ads Can Boost Your SEO Results (Really!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u><a href="https://moz.com/blog/how-google-adwords-ppc-affects-organic-results">Google has said over and over again that SEO is not a paid activity</a></u>. This means that advertising with Google Ads will not have an impact on your organic search rankings.</p>
<p>This article does not dispute the above. We definitely believe that using Google Ads alone is not enough for your site to see a boost in its results on the SERPs. However, there are definitely ways that using Google Ads can help improve your SEO strategy. Google Ads and SEO have a similar premise behind them; the benefit of using Google Ads over SEO is that it generates data immediately. Google Ads can provide a wealth of useful audience and keyword-specific data that can be used to inform an SEO campaign before wasting a lot of time and money figuring out what works with slower SEO results.</p>
<p>For example, you may choose keywords for SEO that you think are relevant and spend significant amounts of time and money to rank for them, only to discover months down the line that the traffic those particular keywords brings in does not convert. If you had run a Google Ads campaign previously, you would have already identified that this keyword was not effective.</p>
<p>The following are some of the other ways that you can apply Google Ads to help with your SEO strategy.</p>
<h2> 1. Look at the Search Terms Report</h2>
<p>The Search Terms report from Google Ads provides advertisers with a list of the phrases that people are actually typing into Google before clicking on the ads. It shows the exact phrases that are triggering your ads, which is vital information for your business to know. You can use this report to identify words or phrases that get a lot of impressions and clicks, and most importantly, the ones that lead to conversions. This information can give you a great insight into the keywords that searchers are using to find your business. For SEO, look for the phrases that have intent behind them and the ones that convert to incorporate into your strategy, rather than simply casting a wide net with high-volume keywords.</p>
<h2> 2. Analyse Your Click-Through Rates (CTRs)</h2>
<p>An ad with a high Click Through Rate (CTR) will typically be well written, or contain something compelling that drives a searcher to respond. If you can replicate the formula that gets the best CTR for your ads, you are likely to increase the CTR on your organic results too, which means more traffic for your site without having to increase your position on the SERPs.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>Look at your Google Ads account to see if you can identify anything in your ads that seems to be connecting with the audience and leading to a higher click through rate, such as a specific headline or call to action.</p>
<p>Each part of your ad can corresponds to a different part of your on-page SEO as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Google Ads Headlines = Title Tags</li>
<li>Google Ads Ad Descriptions = Meta Descriptions</li>
<li>Google Ads Display URL = Landing Page URL</li>
</ul>
<p>This knowledge can be used to create SEO meta data that turns searchers into relevant traffic. Just be careful not to optimise Click Through Rate in a way that generates irrelevant traffic, as this will affect bounce rate and dwell time, which may negatively impact your SEO efforts.</p>
<h2> 3. Identify Geographic Locations that Work</h2>
<p>Your Google Ads campaign can provide data on geographic locations that can be useful for creating Local SEO campaigns. Even if your business doesn’t have a physical location to visit, location data from Google Ads can enhance the performance of your campaign in different geographical areas.</p>
<p>In order to use your Google Ads location data, find the areas you are interested in, then, identify which are performing well. For example, look at the ads that have the most conversions, highest sales by revenue, the most clicks or the best Click Through Rates. This information can then be used for location-specific SEO campaigns to improve on-page SEO and refine targeted keywords.</p>
<h2> 4. Compliment SEO With Remarketing</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.dynamicyield.com/glossary/remarketing/">Remarketing (also known as retargeting) is the tactic of serving targeted ads to people who have already visited or taken action on your website</a>. Considering<strong> </strong><u>96-98%</u> of the visitors to your website won’t make a purchase the first time that they are there, this is an incredibly effective way of keeping your brand fresh in their mind and convincing them to come back to your site. When they come back as returning visitors, they are more likely to convert, as they are already aware of your business and its products and services.</p>
<p>Remarketing can help improve your SEO results by giving your business an easy and cost-effective way to get in front of prospects several times, which allows you to get the most value that you can from the visitors that you generate to your site organically.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a specialist <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing agency</a>. Get in touch with us for more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">Google Ads advertising</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO</a>, or your wider digital marketing strategy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/">How Google Ads Can Boost Your SEO Results (Really!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Your Google Ads Aren’t Meeting Performance Goals</title>
		<link>/why-your-google-ads-arent-meeting-performance-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 02:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You’ve set up your Google Ads, but for some reason, they’re not achieving the results you hoped for. So, what went wrong? Get the most out of your advertising investment and reach your performance objectives by avoiding these common mistakes. Your Ads Aren’t Showing in Relevant Contexts Are your advertisements receiving a high number of [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-your-google-ads-arent-meeting-performance-goals/">Why Your Google Ads Aren’t Meeting Performance Goals</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’ve set up your Google Ads, but for some reason, they’re not achieving the results you hoped for. So, what went wrong?</p>
<p>Get the most out of your advertising investment and reach your performance objectives by avoiding these common mistakes.</p>
<h2>Your Ads Aren’t Showing in Relevant Contexts</h2>
<p>Are your advertisements receiving a high number of impressions, but still have a relatively low Click-Through-Rate (CTR)? In such circumstances, your ads are likely being shown in contexts that are not actually relevant to your product or service.</p>
<p>Take, for instance, a brand that specialises in truck wheels. If the reach of their campaign hasn’t been accurately defined, it’s possible that a number of the ad impressions they’re getting are actually from people with no interest in their offering. Audiences who are searching for everything from go-kart wheels to bike wheels could be viewing your ads, so it’s crucial that you create highly targeted ad groups. It’s no surprise that, even if you’re getting lots of impressions, an irrelevant ad isn’t going to generate clicks.</p>
<p><em>So, how can you ensure that your ads are reaching the right people?</em></p>
<p>Start by looking at the advertisements themselves, ensuring that all of their content is appropriate, engaging and easy to comprehend. By completing thorough keyword research for each ad group, you’ll be able to include well-ranking terms and phrases that are specific to your offering. For instance, the brand mentioned in the above example could benefit from using the keyword ‘truck wheel’ as opposed to ‘wheel’ which is relatively broad. You can also refine your search appearance by specifying which keywords you would like to focus on and defining negative keywords (terms you want to avoid).</p>
<h2>Your Landing Page is Poorly Designed</h2>
<p>If your current Google Ads have a high Click-Through-Rate but a low number of conversions, it’s unlikely that the ads themselves are flawed as people are actively engaging with them. Instead, this often occurs when the content of the landing page doesn’t match that of the ad so, when people click to find out more, they are met with information they weren’t expecting.</p>
<p>Even if you’ve created a wonderful advertisement, individuals who are met with a confusing, overwhelming or complicated landing page will likely be deterred from pursuing your business any further. For this reason, it’s important to consider ways you could improve the overall readability of your landing pages. When designing your layout, keep it simple. Focus on enhancing usability and making converting easy. By including your contact details and an enquiry form on the page itself, you can keep the entire process as clear and straightforward as possible.</p>
<p>It’s also important to analyse where most of your clicks are coming from in terms of devices such as mobile, desktop and tablet. If your ads are achieving a high CTR but very few people are actually converting, it’s possible that most of these clicks are coming from mobile users and that your landing page isn’t optimised for small screens. It’s estimated that, worldwide, more than <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/330695/number-of-smartphone-users-worldwide/">2.7 billion</a> people own a smartphone. By ensuring that your online domains are <a href="/optimise-your-website-for-mobile-devices/">mobile compatible</a>, you can tap into this market and make the most out of any clicks your Google ads receive.</p>
<h2>Get Your Ad Headline &amp; Description Right</h2>
<p>Recently, Google released an update increasing the length restrictions of their Expanded Text Ads. Before its introduction, your advertisements could only include two headlines and one description of up to 80 characters. However, with the new and improved Expanded Text Ads, you can use up to three headlines and two descriptions that are 90 characters each.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-7051" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.36.56-am-450x76.png" alt="" width="750" height="127" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.36.56-am-450x76.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.36.56-am-768x131.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.36.56-am-1024x174.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.36.56-am.png 1412w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p>If you’re yet to update your advertisements, now is the time.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Using custom title tags and meta descriptions doesn’t require a high level of expertise, but it contributes to a higher click-through rate from search results” – </em><em><a href="https://databox.com/seo-tips-and-fundamentals">Rhianna Taniguchi</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>By changing your copy to include three headlines and two descriptions, you can improve your ads search ranking and Click-Through-Rate. In fact, Google found that those who were responsive to their larger ad update received <a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2018/08/22/new-expanded-text-ads">20% more clicks</a> than those using older formats.</p>
<p>It is, however, important to ensure your new ads are performing well before pausing those you created prior to the update. Rather than immediately making the transition, you may find it beneficial to compare the results of each ad group and continue to make adjustments until you’re confident.</p>
<h2>Prospects Are Seeing Your Ads Outside Business Hours</h2>
<p>If your advertisements are being displayed at all hours of the day, it may be worth restricting their appearance exclusively to when you have people to manage enquiries.</p>
<p>Depending on your business context and organisational goals, conversions may be highly reliant on prospects actually calling you to speak with a professional. If this is the case and they’re seeing your ad outside of business hours, you could be missing out on a number of potential leads that simply fail to get in contact. Once they’ve unsuccessfully tried to get in touch with you there is, of course, the very apparent risk that they’ll seek out assistance from one of your competitors.</p>
<p>Luckily, Google Ads gives you the option to only run your campaigns when you would like to. This means you can ensure that they’re being viewed by your target audience at relevant times, so there is always someone there to take their call.</p>
<h2>You&#8217;re Not Making Use of Extensions</h2>
<p>Ad Extensions expand your advertisement, providing users with additional information. By using extensions, you can ensure that all of your ads include crucial information about your offering and brand. The best part? There are a variety of Ad Extension options readily available to you, cost-free.</p>
<p><em>So, which ad extension is right for your business?</em></p>
<h4>1. Callout Extensions</h4>
<p>When you enable callout extensions, descriptive text is pulled into the bottom of your advertisements. Typically, Callout Extensions describe the attributes of your product, service or business.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-7050" style="color: #333333; font-size: 14.4px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.37.37-am-450x67.png" alt="" width="750" height="112" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.37.37-am-450x67.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.37.37-am-768x115.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.37.37-am-1024x154.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.37.37-am.png 1494w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<h4>2. Sitelink Extensions</h4>
<p>Sitelink Extensions highlight specific pages of your website that you believe potential consumers will be particularly interested in. By using sitelink extensions, you’re able to make highly relevant pages easily accessible to prospects. You can also measure the Click-Through-Rate for each link, collecting valuable data about consumer preferences.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-7048" style="color: #333333; font-size: 14.4px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.49-am-450x159.png" alt="" width="750" height="265" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.49-am-450x159.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.49-am-768x272.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.49-am-1024x362.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.49-am.png 1510w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<h4>3. Review Extensions</h4>
<p>Review Extensions are an excellent way for your business to evidence previous success, which can lower customer uncertainty. These extensions are automated by Google Ads and, to be shown, require that your ratings meet certain conditions. For instance, there must be at least 100 unique, relevant reviews from users in your country. You also need to achieve an average rating of 3.5 stars or higher.</p>
<p>Since including reviews in their paid advertisements, organisations have reported achieving a <a href="https://www.hallaminternet.com/5-ways-google-ad-extensions-can-improve-your-adwords-campaign/">19% increase</a> in their Click-Through-Rate.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-7049" style="color: #333333; font-size: 14.4px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.11-am-450x90.png" alt="" width="750" height="150" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.11-am-450x90.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.11-am-768x153.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.11-am-1024x204.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.38.11-am.png 1494w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<h4>4. Call Extensions</h4>
<p>By ensuring prospects have direct, convenient access to your contact information, your business can lower potential customers’ search costs. For organisations that rely on phone calls to generate conversions, these extensions can be a particularly useful tool.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-7047" style="font-size: 14.4px;" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.39.13-am-450x55.png" alt="" width="750" height="92" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.39.13-am-450x55.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.39.13-am-768x94.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.39.13-am-1024x125.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Screen-Shot-2019-07-12-at-11.39.13-am.png 1408w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<h2>Speak With an Expert</h2>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we have extensive experience helping businesses like yours create exceptional <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> campaigns. For more information, or if you’d like professional assistance improving your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">Google Ads</a> strategy, get in touch with our team today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-your-google-ads-arent-meeting-performance-goals/">Why Your Google Ads Aren’t Meeting Performance Goals</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keyword Research: How To</title>
		<link>/keyword-research-how-to/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is a Keyword? Keywords are phrases or ideas that relate to your business’ products or services. They will be used organically throughout your content to give users, and search engines a short cut in terms of what your webpage is about. Keywords are essential for Search Engine Optimisation. In terms of SEO, keywords are [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/keyword-research-how-to/">Keyword Research: How To</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>What is a Keyword?</strong></h2>
<p>Keywords are phrases or ideas that relate to your business’ products or services. They will be used organically throughout your content to give users, and search engines a short cut in terms of what your webpage is about.</p>
<p>Keywords are essential for <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">Search Engine Optimisation</a>. In terms of <a href="/what-is-seo/">SEO</a>, keywords are the words that searchers enter into search engines in order to find answers to their queries. In order to be found for the keywords that are most relevant to your business and customers, your keywords should be used across your website in page content, images, videos and blogs etc. If you break down everything on your website into simple words and phrases, then these words become your primary keywords.</p>
<h2><strong>Why are Keywords Important?</strong></h2>
<p>Keywords are important because they’re the crucial factor that connects what people are searching for with the content that you’re providing to fill that need. With SEO, your ultimate goal is to rank well on search engines so that you’re able to drive organic traffic to your site from the search engine result pages (SERPS). The keywords that you’ve decided to target will determine what kinds of traffic you’ll get.</p>
<p>Keywords are as much about your audience as they are about your content. To create content that ranks well organically and drives visitors to your site, you need to understand what your visitors could be searching for. You should also consider using a similar type of language to the language that your visitors use to ensure yours is the content that they are most engaged with. In order to identify the keywords that resonate with your target audience this, you could talk to your customers directly or by creating forums and community groups, as well conducting some of your own keyword research with a tool like <a href="https://moz.com/explorer">Keyword Explorer</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>How do I Find Long Tail Keywords? </strong></h2>
<p>There are a few keyword research tools that you can use to find new keywords, build on your current ones and look at the competition levels for each keyword. It’s quick and easy to find long tail keywords with SEM Rush’s free keyword research tool. All you have to do is type in the word that you want to research, and the tool will provide you with possible long tail keywords that you may want to use.</p>
<p>SEM Rush has a great <a href="https://www.semrush.com/analytics/seomagic/lists">Keyword Magic Tool</a>, which enables you to search for a keyword from any country you want, and it will come up with a variety of new ideas to build on that keyword. See example below for the keyword of ‘Social Media’</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-6725" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Keyword-Magic-450x247.png" alt="Keyword Magic tool" width="609" height="334" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Keyword-Magic-450x247.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Keyword-Magic.png 700w" sizes="(max-width: 609px) 100vw, 609px" /></p>
<p>Another great tool to find long tail keywords is <a href="https://answerthepublic.com/">Answer the Public</a>. Similar to the SEM Rush tool, all you have to do is enter the word you want to research, and the program responds with possible long tail keywords that you may consider implementing in your strategy.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-6726" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Answer-the-Public-flight-centres-450x432.png" alt="Answer the Public Example" width="546" height="524" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Answer-the-Public-flight-centres-450x432.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Answer-the-Public-flight-centres.png 714w" sizes="(max-width: 546px) 100vw, 546px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Google Ads has another great keyword research tool, which has been designed for paid search campaigns, but it’s also applicable to keywords for SEO. To find the Keyword Planner, simply log into your Google Ads account and click the tools button on the top toolbar, you then navigate to the keyword planner from the drop down menu (which should look like the picture below).</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-6727" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-450x156.png" alt="Google Ads" width="479" height="166" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-450x156.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-768x266.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds.png 816w" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 479px" /></p>
<p>From the keyword planner click ‘discover new keywords’ and then you can type in current keywords that you want to build on or discover where they sit when compared to competitors.</p>
<h2><strong>What are the Key Benefits of Keyword Research? </strong></h2>
<h3>Did you know that?</h3>
<ul>
<li>75%of people never scroll past the first page of search engines.</li>
<li>72% of marketers believe that relevant content creation is the most <strong>effective SEO </strong>tactic</li>
<li>Almost 80% of users ignore paid ads in search results</li>
<li>93% of all online experiences begin with a search engine</li>
<li>50% of search queries are 4 words or longer</li>
<li>Organic SEO is 5.66 times better than paid ads</li>
<li>Websites with active blogs featuring on them, generate 67% more leads</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6728" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Google-search-pun-450x256.png" alt="Google Search Pun" width="450" height="256" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Google-search-pun-450x256.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Google-search-pun-768x436.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Google-search-pun.png 845w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Rankings</strong><br />
The use of keywords has a significant impact on organic page rank in search engines. By ranking well for specific topics, search engines will drive traffic to your site by prominently displaying your products and services, thereby enhancing your marketing effectiveness.</li>
<li><strong>Increased Conversions</strong><br />
If the content on your webpage is meaningful to those who view it, based on the keywords they are using to find it, this will lead to an increased conversion rate.</li>
<li><strong>Outdoing your Competitors</strong><br />
By doing keyword research you could possibly find new keywords to help you not only improve your search engine ranking but also help you to outdo your competitors. Finding words that have high monthly search results, which don’t have high competition will give you the opportunity to take advantage of the new keyword idea.</li>
</ol>
<h2><strong>Tips when Searching for Keywords</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Tip 1:</strong> When looking for new keywords, prioritise high– volume keywords that your competitors aren’t currently ranking for. Lower competition for paid search is typically a good indication that your competitors also won’t be using this term in their SEO strategy.</p>
<p>See example below from GoogleAds:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-6729" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-Keywords-450x356.png" alt="GoogleAds Keywords" width="506" height="400" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-Keywords-450x356.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-Keywords-768x607.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/GoogleAds-Keywords.png 892w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px" /></p>
<p><strong>Tip 2:</strong> Geo – targeting keyword – Think about what the searcher wants to find. Most searchers like things local, so having a location as part of your keyword could benefit you. For example if someone wanted to find a lawyer in Melbourne, add Melbourne at the end of your law firm company name as a keyword.</p>
<p><strong>Tip 3:</strong> Consider using long tail keywords. If you’ve decided to use long tail keywords then definitely incorporate them into blogs on your webpage. By doing this you’ll increase your search engine organic traffic.</p>
<p><strong>Tip 4:</strong> When you’re coming up with a list of potential keywords, think about what your customers are looking for when searching online for your products or services. You can do this by looking at the terms that are being searched. This information is available in GoogleAds.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">Content Marketing</a>, get in contact with the expert <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> at the Lead Agency today!</p>
<p>And don’t forget to check out our blog on the importance of <a href="/why-internal-linking-is-a-vital-part-of-any-seo-strategy/">Internal Linking</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/keyword-research-how-to/">Keyword Research: How To</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimising Your Paid Advertising Facebook Campaign as a B2B Business</title>
		<link>/optimise-your-b2b-paid-advertising-facebook-campaign/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 23:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As with any type of marketing campaign, if your business doesn’t develop a strong Facebook strategy, it’s likely that your long-term performance will suffer. It’s crucial that the monetary and time costs of implementing a Facebook campaign are achieving exceptional results for your business. If you’re not reaching your objectives, you need to ask yourself [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimise-your-b2b-paid-advertising-facebook-campaign/">Optimising Your Paid Advertising Facebook Campaign as a B2B Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As with any type of marketing campaign, if your business doesn’t develop a strong Facebook strategy, it’s likely that your long-term performance will suffer.</p>
<p>It’s crucial that the monetary and time costs of implementing a Facebook campaign are achieving exceptional results for your business. If you’re not reaching your objectives, you need to ask yourself why exactly this is the case and make any appropriate changes.</p>
<p>Facebook is a social networking platform and, as such, any marketing approaches your organisation implements will likely differ to those used in more conventional campaigns.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>As of March 31st 2019, Facebook has over 2.38 billion monthly users worldwide &#8211; </em><a href="https://zephoria.com/top-15-valuable-facebook-statistics/"><em>Zephoria</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>Facebook provides businesses with access to an extensive range of audiences, while also offering an abundance of in-depth targeting features. With Facebook advertisements, organisations can reach a vast array of potential customers who have been accurately and precisely defined. This means that you have the opportunity to execute highly targeted, valuable campaigns that truly optimise your investment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The Difficulty With Facebook in B2B Markets</h2>
<p>In B2B contexts, Facebook advertising can often prove to be particularly challenging. When integrating Facebook advertising into their current marketing efforts, B2B businesses may experience difficulty successfully targeting their audience. This is because Facebook is a social platform and, typically, those who use it recreationally are consumers.</p>
<p>It is, therefore, essential that when using Facebook advertising your B2B organisation is carefully and tactically planning your actions to boost the overall effectiveness of your campaign.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Facebook is the preferred place for 97% of marketers to conduct paid advertising – </em><em><a href="https://sproutsocial.com/insights/facebook-advertising-strategy/">Sprout Social</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>Even though organisations may encounter issues when marketing to their audience using Facebook, those who overcome these can achieve exceptional outcomes. At the end of the day B2B buyers are still consumers and, as such, Facebook advertisements are relevant.</p>
<p>Even if your promotions don’t drive immediate action, you will have the opportunity to increase brand recognition and establish mutually beneficial relationships that offer long-term value. By executing the following steps, your business can enhance the overall viability of your B2B Facebook marketing efforts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Define Your Target Audience</h2>
<p>When setting up Facebook advertisements, accurately defining your distinct target audience is crucial. By doing this, you can ensure that all of your funds are going towards engaging people who are likely to have a genuine interest in your business’ offering.</p>
<p>With Facebook, your organisation can refine exactly who you want to be seeing your advertisements by defining <a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2016/06/27/facebook-ad-targeting-options-infographic">certain parameters</a>. Generally, Facebook provides access to more extensive audience specification options than other channels. These categories include the unique behaviours, connections, interests and demographics of the individuals you intend to target.</p>
<p>Facebook can also be used to create Custom Audiences. If a member of your target market engages with your content, whether it’s on Facebook or another platform, they’ll become a part of your custom audience. Businesses can then remarket to individuals who’ve already interacted with their content, aiming to reignite previous interest.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Refine Your Ad Creatives</h2>
<blockquote><p><em>According to </em><a href="https://sproutsocial.com/insights/facebook-advertising-strategy/"><em>41% of consumers</em></a><em>, advertisements that they find entertaining are the most engaging.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>If your promotional efforts don’t spark interest, then it’s unlikely you’ll make a lasting impression that encourages action. Whether you engage potential consumers through humour, imagery or another means, your ad creatives need to offer some form of value.</p>
<p>Typically those using Facebook are doing so to make personal connections with others, as opposed to intentionally shopping for products or services. For B2B organisations this can cause difficulties, however, there are still plausible ways for businesses to endorse their brand while building meaningful relationships.</p>
<p>Entertaining advertisements are effective in overcoming this barrier, being seamlessly integrated into your target markets news feed and going beyond merely promoting your offering. In addition to this, innovative and interactive content can help your B2B business differentiate your brand from competition and engage your audience.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Monitor Your Campaign</h2>
<p>Once you’ve launched your campaign, it is essential to examine its ongoing performance and effectiveness. Facebook provides access to an array of metrics that can be used to analyse the different aspects of a business’ advertisements.</p>
<p>The analytics provided by Facebook can be tailored to meet your specific organisational objectives. For instance, your business could choose to analyse the commonalities between individuals who are highly engaged in your posts. This may include their age, gender or demographics and would allow for you to define your target audience more accurately in future promotional efforts.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Adopt an Integrated Approach</h2>
<p>It’s important to ensure that your organisation is doing more than paid advertisements on Facebook. Those wanting to maximise the long-term prosperity of a campaign need to frequently post relevant content of different varieties that truly engages their target audience.</p>
<p>Integrating video, shared posts, and original content is at the heart of growing and maintaining a strong following on Facebook. Those who do this are offering their target audience real value that engages, entertains and sparks ongoing interest.</p>
<p>Paid advertisements on Facebook can help to generate greater awareness of your brand and boost conversions, but organic activity is just as essential in a strong Facebook marketing strategy. By organically targeting their audience, organisations can build meaningful relationships with customers, fostering communities and brand advocacy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Want to Find Out More?</h2>
<p>If you’re interested in taking your business’ <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">B2B Social Media Marketing Strategy</a> to the next level, speak with an expert. At the Lead Agency, our team has more than 20 years of experience in <a href="/">B2B marketing</a> and can provide you with the professional guidance required to achieve your organisational objectives.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimise-your-b2b-paid-advertising-facebook-campaign/">Optimising Your Paid Advertising Facebook Campaign as a B2B Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Steps to Success with Your B2B Paid Search Campaigns</title>
		<link>/steps-to-success-with-your-b2b-paid-search-campaigns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 01:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Paid search advertising isn’t used as often in B2B marketing as it is in B2C. Running a successful B2B paid search advertising campaign in niche B2B target markets can be extremely difficult. This is primarily because B2B target markets are smaller, so defining profitable keywords can be challenging. In addition, even once you have found [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/steps-to-success-with-your-b2b-paid-search-campaigns/">Steps to Success with Your B2B Paid Search Campaigns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Paid search advertising isn’t used as often in B2B marketing as it is in B2C.</p>
<p>Running a successful B2B paid search advertising campaign in niche B2B target markets can be extremely difficult. This is primarily because B2B target markets are smaller, so defining profitable keywords can be challenging. In addition, even once you have found suitable keywords, <a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/269613">turning them into conversions and sales isn’t always easy</a>. However, when done right, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">B2B paid search campaigns</a> can be instrumental in growing your B2B business through generating leads and ultimately, sales.</p>
<p>The key to a successful B2B search campaign lies in fully understanding <a href="https://www.thebalancesmb.com/b2b-vs-b2c-marketing-2295828">the differences between B2B marketing and B2C marketing</a>. B2B and B2C marketing differ in a number of ways; from the length of the sales cycle, to the buyer journey and decision-making processes.</p>
<p>When it comes to paid online campaigns, ROI is a huge consideration and it’s important to remember the discrepancy in conversion value between B2B and B2C. Typically, the value of a customer is much higher for B2B businesses. The average e-commerce transaction is worth $85 to $120, so even when you factor in the potential for repeat business, B2C businesses might make $250 per customer. For B2B companies, however, <a href="https://blog.chartmogul.com/actionable-saas-metrics-customer-lifetime-value/">the lifetime value of a customer is often between $20,000 and $200,000</a>. This means that while cost per click and as such, cost per conversion may seem very high for B2B businesses, the potential for a good ROI on the channel is huge.</p>
<p>The main thing to bear in mind when it comes to generating leads through B2B paid campaigns, is that clicks are likely to cost more. This doesn’t necessarily mean that the channel isn’t profitable. Another important consideration for B2B paid search campaigns, is that you’re likely to see less direct conversions as B2B products and services typically are not bought and sold online, so you can’t see direct purchases or e-commerce sales.</p>
<p>There are certain things however, that you can do to ensure your B2B paid campaigns are as effective as possible in generating ROI for your business. The following are some of our most effective tips and tricks for <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">B2B AdWords</a> and other B2B paid search campaigns.</p>
<h2>Tips for Paid Search Success From B2B Experts</h2>
<h3>Implement Comprehensive Tracking &amp; Attribution</h3>
<p>As the B2B buying cycle is longer and involves multiple touch points (<a href="https://www.rainsalestraining.com/blog/how-many-touches-does-it-take-to-make-a-sale">8 on average before making a sale</a>), customers are likely to be interacting with your brand through a variety of channels and campaigns before finally converting.</p>
<p>Tracking and attributing your leads, clients, and sales back to specific campaigns and keywords is one of the most important parts of your B2B paid search marketing strategy. Effectively tracking your digital lead generation campaign involves collecting data from multiple sources and pulling it together to get a clear picture of the performance of each of your campaigns and how they work together.</p>
<p>There is a range of <a href="https://agencyanalytics.com/blog/marketing-attribution-models">different attribution models</a> that you can apply to track the success of your paid search campaigns. Some of the most common are below:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Last Click Attribution:</strong> Last Click Attribution gives 100% of the credit to the channel that brought the last interaction with the lead before they converted.</li>
<li><strong>First Click Attribution:</strong> Similar to Last Interaction, however, 100% of the credit is given to the channel that brought the customer to the website for the first time.</li>
<li><strong>Last Non- Direct Click:</strong> In many cases, customers will research and find a brand on a certain channel, then come back to the website by typing the URL directly into the search bar. The Last Non-Direct Click model helps to eradicate these visits by eliminating any &#8220;direct&#8221; interactions that occur right before the conversion. Instead, 100% of the credit is given to the channel before the direct interaction.</li>
<li><strong>Linear Attribution:</strong> With a Linear attribution model, credit for a conversion is split equally between all the interactions that a customer had with your business.</li>
<li><strong>Time Decay:</strong> Similar to Linear attribution, Time Decay attribution spreads the credit across multiple channels. However, with time decay, channels that were used closest to the conversion get more credit.</li>
<li><strong>U-Shaped Attribution:</strong> This type of attribution assigns more credit to the first and last touch-points, splitting the rest of the credit equally between any other channels.</li>
</ul>
<p>By measuring the success of your paid search campaigns using the Attribution Model that makes more sense for your business’ unique buyer journey, you get more insight into how effective the channel is for your business.</p>
<p>In addition, if your business uses a CRM, you can categorise the leads generated from your paid search campaigns, and report on their lead status, for example, ‘closed, lost, ongoing’ etc, as well as assign any associated revenue to these leads. This can also give you a more in-depth analysis of the profitability of your campaign.</p>
<h3>Don’t Forget About Bing Ads</h3>
<p>It’s no secret that Google dominates the search marketing landscape. As such, most B2B marketers tend to put most of their budget into Google, overlooking other options like Bing. Despite Google being the prominent search engine, the power of Bing should not be underestimated. According to the latest data, Bing has a <a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/bing-grabs-33-market-share-in-the-us-according-to-data-presented-by-microsoft">33% market share</a> in the US and a significant market share in other countries across the globe, powering <a href="https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/insights/planning-tools/bing-network-audience">six billion</a> unique searches per month from 145 million active users. This gives marketers huge potential to reach their target audience. <a href="/using-bing-as-an-alternative-sem-tool/">Bing is particularly effective for B2B marketers</a> as most businesses use Microsoft OS on their hardware, with Bing set as the default search engine.</p>
<p>While Bing is unlikely to give you the same number of impressions, clicks and conversions as Google, <a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/24893/6-Reasons-Marketers-Should-Use-Bing-for-Paid-Search.aspx">bids on Bing tend to be lower, and the competition for keywords is lower</a>. This means that cost per conversion is typically a lot lower on Bing.</p>
<p>Bing even makes it really easy to get set up, as you can basically copy and paste your current Google campaigns using its import feature. That being said, it can be equally valuable to build a campaign strategy specifically for Bing, taking into consideration things specific to the search engine such as search volumes, user intent, and demographics. Depending on the products and services that you’re promoting, the <a href="https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-au/insights/planning-tools/bing-network-audience">audience on Bing</a> may work well for your business.  According to the search engine, 40% of its network is 35-54 years old, whereas Google’s search audience is much younger. In addition, over one-third of Bing’s audience has a household income of over $100,000. For marketers who are promoting products and services to these specific target segments, advertising on Bing could have significant impact.</p>
<h3>Audience Targeting</h3>
<p>“I’m not going to talk about the death of keywords this year. In my opinion, they’re already dead, in a sense, as a primary targeting method. If you’re thinking about them first, you’re already behind.” <a href="https://searchengineland.com/author/aaron-levy">Aaron Levy</a> &#8211; Paid search expert.</p>
<p>In 2018, there was a significant shift in targeting from keywords to an<a href="https://www.thedrum.com/opinion/2018/02/23/audience-first-the-future-paid-performance"> “audience first” mentality</a>, as paid search platforms improved their audience targeting and segmenting abilities for advertisers. Google and Bing are both pushing advertisers to use audience targeting and the options that they now provide can be beneficial to B2B marketers.</p>
<p>While keyword targeting is undoubtedly effective, the problem with targeting in this way is that the keywords you choose may not exactly match the search <strong>intent </strong>you’re looking for. Accurately gauging the intent behind a keyword can be difficult, for example, an insurance company targeting dental practices may use keywords like ‘insurance for dentists’ and ‘dentists insurance’. However, many patients who are looking for insurance that covers dental work may also use these search terms, which is where the confusion comes in and the ads may not match the search intent.</p>
<p>Paid search advertising is intent-based, in that you’re targeting people who are actively looking for a solution to their problems. But, with keyword targeting, you’re not targeting the potential customers, but rather the keywords. If the keywords you’ve chosen don’t reliably match the search intent you’re trying to target, you end up wasting a lot of money on the wrong clicks. This is where <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/paid-audiences-replace-keywords/">audience targeting</a> comes in.</p>
<p>Audience targeting is all about targeting people and it’s the most commonly used type of targeting on social media platforms like <a href="https://www.disruptiveadvertising.com/social-media/facebook-marketing/">Facebook Ads</a>. With audience targeting, you’re not using the keywords that you think your audience is interested in, instead, you’re targeting people who actually match your customer base. Audiences can be created based on factors that match your <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/buyer-persona-definition-under-100-sr">buyer persona</a>s such as age, interests, income, behaviours and a variety of other factors. However, audience targeting alone may not be particularly effective for paid search campaigns.</p>
<p>Combining keywords with audiences is the best way to make sure your ads reach the right people. Search Engines like Google and Bing don’t have the same insight into their audience’s personal lives as social media channels like Facebook do. However, using the audience targeting options that are available is an excellent way to improve the targeting of your paid search ads.</p>
<p>You can also modify your bids based on the audience, which is a great way to analyse the performance of your campaign. Setting up targeting in this way allows you to qualify users before they get to your site by seeing which audiences are converting and which aren’t. You can then use this information to target only the traffic that works for your business, which will reduce your <a href="https://searchenginewatch.com/2019/02/18/google-ads-2019-what-to-look-out-for/">Cost Per Acquisition</a> and improve the quality of the leads that are generated. Going a step further, you can even create specific audience-focused campaigns to give you more control over your bidding and CPA performance.</p>
<p>If you need help with your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">B2B AdWords</a> campaign or other paid search campaigns, get in touch with the <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> at the Lead Agency. We’re a Google certified <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">AdWords Agency</a> and as such, can help boost your results on the channel.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/steps-to-success-with-your-b2b-paid-search-campaigns/">Steps to Success with Your B2B Paid Search Campaigns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using Bing as an Alternative SEM Tool</title>
		<link>/using-bing-as-an-alternative-sem-tool/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 23:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If until now, you’ve been neglecting Bing as a channel in your search marketing strategy, you’re not alone. In 2018, Google&#8217;s ad revenue amounted to almost $US116.3 billion, while Bing’s ad revenue came in at $US3.2 billion. The reason most marketers opt for Google rather than Bing is that more people are on the channel, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/using-bing-as-an-alternative-sem-tool/">Using Bing as an Alternative SEM Tool</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If until now, you’ve been neglecting Bing as a channel in your search marketing strategy, you’re not alone</span><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/266249/advertising-revenue-of-google/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2018, Google&#8217;s ad revenue amounted to almost $US116.3 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, while </span><a href="https://www.ventureharbour.com/visualising-size-google-bing-yahoo/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bing’s ad revenue came in at $US3.2 billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reason most marketers opt for Google rather than Bing is that more people are on the channel, so they think that their ads are being served to a wider target audience.  This is an accurate assumption, as the latest </span><a href="https://netmarketshare.com/search-engine-market-share.aspx"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netmarketshare</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> report found that 73% of global searches are powered by Google and only 7.91% by Bing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While there’s no disputing that Google is the dominant search engine, there are definite advantages for digital marketers using Bing alongside, if not instead of, the search engine giant.</span></p>
<h2><b>Why Use Bing Advertising in Your Digital Campaign?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lot of advertisers overlook Bing as it just doesn’t have the scale of Google; however global statistics are slightly skewed. According to the latest data, Bing has a </span><a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/bing-grabs-33-market-share-in-the-us-according-to-data-presented-by-microsoft"><span style="font-weight: 400;">33% market share</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the United States and a significant market share in other countries worldwide. The search engine powers </span><a href="https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/insights/planning-tools/bing-network-audience"><span style="font-weight: 400;">six billion</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> unique searches per month, by its 145 million active users. This gives marketers huge potential to reach their target audience.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The real beauty of Bing Ads, however, is that it is so underused.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;"> This makes the channel particularly effective for advertisers in competitive fields.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Millions of advertisers use Google to promote their products and services, which has made its advertising platform overcrowded and saturated. </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">On Bing, you have much fewer competitors to bid against. With fewer people in the auction, the cost per click on Bing is much cheaper than Google. </span><b> </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">As clicks are cheaper, this means you don&#8217;t need to spend as much to attract new customers and get a better ROI on the channel. </span></p>
<h2><b>Who Can you Reach on Bing?</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-au/insights/planning-tools/bing-network-audience"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bing has released demographic information</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on its 145 million active users.  Depending on the products and services that you’re promoting, the demographics on the channel may work well for your business.  According to the search engine, 40% of their network is 35-54 years old and half of the users are married or living with a domestic partner. Google’s search audience is much younger. In addition, over one-third of Bing’s audience has a household income of over $100,000. For marketers who are promoting products and services to these specific target segments, advertising on Bing could generate leads and sales. However, if the overall marketing goal is to bring in high-volume traffic and raise brand awareness, Google is more likely the go-to.</span></p>
<h2><b>The Future of Bing Advertising</b></h2>
<p><a href="https://news.microsoft.com/2018/07/19/microsoft-cloud-drives-record-fourth-quarter-results-2/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Microsoft reported record results in the fourth quarter of FY17-18</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  This has been largely due to the growth of the company’s cloud services. However, while Bing accounts for a small share of Microsoft’s revenue, the search platform should not be overlooked as it is steadily growing and has seen a 17% increase year on year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As more people are using Bing, search revenue is growing. While it may never reach the heights of Google with its dominant market share, Bing search is a vital digital platform to offer businesses an alternative to Google to grow their visibility.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bing knows it has a strong position in the search engine world and has been working to improve its product offerings for businesses and consumers. At a basic level, Bing has advanced its search results to expand on top-level search queries. For example, if you search for ‘Movies’ on your smartphone, both Bing and Google will show what movies are playing in cinemas close to your location.  But Bing results will also display tabs for movies that are currently available on Netflix and Amazon to give a deeper search result and show wider offerings to searchers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bing has also enhanced its search results with the introduction of its </span><a href="https://blogs.bing.com/search-quality-insights/2018-02/bing-entity-search-api-now-generally-available"><span style="font-weight: 400;">search entity API</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. With Bing Entity Search, the API sends a search query to Bing and produces results that include entities and places such as restaurants, hotels, or other local businesses. Bing returns </span><b>places</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> if the query specifies the name of the local business or asks for a type of business (for example, restaurants near me). It returns </span><b>entities</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> if the query is about well-known people, locations or things.  This provides a richer contextual search result about people, places, things, and local businesses.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition, Bing has continuously worked on its ability to provide a more visually appealing search.  Bing has always been recognised for its superior design on its home page and search results pages. Taking video as an example, Bing offers results in easy to navigate, visually appealing thumbnail panels, while Google’s video results are more utilitarian.  Building on its reputation for visuals, Bing </span><a href="https://searchengineland.com/bing-announces-ai-powered-new-intelligent-search-features-288363"><span style="font-weight: 400;">announced the launch of visual search</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which lets people use images to easily navigate the search engine and find content. With this feature, using the Bing app you can take a photo on your smartphone or upload one and use it to perform visual searches. This visual search feature from Bing was assumed to be an answer to Google Lens; however, it offered capabilities for users on both Android and iOS while Google’s visual search capability was limited.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re thinking of using Bing in your strategy, the first step is to familiarise yourself with the platform. Try using the search engine on your desktop and download the app.  When you can see results as your customers would, you’re in a better position to start marketing to them</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For help with your </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Search Engine Marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> campaign, get in touch with the experts at the Lead Agency. And don&#8217;t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/using-bing-as-an-alternative-sem-tool/">Using Bing as an Alternative SEM Tool</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Are Not On The First Page Of Google</title>
		<link>/why-you-are-not-on-the-first-page-of-google/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 05:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today’s businesses won’t survive for long without a website. Your website is your brand’s presence online and should demonstrate how your business can add value to potential customers. However, getting online by creating your website is the easy part, ensuring people see it is where it becomes more difficult. 75% of people will never scroll past [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-you-are-not-on-the-first-page-of-google/">Why You Are Not On The First Page Of Google</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today’s businesses won’t survive for long without a website. Your website is your brand’s presence online and should demonstrate how your business can add value to potential customers. However, getting online by creating your website is the easy part, ensuring people see it is where it becomes more difficult.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/14416/100-Awesome-Marketing-Stats-Charts-Graphs-Data.aspx?__hstc=240018588.27d886af2a2d305aee606c363c78756d.1550899186112.1552385527993.1552898841081.6&amp;__hssc=240018588.2.1552898841081&amp;__hsfp=4085446803">75% of people will never scroll past the first page</a> on a Google search.</p>
<p>While you’ve probably heard of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO</a> and how it can help boost your ranking on the Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs), you don’t have to invest in an expensive campaign to get here.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internetlivestats.com/one-second/#google-band">Google receives over 63,000 searches per second on any given day.</a> So you know how important it is for your website to be there when people are looking. The following are some of the reasons your business may not be appearing on the first page of Google and some of the steps you can take to combat this.</p>
<h2><strong>You Haven’t Set Up Google Accounts</strong></h2>
<p>If you haven’t set up a <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en_au/business/">Google My Business</a>, the search engine giant may not know you exist. This is quick, free, and simple to set up, so absolutely every business should have one. With a Google My Business account, you can list your hours, website, address and upload photos, so you are in control of how users see your business. Your Google My Business account works with Google Maps to show your business on page one of Google to local searches looking for your products or services.</p>
<p>It’s also a good idea to set up <a href="https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/home">Google Search Console</a>, which was previously known as Google Webmaster Tools. This is a dashboard that can give you insights about what people are searching to find you and how Google is crawling your pages. This can allow you to better optimise your website for search.</p>
<h2><strong>Your Site Isn’t Well Optimised for Search Engines</strong><strong> </strong></h2>
<p>Search Engine Optimisation can be complex, but there are things you can do to boost your rankings without having to hire an SEO specialist. One of the first things to consider is your website load time, as this is a major ranking factor for Google. If your website has loads of large pictures or videos, it is likely to be slower to load. You can check this on <a href="https://www.pingdom.com/">Pingdom</a>.</p>
<p>Another main factor to consider, is your website content, which should be optimised for both searchers and search engines. On-page ranking signals include the page content, meta descriptions and alt tags. Your keywords should be used across all of these to ensure your website ranks well on the SERPs.</p>
<h2><strong>Your Keywords are Too Competitive </strong></h2>
<p>Every business has competitors, and yours are likely to be online, targeting the same keywords that you are. This makes means you are effectively competing with others in your industry for your position on the SERPs.</p>
<p>You don’t need a complicated SEO strategy to work out how to fix this problem. <a href="https://ads.google.com/intl/en_au/home/">Google Ads</a> has a Keyword Planner tool that lets you research keywords that you want to rank for. It will then give you their monthly search volume, difficulty and level of competition, as well as suggesting other closely related searches that may be relevant for your business. The next step is to <a href="https://www.impulsecreative.com/blog/a-guide-to-proper-keyword-implementation">insert your chosen Keywords effectively in your website content</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>You’re Not Running Paid Ads</strong></h2>
<p>It can take a while to see results organically on the SERPs, so paid advertising can give your website a boost. Google gives its top three positions on its SERPs to paid advertisers, displaying ads that are related to their search query. This works by advertisers bidding on certain keywords in order for their clickable ads to appear in these paid ads spots.</p>
<p>Paid advertising is an option for most businesses as you can start with any budget. As you only pay when someone clicks your ad, you’re only spending on visitors that are interested in your products and services. Once your ads have been running for some time, you can start to work out what keywords, ad copy and landing pages are working, and optimise your campaigns for more conversions.</p>
<h2><strong>You Don’t Have Any Reviews</strong></h2>
<p>Reviews are significant <a href="https://moz.com/local-search-ranking-factors">ranking signal</a> for both local search and organic results as they impact how searchers see you online. Depending on your business, there are a number of ways you can get reviews. Consider signing up for a Yelp account, or get a Trip Advisor account if it is relevant to your business.</p>
<p>You should also encourage customers to leave a Google+ rating, which will appear beside your Google My Business listing, with a star rating for the business. These review can also be added as testimonials your website to provide social proof for your products and services.</p>
<p>The above are some simple steps you can take to improve your presence on Google. If you want to boost your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">digital marketing</a> more, the <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B marketing consultants</a> at the Lead Agency can help.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-you-are-not-on-the-first-page-of-google/">Why You Are Not On The First Page Of Google</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Optimise Your Paid Advertising Facebook Campaign</title>
		<link>/how-to-optimise-your-paid-advertising-facebook-campaign/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 03:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Despite a growing list of competitors in the social media space, Facebook’s user base on continues to increase every year. As do the marketing opportunities on the platform, as the company continues to update its capabilities and attract a wider audience. Digital Marketers know the power of the Social Media giant and spent $16.6 billion [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-paid-advertising-facebook-campaign/">How To Optimise Your Paid Advertising Facebook Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Despite a growing list of competitors in the social media space, Facebook’s user base on continues to increase every year. As do the marketing opportunities on the platform, as the company continues to update its capabilities and attract a wider audience. Digital Marketers know the power of the Social Media giant and <a href="https://martechtoday.com/despite-ongoing-criticism-facebook-generates-16-6-billion-in-ad-revenue-during-q4-up-30-yoy-230261">spent $16.6 billion on advertising</a> on the platform in the final quarter of 2018 alone.</p>
<p>There’s no denying that Facebook Ads work. You just need to find the right balance between messaging, creative and audience. This comes from regular in-depth analysis and optimisation of your campaign.</p>
<p>Here are some of the practical steps that you can take to optimise your Facebook ad campaign and maximise your results.</p>
<h2>Make the Most of ‘Social Proof’ In Your Ads</h2>
<blockquote><p>Social proof is a “psychological phenomenon where people assume the actions of others in an attempt to reflect correct behaviour for a given situation.” &#8211; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_proof">Wikipedia</a></p></blockquote>
<p>This basically means that we take cues from the opinions and actions of people around us<em>. </em>The likes and shares that appear under Facebook posts and ads are a form of social proof. Digital marketers can take advantage of this when creating a Facebook Ad campaign.</p>
<p>There are two options for creating ads for a Facebook campaign: create new ads, or use an existing post. By default, Facebook will select ‘Create New Ads’, however, using an existing post is an incredibly efficient (and easy) way of optimising your ads. By choosing a well-performing post as your ad, it will display with the existing likes and shares underneath it. This gives your ad an instant boost as people will see that others already like it and assume that whatever you are promoting must be good.</p>
<h2>Create a Custom Ad Schedule<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>While there’s no denying that there are users on Facebook 24/7, your ads shouldn’t be.</p>
<p>By default Facebook campaigns by will run every hour of the day and day of the week 24/7, creating an ad schedule can be an effective way to optimise your campaign. The ideal combination of times and days for your business to show its ads will depend on a number of factors, such as what you’re selling, who you’re targeting and what your campaign objectives are.</p>
<p>Take some time to analyse your Facebook ad accounts. Use the Breakdown menu to look at your campaigns by day, combining this with performance data by hour of the day to identify the best times to advertise. You can then use this information to create a custom ad schedule.</p>
<h2>Use Ad Rotation to Combat Ad Fatigue</h2>
<p>The more people see your ads, the less they interact with them. This means that you’ll start to see your cost-per-click increase significantly. This is known as <a href="https://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/recognize-overcome-facebook-ad-fatigue/">ad fatigue</a> – and it’s one way to kill your campaign.</p>
<p>The best way to ensure this doesn’t happen is to make several different variations of your ads, with different creative and messaging. You can then set up one campaign with multiple ad sets, each containing a different version of the creative. To use this technique to its full potential, try creating 5 ad sets and scheduling each to show on a different weekday. As such, people will see a different ad every day and they won’t get so repetitive.</p>
<h2>Choose Your Ad Placements Wisely</h2>
<p>Where you choose to place your ads has a significant impact on your Facebook advertising costs. According to <a href="https://adespresso.com/blog/facebook-ads-cost/">AdEspresso</a>, CPC on Facebook can vary up to 550%, depending on the ad placements that you choose.</p>
<p>Facebook Ads Manager reports can help you to identify the ad placements that are working for you. Once you work out the best performing ad placements, you can then optimise the campaigns by increasing bids on these placements. Similarly, if a placement isn’t working for your business, you can reduce the bids for that placement, or remove it altogether.</p>
<h3>One final hack …</h3>
<p>Exclude visitors who have already converted from your target audience.</p>
<p>This is an excellent way to expand the campaign reach to the most relevant audience, as it doesn’t make sense to keep delivering the same ads to someone who has already taken up your offer. By this point, these leads will have moved through to the next stage of the marketing funnel and should be targeted with new messaging and communications.</p>
<p>This is particularly relevant for a B2B lead capture campaign, for example, if you’re using Facebook ads to promote a lead magnet such as a free eBook. When someone gives you their email address and downloads the eBook, there’s no need to spend any more of your campaign budget showing this ad to the same person again. In order to do this, you can make the most of Facebook’s Custom Audience feature. This allows you to take converted prospects and exclude them from the campaign audience.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Optimising your Facebook campaign is a continuous process of testing, monitoring and making changes. At the Lead Agency, we’re experts in creating <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">social media marketing</a> campaigns that allow you to establish connections with stakeholders, position your brand and initiate social interactions that will improve your conversion rates. Get in touch today for more information.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-paid-advertising-facebook-campaign/">How To Optimise Your Paid Advertising Facebook Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Ways to Optimize your B2B Google Ads Campaign</title>
		<link>/5-ways-to-optimize-your-b2b-google-ads-campaign/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 03:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondered how Google reads just a few keywords typed to what you’re looking for and lays down exact results to your search? This is all due to a complex algorithm that first identifies what you’re searching for based on the words that you type, and then delivers the most relevant web content to fit [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-ways-to-optimize-your-b2b-google-ads-campaign/">5 Ways to Optimize your B2B Google Ads Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondered how Google reads just a few keywords typed to what you’re looking for and lays down exact results to your search? This is all due to a complex algorithm that first identifies what you’re searching for based on the words that you type, and then delivers the most relevant web content to fit your search.</p>
<p>In order to display on the first page of Search results, you can build a website that is optimised for Google’s algorithm, which can be complex, expensive and time consuming. Alternatively, you can give your website a boost to the top of the results page by setting up a paid Google Ads campaign.</p>
<p>The first two three results that are displayed on a Google Search Engine results Page are what we refer to as Google Ads, previously known as <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">AdWords</a>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5558 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-1-450x393.png" alt="Google Ads" width="450" height="393" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-1-450x393.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-1-768x670.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screen-Shot-1.png 863w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>Google Ads is an easy online advertising platform that inspires shoppers and helps marketers attract more customers, promoting products and services through visiting their websites, shopping through their stores or getting in touch with their business. It is an advertising system where advertisers bid for certain keywords pertaining to the product or service, so that their clickable ads appear in Google’s search results.</p>
<p>Google Ads are an excellent way to generate B2B leads and sales but can be brutal to manage at times for many B2B businesses in competitive marketplaces. With rising competition between brands, vast choices and reasonably low search volumes, it has been resulting in higher Cost Per Clicks (CPCs). One way to reduce the cost per click is to increase the ‘Quality score of the Ads’. Gradually leading into the following 5-optimisation tips that can be implemented by any company for their B2B Google Ads campaign.</p>
<h2>Choose Relevant Keywords</h2>
<p>Choosing relevant keywords is critical to the success of any Google Ads campaign as the goal is to turn clicks into conversions and sales. This can be a real challenge when it comes to targeting search terms.</p>
<ul>
<li>Terminology counts – Using B2B terminology, search term reports and keywords with intent is essential to attract the right traffic that connects or relates in the minds of the buyer.</li>
<li>Alternatively, making use of negative keywords is as important. Trimming on words or phrases that are similar to your product or service, but do not align with your brand whatsoever are the keywords you must update as negative keywords.</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5559" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screenshot-2-450x450.png" alt="Keywords" width="422" height="422" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screenshot-2-450x450.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screenshot-2-150x150.png 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Screenshot-2.png 655w" sizes="(max-width: 422px) 100vw, 422px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>By adding negative keywords, you’re ensuring your keywords are only attracting searches that a qualified lead would perform.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Create Dedicated Landing Pages</h2>
<p>Believe it or not, landing pages make all the difference. Landing pages affect the quality score of an ad. Quality score is basically an estimate of the quality of the ad, keywords used and landing pages linked. Higher the quality score of an ad, lower the prices and better the ranking of the ad position.</p>
<p>According to Forbes, after the creation of a custom-landing page, which they aptly named campaign landing page (CLP), their results improved dramatically. B2B marketers must create CLPs whenever the link to the existing content is not completely aligned or relevant.</p>
<p>Landing pages need to be specific to the ad including all the given information, appropriate resources and related content that could be easily found by a client. They could be customer stories, data sheets, videos, testimonials, CTAs and more on one landing page.</p>
<p>Having marketing teams follow up on no-quality leads is an absolute waste of time on sales. To avoid this, it is essential to make it clear that you’re a B2B company – by asking for the visitor’s business email, company name or highlight the fact that your customers are other businesses.</p>
<h2>Write Ad Copy for B2B Buyers</h2>
<p>Ad Copy is the main text for a clickable advertisement that is displayed on a search engine results page.</p>
<p>Here are a few tips to keep in mind to write an Ad Copy for B2B Buyer:</p>
<ul>
<li>First impression is the best impression they say so it’s not advised to beat around the bush as its businesses you’re attracting and not people.</li>
<li>Understand what your clients want to convey.</li>
<li>Don’t overload the reader with excessive content. Give them sufficient content for them to make a choice of choosing you over another company and make them come to you for the fine details.</li>
<li>Address their point in the Buyer Journey by using industry terminology.</li>
<li>Headlines really draw attention of the reader; hence give them a headline that addresses the specific need.</li>
<li>Make your Call To Action clear and attention grabbing but linking sufficient buttons such as ‘Sign up now’, ‘Call us!’, ‘Get in touch with us’, ‘Shop more at our website’ etc.</li>
<li>Make the content of the ad clear and deliverable with relevant headlines and description within word limits.</li>
<li>Use helpful online tools that are at disposal to frame better sentences.</li>
<li>The content of Ad Copy must align to the information provided on their respective landing pages.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Make the Most of Ad Extensions</h2>
<p>Ad Extensions help your ad stand out and provide more information. They are snippets of relevant information about your business that can be added to the AdWords text ads. Some of the benefits of using ad extensions are that they increase visibility and Click Through Rates, create a better user experience and provide relevant information at the right time. Different extensions do different things. Some of the most common are as follows:</p>
<p><u>Sitelink Extensions</u>: Sitelink Extensions provide additional information giving the client an opportunity to finding the most relevant result. They provide a brief summary of the subpages, which could increase CTAs. You can add up to maximum four links with the ad.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5555 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sitelink-ext-448x450.png" alt="Sitelink extensions " width="448" height="450" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sitelink-ext-448x450.png 448w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sitelink-ext-150x150.png 150w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sitelink-ext.png 562w" sizes="(max-width: 448px) 100vw, 448px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><u>Call Extensions</u>: Call Extensions are usually incorporated to help the searcher get in touch with the business immediately and not having to go through the website and find their contact details.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5557 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Call-out-450x351.png" alt="Call link extensions" width="450" height="351" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Call-out-450x351.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Call-out.png 699w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><u>Location Extensions</u>: Businesses usually have multiple locations and it is important to direct traffic to the right store location. Adding location extensions only helps instating trust and legitimacy of the business.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5560 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Location-Ext-450x109.png" alt="Location Extensions" width="450" height="109" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Location-Ext-450x109.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Location-Ext.png 451w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><u>Structured Extensions</u>: These extensions usually provide information on the nature, types or varieties of products or services helping highlight specific aspects of the product or service offered by the company.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5556 size-medium" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Structured-ext-copy-450x154.png" alt="Structured Extensions" width="450" height="154" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Structured-ext-copy-450x154.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Structured-ext-copy.png 576w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<h2>Test and Optimise Your Ads</h2>
<p>Lastly, it’s critical to optimise all the above elements and look into the account regularly to make improvements or update necessary information when needed. Timely checks on ads are advised such as checking keywords using ‘Search terms’ report. Regularly updating the keywords list to add to your Ad Groups or monitoring which ad is working out in the best interest of the company. Google ideally advises to have three ads at all times for effective results, so never discontinue optimising your AdWords Campaigns.</p>
<p>Google AdWords therefore is definitely an added advantage to your existing B2B campaign. By integrating necessary keywords, landing pages, relevant content, CTAs, added extensions etc., they will properly leverage the capabilities of Google Ads and over a fairly short period of time this will result in significant improvement for your business.</p>
<p>Get in touch with the expert <a href="/">Marketing Consultants</a> at the Lead Agency to convert your B2B business traffic to leads, virtually! There couldn’t be a greater way than Google Ads to combine all the little pieces of necessary information to attract potential customers.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget to check out our other service industries which include the following; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-ways-to-optimize-your-b2b-google-ads-campaign/">5 Ways to Optimize your B2B Google Ads Campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</title>
		<link>/six-steps-account-based-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Services Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So, you’ve heard of Account Based Marketing and want to know what all the fuss is about? Well, you’ve come to right place. In this article, we’re going to outline what Account Based Marketing is and how you can use it in your business. Account Based Marketing was initially developed to solve the B2B problem [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/six-steps-account-based-marketing/">The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, you’ve heard of Account Based Marketing and want to know what all the fuss is about? Well, you’ve come to right place. In this article, we’re going to outline what Account Based Marketing is and how you can use it in your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing was initially developed to solve the B2B problem of multiple decision makers being involved in a purchase. Rarely is there ever just one sole decision maker in a business deciding what product to buy &#8211; there can be anywhere up to a dozen decision makers in any one account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing can offer a lot to B2B enterprises looking to improve their ROI. According to research from the</span><a href="https://au.marketo.com/account-based-marketing/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Altera Group</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, “97% [of B2B businesses] had a somewhat higher or much higher ROI than other marketing initiatives.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whereas traditional lead generation is akin to fishing with a net, ABM is the equivalent of fishing with a spear. Rather than general broadcasts, you are focused on winning over key accounts. Adjusting to the demands can be difficult at first, but ABM tends to have better results, especially for B2B marketers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, how do you know who to contact? How do you personalise interactions with each decision maker? Read on for a step-by-step method to unlocking complex B2B accounts!</span></p>
<h2><b>How Does Account Based Marketing Differ From The Traditional Sales Pipeline Approach?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing may seem a little alien to those used to employing a sales pipeline. Metrics such as the number of qualified leads, prospects and other such demarcations don’t easily fit the Account-Based Marketing model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the biggest differences is that Account Based Marketing is about creating quality relationships with a few key influencers and decision makers, as opposed to playing a numbers game hoping to attract significant numbers of qualified leads. You will also find that, given the low volume of accounts, you will not be able to use traditional funnel metrics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The longer sales cycles will impact what types of metrics you should focus on. Given your objective is to build stronger relationships over time, engagement becomes an increasingly important metric to use.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing means that sales and marketing have to work closely together to generate real results. Demonstrating value then becomes increasingly important.</span></p>
<h2><b>What Are The Benefits of Account Based Marketing?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account-Based Marketing doesn’t mean you have to start from scratch with your existing marketing. So long as your have your executive on board, have a good team of people and  are able to align your sales and marketing, you will find that this type of marketing will slot in nicely with your existing marketing strategies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Big businesses are run by individuals, if you can harness the power of scaled personalisation, you will find that you will be able to develop one-to-one communication quite easily.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the benefits of employing Account Based Marketing is a higher Return On Investment (ROI), better relationships with existing clients, and better alignment between your sales and marketing departments.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4618 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/findingyouraccount.jpg" alt="Find Your Account" width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h2><b>Step 1. Find Your Account</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Create a list of target accounts and then organise them according to a tiered structure. Once you have your list, you want establish how much of a percentage of your time you wish to dedicate to each tier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You may wish to have three tiers set up:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first tier contains those accounts that you believe are worth investing more time in researching, developing personalised touchpoint and investing in long-term. Tactics may include heavy targeting by sales and significant support. (20-50)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second tier might be accounts you see merit in, but are not willing to spend a significant amount time in pursuing. You may choose to use tactics that are less time intensive, such as direct mail and phone calls. (200-500)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The third tier will be accounts that are in your general periphery but not your focus. General marketing automation and limited personalisation would apply to this group. (2000-5000)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Establishing your list of accounts is a fine balance between art and science. Use any data you have access to to establish the viability of prospects and whom you should priortise.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 2. Map Out Who The Decision Makers Are</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you have your list of accounts it’s time to get started building some generalised personas to represent different members of the teams. Yet again, prioritise these accounts according to key stakeholders, and lower influence team members.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now comes the nitty-gritty of researching each target account and mapping out their staff individually. Attach your persona profiles to each contact and start building a comprehensive database. Tools for developing this could be LinkedIn, or even going through a data vendor.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 3. Research The Account</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now comes the time to get research done on the accounts as whole. You will need to find out the following:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who their target market is?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their mission, vision and values?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their culture and agenda?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The work dynamic within the organisation?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are there any existing connections to the account?</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This research can come from conversations, surveys, stalking their website and social media or even just general market data.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4618 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/createcontent.jpg" alt="Relevant Content " width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h2><b>Step 4. Create Relevant Content</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Creating content that is going to resonate with your different accounts is the next step. We don’t suggest you create specific content for each account but have a wide range of content that varies in its level of personalisation depending on the importance of the account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the higher end of this spectrum is content specifically for one account, at the lower end is generic broad content and in between might be content targeted towards certain industries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Changing the title, feature picture and headline may be all that is needed to personalise content. If you have the time and see value in a particular prospect, you may wish to spend time labouring over some more specific content.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 5. Decide On Your Tactics For Interaction</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where all your hard work and research can finally be put to use. Now you have your accounts, and you know who you are targeting within each account, you can begin to reach out to your prospects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing interactions are unique in that you are applying inbound two-way communication and sharing of relevant content to an outbound marketing strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some tactics you may wish to employ may include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Hosting Events </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Create, or simply host, business networking events. These events allow your sales team to get direct access to those accounts they are targeting.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Direct Mail </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; In a digital world, physical mail is more likely to cut through the clutter. Creating personalised direct mail campaigns to target priority accounts is a great way to open doors.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><b>Email Marketing </b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; You may have general eNewsletters accounts can subscribe to, however, if you want to build two-way communication, consider avoiding smart looking templates and using more text-based personal emails.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Digital Advertising </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Use retargeting, personalised search and social media paid advertising to get to your audience. LinkedIn, for example, allows you to target your posts exclusively to certain demographics.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Free Webinars </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Host relevant and interesting webinars to get the attention of account-holders. By creating personalised invitations to events you are also able to make a good impression.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Step 6. Progress Your Strategy</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now the campaign is up and running, consider what your game plan is going to be. Rather than traditional tactics of broadcasting to a wide net and hoping some stick, you need to be very specific in your planning. Have a marketing flow chart prepared with the list of the different channels and tactics you plan to employ for each account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are two things you need to consider when building your strategy. The first is how long you plan to run your campaign for and how often you plan to post. The second is creating a strategy employing a diverse range of integrated channels.</span></p>
<h2><b>Summary</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are interested in ABM marketing and looking for assistance employing it for your B2B business, please contact <a href="/">The Lead Agency</a>. Our expert <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> are generating leads and prospects for your business and building strong, resilient ties with them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more information about the impact Account Based Marketing is having on <a href="/">B2B marketing</a>, try reading this article on</span><a href="/account-based-marketing-revolutionising-b2b/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">How Account Based Marketing Is Revolutionising B2B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<noscript class="ninja-forms-noscript-message">
    Notice: JavaScript is required for this content.</noscript><style>

        /* PLUGIN WIDE STYLES */
    
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container.textarea-container .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    height:100px!important;
                    }
    </style><style>

        /* FORM STYLES */
    
        #nf-form-2_1-cont {
                                    background-color:#e74c3c;
                                            padding:10px;
                                                    box-shadow: -webkit-box-shadow: 4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);
-moz-box-shadow:    4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);
box-shadow:         4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);                    }
        #nf-form-2_1-cont .nf-form-title h3 {
                                    color:#f8c9c3;
                                            font-size:30px;
                                            margin:10px 0px;
                                                    text-align: center                    }
    </style><style>

        /* FIELDS STYLES */
    
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap {
                                    color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-10_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-10_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-6_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap {
                                    width:100%;
                                            display:block;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    width:100%;
                                            display:block;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    background-color:#31415c;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                                            width:100%;
                                            font-size:18px;
                                            padding:10px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field:hover {
                                    background-color:#162542;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                    }
    </style><div id="nf-form-2_1-cont" class="nf-form-cont" aria-live="polite" aria-labelledby="nf-form-title-2_1" aria-describedby="nf-form-errors-2_1" role="form">

    <div class="nf-loading-spinner"></div>

</div>
        <!-- TODO: Move to Template File. -->
        <script>var formDisplay=1;var nfForms=nfForms||[];var form=[];form.id='2_1';form.settings={"objectType":"Form Setting","editActive":true,"title":"Contact The Lead Agency","key":"","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","default_label_pos":"hidden","conditions":[],"show_title":1,"clear_complete":"1","hide_complete":"1","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","add_submit":"1","logged_in":"","not_logged_in_msg":"","sub_limit_number":"","sub_limit_msg":"","calculations":[],"formContentData":[{"order":1,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["name"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":2,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["contact_number_1491218320211"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":3,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["email"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":4,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["i_need_help_with_1549425070059"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":5,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["recaptcha_1602543056346"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":6,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["hidden_1571292741941"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":7,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["speak_to_a_b2b_expert_1508319997306"],"width":"100"}]}],"container_styles_background-color":"#e74c3c","container_styles_border":"","container_styles_border-style":"","container_styles_border-color":"","container_styles_color":"","container_styles_height":"","container_styles_width":"","container_styles_font-size":"","container_styles_margin":"","container_styles_padding":"10px","container_styles_display":"","container_styles_float":"","container_styles_show_advanced_css":1,"container_styles_advanced":"box-shadow: -webkit-box-shadow: 4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);\n-moz-box-shadow:    4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);\nbox-shadow:         4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);","title_styles_background-color":"","title_styles_border":"","title_styles_border-style":"","title_styles_border-color":"","title_styles_color":"#f8c9c3","title_styles_height":"","title_styles_width":"","title_styles_font-size":"30px","title_styles_margin":"10px 0px","title_styles_padding":"","title_styles_display":"","title_styles_float":"","title_styles_show_advanced_css":1,"title_styles_advanced":"text-align: center","row_styles_background-color":"","row_styles_border":"","row_styles_border-style":"","row_styles_border-color":"","row_styles_color":"","row_styles_height":"","row_styles_width":"","row_styles_font-size":"","row_styles_margin":"","row_styles_padding":"","row_styles_display":"","row_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","row_styles_advanced":"","row-odd_styles_background-color":"","row-odd_styles_border":"","row-odd_styles_border-style":"","row-odd_styles_border-color":"","row-odd_styles_color":"","row-odd_styles_height":"","row-odd_styles_width":"","row-odd_styles_font-size":"","row-odd_styles_margin":"","row-odd_styles_padding":"","row-odd_styles_display":"","row-odd_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","row-odd_styles_advanced":"","success-msg_styles_background-color":"","success-msg_styles_border":"","success-msg_styles_border-style":"","success-msg_styles_border-color":"","success-msg_styles_color":"","success-msg_styles_height":"","success-msg_styles_width":"","success-msg_styles_font-size":"","success-msg_styles_margin":"","success-msg_styles_padding":"","success-msg_styles_display":"","success-msg_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","success-msg_styles_advanced":"","error_msg_styles_background-color":"","error_msg_styles_border":"","error_msg_styles_border-style":"","error_msg_styles_border-color":"","error_msg_styles_color":"","error_msg_styles_height":"","error_msg_styles_width":"","error_msg_styles_font-size":"","error_msg_styles_margin":"","error_msg_styles_padding":"","error_msg_styles_display":"","error_msg_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","error_msg_styles_advanced":"","changeEmailErrorMsg":"Please enter a valid email address!","confirmFieldErrorMsg":"These fields must match!","fieldNumberNumMinError":"Number Min Error","fieldNumberNumMaxError":"Number Max Error","fieldNumberIncrementBy":"Please increment by ","formErrorsCorrectErrors":"Please correct errors before submitting this form.","validateRequiredField":"This is a required field.","honeypotHoneypotError":"Honeypot Error","fieldsMarkedRequired":"Fields marked with an <span class=\"ninja-forms-req-symbol\">*<\/span> are required","currency":"","unique_field_error":"A form with this value has already been submitted.","allow_public_link":0,"embed_form":"","drawerDisabled":false,"ninjaForms":"Ninja Forms","changeDateErrorMsg":"Please enter a valid date!","fieldTextareaRTEInsertLink":"Insert Link","fieldTextareaRTEInsertMedia":"Insert Media","fieldTextareaRTESelectAFile":"Select a file","formHoneypot":"If you are a human seeing this field, please leave it empty.","fileUploadOldCodeFileUploadInProgress":"File Upload in Progress.","fileUploadOldCodeFileUpload":"FILE UPLOAD","currencySymbol":"&#36;","thousands_sep":",","decimal_point":".","siteLocale":"en_AU","dateFormat":"m\/d\/Y","startOfWeek":"1","of":"of","previousMonth":"Previous Month","nextMonth":"Next Month","months":["January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"monthsShort":["Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"weekdays":["Sunday","Monday","Tuesday","Wednesday","Thursday","Friday","Saturday"],"weekdaysShort":["Sun","Mon","Tue","Wed","Thu","Fri","Sat"],"weekdaysMin":["Su","Mo","Tu","We","Th","Fr","Sa"],"currency_symbol":"","beforeForm":"","beforeFields":"","afterFields":"","afterForm":""};form.fields=[{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":1,"label":"Name","key":"name","type":"textbox","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Name","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":"","disable_input":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","disable_browser_autocomplete":"","mask":"","custom_mask":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"#ffffff","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"#ffffff","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"#ffffff","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3466","custom_name_attribute":"","personally_identifiable":"","value":"","id":"5_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["textbox","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":2,"label":"Contact Number","key":"contact_number_1491218320211","type":"textbox","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Contact Number","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":"","disable_input":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","disable_browser_autocomplete":"","mask":"","custom_mask":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"0px","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3470","custom_name_attribute":"","personally_identifiable":"","value":"","id":"10_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["textbox","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":3,"label":"Email","key":"email","type":"email","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Email","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3473","custom_name_attribute":"email","personally_identifiable":1,"value":"","id":"6_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"email","element_templates":["email","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":4,"label":"I need help with...","type":"textarea","key":"i_need_help_with_1549425070059","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"default":"","placeholder":"I need help with...","container_class":"","element_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":false,"admin_label":"","help_text":"","textarea_rte":"","disable_rte_mobile":"","textarea_media":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"cellcid":"c3476","drawerDisabled":false,"value":"","id":"71_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textarea","element_templates":["textarea","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":5,"label":"Recaptcha","type":"recaptcha","container_class":"","element_class":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"size":"visible","key":"recaptcha_1602543056346","cellcid":"c3731","id":"80_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["recaptcha","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap","site_key":"6LdootYZAAAAAEwDzfbB_4BI4UK8B2U9F1bmQcbQ","theme":"dark","lang":"en"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":6,"label":"Hidden","type":"hidden","key":"hidden_1571292741941","default":"{wp:post_title}","admin_label":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_border":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_border":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"cellcid":"c3479","drawerDisabled":false,"id":"72_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"hidden","element_templates":["hidden","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap-no-label"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":7,"label":"SPEAK TO A B2B EXPERT","key":"speak_to_a_b2b_expert_1508319997306","type":"submit","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","processing_label":"Processing","container_class":"","element_class":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"100%","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"block","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"100%","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"block","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"#31415c","element_styles_border":"","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"#ffffff","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"100%","element_styles_font-size":"18px","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"10px","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","submit_element_hover_styles_background-color":"#162542","submit_element_hover_styles_border":"","submit_element_hover_styles_border-style":"","submit_element_hover_styles_border-color":"","submit_element_hover_styles_color":"#ffffff","submit_element_hover_styles_height":"","submit_element_hover_styles_width":"","submit_element_hover_styles_font-size":"","submit_element_hover_styles_margin":"","submit_element_hover_styles_padding":"","submit_element_hover_styles_display":"","submit_element_hover_styles_float":"","submit_element_hover_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"submit_element_hover_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3482","drawerDisabled":false,"id":"8_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["submit","button","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap-no-label"}];nfForms.push(form);</script>
                <script id="nf-tmpl-cell" type="text/template">
            <nf-fields></nf-fields>
        </script>

        <script id="nf-tmpl-row" type="text/template">
            <nf-cells></nf-cells>
        </script>

        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/six-steps-account-based-marketing/">The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
