<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 02:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>B2B Marketing 2022 Trends</title>
		<link>/b2b-marketing-2022-trends/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 02:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=49129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The COVID-19 pandemic that has dominated our lives for the last 18 months has changed how we live both professionally and personally, and the B2B landscape is no different. The way companies buy from and sell to each other is very different than it used to be just a couple of years ago and is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-marketing-2022-trends/">B2B Marketing 2022 Trends</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The COVID-19 pandemic that has dominated our lives for the last 18 months has changed how we live both professionally and personally, and the B2B landscape is no different. The way companies buy from and sell to each other is very different than it used to be just a couple of years ago and is likely to continue to evolve in 2022 and beyond. To succeed with marketing campaigns in 2022, businesses will have to continue to adapt their strategies to suit buyer trends.</p>
<p>In order to gain a deeper understanding of how the COVID19 pandemic has changed B2B buying behaviour, McKinsey &amp; Company put together the <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/how-b2b-decision-makers-are-responding-to-the-coronavirus-crisis">B2B Decision Maker Pulse</a> survey. With responses from 3,600 B2B decision-makers across 11 countries, the report outlines the major shifts and swings that have been seen across the B2B sector, as follows.</p>
<h3> 1. Shift to A Digital Reality</h3>
<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has driven a shift to digitisation. What started out as a crisis response has become our normality, and this has had a major impact on how business buyers and sellers will operate going forward, even after lockdowns have largely ended.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>According to the report, over 75% of buyers and sellers say they now prefer digital self-serve and remote human engagement over face-to-face interactions. &#8211; <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/how-b2b-decision-makers-are-responding-to-the-coronavirus-crisis">B2B Decision Maker Pulse</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buyers have gotten used to remote interactions, and in many cases, have realised that this type of interaction makes it easier for them to get information, place orders, and arrange services. Buyers are widely enjoying the change and flexibility that comes with remote buying, with only around 20% of B2B buyers saying they hope to return to in-person sales.</p>
<h3> 2. B2B Customers are Buying Big Online</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>70% of B2B decision-makers say they are open to making new, fully self-serve or remote purchases in excess of $50,000 online. &#8211; <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/how-b2b-decision-makers-are-responding-to-the-coronavirus-crisis">B2B Decision Maker Pulse</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>While e-commerce used to be primarily used for B2C buying and smaller, less involved purchases, B2B buyers are more confident than ever in making large purchases online – even with new businesses. It’s not only buyers who are embracing the change, as B2B sellers have reported online sales to be just as effective or more effective than in-person sales engagements. According to the McKinsey &amp; Company report, sellers also reported digital prospecting to be just as effective as meeting in-person to connect with potential new customers.</p>
<h3> 3. Video and Live Chat Growing in Prominence</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount of revenue generated from video-related interactions has jumped by 69% since April 2020. &#8211; <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/how-b2b-decision-makers-are-responding-to-the-coronavirus-crisis">B2B Decision Maker Pulse</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>With the shift to digital, consumers have turned to video and live chat to find out more about the businesses they are buying from. The majority of survey respondents stated that, given the choice, they prefer video to phone. From a sales perspective, businesses are making the most of these digital channels and using them to interact with and even close sales with B2B customers, as opposed to attending in-person meetings and networking events. According to the McKinsey report, e-commerce and videoconferencing now account for 43% of all B2B revenue.</p>
<h2>The Digital Future: B2B Marketing Trends 2022</h2>
<p>It looks like the B2B buying and selling practices that have come around as a result of the pandemic are here to stay and will permanently impact B2B interactions between buyers and sellers.</p>
<p>This significant shift to digital adoption presents a number of opportunities for B2B businesses, namely lowering cost per acquisition, extending reach, and improving sales effectiveness. Businesses will have to move fast to adapt to this new digital norm to ensure they are not left behind. As such, the dominant trends for 2022 are primarily in the digital sector.</p>
<p>Businesses with an understanding of the top B2B trends that are impacting the industry are best positioned to outpace the competition. The following are the strategies that we think B2B marketers should take note of to inform their 2022 strategies.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Trend 1:</strong> Rising Popularity of Video for B2B</li>
<li><strong>Trend 2:</strong> Ensure You&#8217;re Using Live Chat</li>
<li><strong>Trend 3:</strong> Don’t Forget About Written Content</li>
<li><strong>Trend 4:</strong> Focus on Customer Retention</li>
<li><strong>Trend 5:</strong> Keep an Eye on Evolving SEO Strategies</li>
<li><strong>Trend 6:</strong> Smart Businesses will Use Predictive Analytics</li>
<li><strong>Trend 7:</strong> Omnichannel Marketing Becomes a Necessity</li>
<li><strong>Trend 8:</strong> Update Digital Strategies for Google Discovery</li>
</ul>
<h3>Trend 1: Rising Popularity of Video for B2B</h3>
<p>Viewers retain <a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2017/03/08/video-marketing-statistics#:~:text=Viewers%20retain%2095%25%20of%20a,of%20all%20consumer%20Internet%20traffic.">95% of a message</a> when they watch it in a video compared to just 10% when reading text. As such, it’s not surprising that video content has become an increasingly popular marketing choice for companies worldwide. As a result of the global pandemic, video marketing shows no signs of slowing down. In fact, during 2020, at the height of the COVID-19 pandemic, <a href="https://business.linkedin.com/marketing-solutions/blog/video-marketing-/2021/b2b-video-marketing-in-2021--the-top-trends">80% of marketers</a> incorporated video into their non-paid advertising strategies, using the channel to drive traffic to their websites, as well as to attract and convert leads.</p>
<p>Video has traditionally been considered an appropriate and effective marketing tool for B2C marketing. However, more and more B2B companies are starting to incorporate video content into their marketing strategy as they realise the value that it can add to their campaigns.</p>
<p>Video is the ideal channel for engaging users at every stage of the inbound marketing funnel and nurture them through to sale. With the pandemic resulting in increased competition across industries, it is the ideal time for businesses to try incorporating video into their strategy if they are not already.</p>
<h3>Trend 2: Ensure You&#8217;re Using Live Chat</h3>
<p>Today’s B2B buyers want to communicate with businesses in real-time. Servicing this need is essential, as <a href="https://go.forrester.com/blogs/retailers-without-chat-a-missed-opportunity/">50% of adults will abandon a purchase if you can’t give them a quick answer to their question</a>. One of the most effective ways to do this is through a live chat function on the business website.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.b2bmarketing.net/en-gb/resources/blog/super-charged-lead-generation-10-reasons-why-live-chat-increases-marketing-roi">Businesses using Live chat have an average response time of 11 seconds, compared to two to three hours for an email response</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Live chat provides a method for businesses to have a more direct and personal interaction with customers. It helps companies answer their customers’ questions in order to remove buying objections and move them through the buying funnel to sale. When customers receive an immediate response to their questions, they are more likely to feel satisfied with the business’ service and have more positive feelings toward the brand. Ultimately, this means they are more likely to buy. In fact, <a href="https://www.crazyegg.com/blog/live-chat-software-solutions/">38% of consumers are more likely to buy</a> from a company if they offer live chat support.</p>
<p>Remember that today’s customers are more in control than ever, and they want to talk to businesses on their own terms, so having a multi-channel chat option is key. Offer a range of options for customers and potential customers to communicate with your business, for example, through web chat, social media, or SMS and WhatsApp.</p>
<h3>Trend 3: Don’t Forget About Written Content</h3>
<p>We’ve said it before, and we’ll say it again: content is king.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>60% of customers consider inquiring and buying a product after reading any kind of content about it. – <a href="https://www.demandmetric.com/content/content-marketing-infographic">Demand Metric</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://pamhughes.io/12-advantages-of-a-high-quality-content-marketing-strategy/">High-quality content marketing</a> not only helps businesses share important communications with customers and prospects, but it is also essential for being found online as search engines love content. Content marketing is essential for SEO consistency, and websites that post unique, creative, and original content are indexed more quickly on search engine results pages and are more likely to rank higher than competitors.</p>
<p>However, <strong><a href="https://www.meaningful-brands.com/">58% of content provided to customers is considered hollow and meaningless.</a></strong> Content should be written above all else for the reader, not the search engine. Be persuasive, and appeal to customers who are looking for a solution to a problem or an answer to their question. Ensure your key focus is to provide something that adds value to them. Just be mindful to include target keywords in the content and focus on specific visitor queries so that search engines know what terms to rank your page for.</p>
<h3>Trend 4: Focus on Customer Retention</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>Increasing customer retention by just 5% boosts profits by 25% to 95% &#8211; <a href="https://www.smallbizgenius.net/by-the-numbers/customer-loyalty-statistics/#gref">SmallBizGenius</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>As marketers, we typically focus on attracting new customers. While this is a necessity for business growth, focusing more on existing customers can significantly boost a business’ bottom line. <a href="https://altfeldinc.com/pdfs/Customer%20Loyalty.pdf">The likelihood of selling to an existing customer is 60-70%. For new customers, that figure drops to 5-20%.</a>  </p>
<p>Retaining customers over the long term can be achieved through proactive account management strategies based on data and actions that are put in place to continually improve the customer experience. In the B2B sector, customer retention strategies centre around developing long term and close relationships. The most successful methods involve focusing on tailoring unique solutions to each individual customer to reduce churn rather than offering blanket promotions to a wide audience. As customer retention tactics are so specific to each customer, there is no one-size-fits-all approach to what works. However, the following are some of the most effective customer retention tactics that should be considered.</p>
<h3>Trend 5: Keep an Eye on Evolving SEO Strategies</h3>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.hubspot.com/state-of-marketing">61% of B2B marketers stated that SEO and organic traffic generate more leads than any other marketing initiative</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://inter-growth.co/seo-stats/">Google currently holds 92.27% of the total search engine market share</a>. The search engine giant is constantly working to improve the search experience for users to ensure that the information it displays is relevant to the searcher’s intent, history of visited pages, and frequent queries.</p>
<p>In 2022, keyword results are likely to become more practical due to the implementation of voice recognition that has led to casual, conversation-type questions being used more often by searchers.</p>
<p>What does this mean for SEO in 2022?</p>
<p>Content will remain a key part of SEO in 2022; however, the way businesses do it will have to evolve. Google is starting to look at synonyms and related words; as such, the age of keyword stuffing is well and truly over. Instead, marketers should write high-quality content that considers user search intent. Writing for the user rather than the search engine is vital, as search engines are now smart enough to understand what users want.</p>
<p>Other SEO strategies for 2022 include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Local Search:</strong> Surveys have shown that people prefer to work and study at home and will likely continue to do so long after the pandemic. This means they are more likely to be looking for businesses and services in their local area.</li>
<li><strong>Site Speed:</strong> More and more users are accessing websites on the go, so it has become critical for companies to provide fast website experiences.</li>
<li><strong>Go Mobile (If you’re not already):</strong> Google uses a mobile-first indexing system, which means it takes a website’s mobile version into account when ranking search results.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Trend 6: Smart Businesses will Use Predictive Analytics</h3>
<p>Predictive analysis is the process of offering personalised recommendations based on previous user behaviour, consumption, and buying patterns. For years, major global companies like Amazon, Netflix and Facebook have been using predictive analytics to give consumers what they want. While these businesses are in the B2C sector, B2B businesses should take note, as B2B buying behaviour and expectations are not dissimilar to those of B2C consumers.</p>
<p>But, what does predictive analytics look like for B2B?</p>
<p>B2B businesses can use their historical data to predict future outcomes. Modern technologies like statistical modelling and machine learning give marketers the opportunity to gain deep insights into previous campaigns so that they can <a href="https://www.cio.com/article/3273114/what-is-predictive-analytics-transforming-data-into-future-insights.html">forecast consumer trends, study behavioural aspects, and tweak future marketing strategies based on derived inferences</a>.</p>
<p>Predictive analytics gives businesses the ability to answer questions, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is the lifetime value of adding a particular client?</li>
<li>What is the likely impact on the bottom line if a particular customer is lost?</li>
<li>How much inventory is necessary / how many employees do we need to cope with busy seasons?</li>
<li>Out of 3 specific options, which service will add the most value to customers?</li>
</ul>
<p>In short, predictive analysis helps businesses attract, retain, and nurture new and existing customers. Marketers can also use predictive analytics to optimise campaigns so that they generate more leads and drive more conversions.</p>
<h3>Trend 7: Omnichannel Marketing is a Necessity</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/omnichannel-in-b2b-sales-the-new-normal-in-a-year-that-has-been-anything-but">According to a 2021 report from McKinsey</a>, ‘omnichannel is the standard, not the exception.’</p>
<p>Tipped to be another result of the pandemic, omnichannel interactions have become the major method of making B2B sales. Throughout 2020 and 2021, B2B buyers have had to adapt to remote and digital ways of engaging, and while it may have taken some adjustment, they seem to like the change. So much so that even though we have been able to meet in person again, B2B buyers still prefer a cross-channel mix, with the McKinsey report finding that they want in-person, remote, and digital self-serve interactions in equal measure.</p>
<p>The report also found that buyers moved easily between traditional in-person sales to remote sales, basing their choice of channel on practicality and timing. From a sales perspective, <a href="https://www.digitalcommerce360.com/2021/07/12/business-managers-make-digitally-enabled-selling-the-new-norm/">eight in ten B2B leaders say that omnichannel is as or more effective than traditional methods</a>, up significantly from 54% of leaders who said the same at the start of the pandemic. Omnichannel selling has become a more successful way to prospect and secure new business.</p>
<p>However, omnichannel marketing is not easy. It means putting the customer at the centre of all marketing activities, and thinking holistically in terms of customer experience, interactions, and messaging. In order to be successful, all customer touchpoints have to be connected. So, if a user visits a website, Facebook page, sees a digital ad, receives an email, or sees POS materials in-store &#8211; they all have the same message.</p>
<h3>Trend 8: Update Digital Strategies for Google Discovery Ads</h3>
<p>Google Discovery Ads have been designed to help users discover products that may be of interest to them before they have even started researching. These ads appear in Google&#8217;s &#8216;Discover&#8217; feed for mobile users, as well as across YouTube, where they are displayed in the home feed and on Gmail in the promotions tab. Google uses targeting based on behavioural insights and browsing habits across the Internet to make relevant suggestions to the user.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://valasys.com/google-discovery-ads-for-b2b-business/">According to a recent Ipsos study by Google, 76% of customers enjoy making unexpected discoveries while shopping and 85% of them take a product-oriented action within 24 hours of discovery</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For advertisers, using Google Discovery ads helps leverage the impactful audience targeting features by Google, empowering them to tell visual brand stories to boost brand awareness.</p>
<p>Google discovery ads are ideal for scaling B2B businesses and can help to fill top of the funnel lead generation campaigns, as they are effective in increasing the reach of campaigns across a range of channels. While the cost of attracting top of funnel leads is increasing across digital platforms such as Facebook and LinkedIn, Google discovery ads can boost awareness to B2B users in a cost-effective way.</p>
<p>Google Discovery ads have already started getting positive responses from both media buyers and brands due to their creative visual appearance, widespread reach across hundreds of millions of potential users, and proven results that can be attributed to Google&#8217;s machine learning algorithms that understand their users and what they are looking for.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Technology and marketing strategies change quickly. The most successful B2B marketers have dynamic strategies in place and are aware of the B2B marketing trends that are impacting the sector and those that are likely to in the near future.</p>
<p>Consider all of the above trends in relation to your business’ marketing goals and the resources that you have in order to decide which are most relevant to your business.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a specialist <a href="/">B2B marketing agency</a> with experience across a number of B2B sectors. The above are our predictions for 2022 and beyond, that we will be implementing in our client campaigns. Get in touch with us today to get your <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a> for 2022 organised.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-marketing-2022-trends/">B2B Marketing 2022 Trends</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top tips for executing a successful B2B telemarketing campaign</title>
		<link>/top-tips-for-executing-a-successful-b2b-telemarketing-campaign/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:54:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The year 2020 meant many B2B marketers have (in most cases) turned away from outbound marketing and towards inbound and B2B digital marketing activities. This pivot was, of course, necessary with the shift of individuals working from home driving digital initiatives. Telemarketing became a challenge, with office calls being diverted to a receptionist working at [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/top-tips-for-executing-a-successful-b2b-telemarketing-campaign/">Top tips for executing a successful B2B telemarketing campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The year 2020 meant many B2B marketers have (in most cases) turned away from <a href="/auto-draft-2/">outbound marketing and towards inbound</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> activities. This pivot was, of course, necessary with the shift of individuals working from home driving digital initiatives. Telemarketing became a challenge, with office calls being diverted to a receptionist working at home, and therefore not easily able to transfer those calls onto key decision-makers. However, while it may be more challenging than before, telemarketing can be an extremely effective channel for B2B marketers and marketing agencies, and B2B organisations are eager to dip their toes back in.</p>
<p>As we (in Australia) return to a new state of &#8216;normal&#8217;, many B2B marketers are keen to diversify their marketing campaigns and slowly beginning to incorporate some more direct and outbound marketing activity. Further, many B2B organisations are excited to move back towards some &#8216;old school&#8217; or more traditional activity, with digital marketing perpetuating some fatigue among the professional spheres.</p>
<p>Many B2B marketing agencies leverage telemarketing to recruit <a href="/event-marketing-for-b2b-brands/">face-to-face events</a>, sell products and services and build rapport with customers. If you haven&#8217;t conducted telemarketing before or need a bit of a refresher on how B2B marketers can use it as a successful lead generation tool, let&#8217;s take a moment to refresh our memories.</p>
<blockquote><p>Telemarketing for B2B helps companies reach a group of targeted prospects or customers to communicate a message, gather feedback, and determine a next step for the relationship – <a href="http://www.marketingmo.com/campaigns-execution/telemarketing-for-b2b/">Marketing MO.</a></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="/whats-the-best-for-b2b-marketing-cold-calling-prospecting-or-telemarketing/">Much like &#8216;marketing&#8217;, telemarketing can be used for a range of different activities</a>, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Communicating with your existing customers;</li>
<li>Reengaging with lapsed or old customers;</li>
<li>Speaking to prospective customers;</li>
<li>Following up other marketing activities with prospects; or</li>
<li>Identifying new business prospects that you&#8217;ve never contacted before.</li>
</ul>
<h2>B2B telemarketing tips</h2>
<p>As we witness this shift, what are some of the key points to keep in mind? What can telemarketing or inside sales teams do to ensure their outbound calls are as successful as they could be?</p>
<h3>Be mindful</h3>
<p>COVID-19 has impacted many businesses. Some positively, but many negatively. When beginning to make calls, be mindful of the industry your targeted accounts operate within and what the last 12 months have meant for them.</p>
<h3>Don&#8217;t sound like a telemarketer</h3>
<p>It is no secret that individuals don&#8217;t like to receive sales or telemarketing calls. Further, we can all agree that often it is very easy to identify a sales call within the first few seconds of them speaking. They might sound stiff, and their <a href="https://gsa-marketing.co.uk/10-telemarketing-tips-for-beginners/">dialogue may sound overly scripted</a>. This approach can put prospects off and increase the chance of an unsuccessful call. To be effective with B2B telemarketing, you need to sound comfortable, relaxed and use natural language. Most telemarketers receive a script from a <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-efficiencies/">B2B sales or marketing team</a>, so we recommend adjusting the provided script to reflect your natural language, so the conversations flow and sound like you.</p>
<h3>Be assumptive and exert confidence</h3>
<p>While this ties into our first point of not sounding like a telemarketer, it is one of the most crucial points to remember, so it deserves to stand alone. Being assumptive in telemarketing conversations instils confidence with the caller that you know what you are talking about, which, in turn, gives you credibility and makes the prospect more likely to speak to you and listen to what you have to say.</p>
<h3>Planning is crucial</h3>
<p>Understanding your audience, industry, message, value proposition, and offering is essential for a successful B2B telemarketing campaign. Planning will guide your script and give you the ability to relate to and understand the prospect, further giving you more credibility. As mentioned, there is a fine line between planning and overplanning. As previously discussed, your script must still sound natural, despite the knowledge you may have going into the conversation.</p>
<h3>Understand your value proposition</h3>
<p>When discussions around a <a href="/whats-the-best-for-b2b-marketing-cold-calling-prospecting-or-telemarketing/">B2B telemarketing</a> campaign commence, it is crucial not to lose sight of what you are selling and, further, your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/business-value-proposition/">B2B value proposition</a>. Ask yourself questions – <a href="https://gsa-marketing.co.uk/10-telemarketing-tips-for-beginners/">why should identified prospects speak to you</a>? What have you got that they need that they can&#8217;t do themselves? The answers to these questions should be weaved into the dialogue when crafting your scripts.</p>
<blockquote><p>Therefore, do some research on likely challenges or issues and weave those into your reason for the call to engage the customer from those important first few seconds of the call – <a href="https://gsa-marketing.co.uk/10-telemarketing-tips-for-beginners/">GSA Marketing</a></p></blockquote>
<h3>Embrace rejection</h3>
<p>It is no secret in the telemarketing profession that rejection comes with the territory. It is certainly not for the faint-hearted. It is essential not to personally take criticism or negative feedback and simply move onto the next prospect call. Remain goal-oriented and keep your eyes on the prize.</p>
<h3>Speed up call handling</h3>
<p>Time is precious for both the caller and the receiver. The last thing a busy decision-maker wants is a lengthy introduction to a sales call. Leverage planning time and value proposition knowledge to drive critical points in an &#8216;elevator pitch&#8217; style introduction and get straight to the point.</p>
<p>B2B telemarketing can be a very successful <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B lead generation</a> activity when executed correctly. Ensure your team is well versed in your value proposition and confident speaking on your <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/">B2B business.</a></p>
<p>If you have any questions about this article, or interested in learning more about B2B marketing, please don&#8217;t hesitate to get in contact with one of our <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B marketing consultants.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/top-tips-for-executing-a-successful-b2b-telemarketing-campaign/">Top tips for executing a successful B2B telemarketing campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 types of B2B email marketing campaigns and when to use them</title>
		<link>/3-types-of-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns-and-when-to-use-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 05:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s a reason why approximately 85% of B2B marketers have integrated email marketing into their campaigns – because it works. In fact, 45% of B2B marketers say email is the most effective digital marketing channel. Email is a practical and feasible option for many B2B businesses looking to reach out to new leads, nurture existing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-types-of-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns-and-when-to-use-them/">3 types of B2B email marketing campaigns and when to use them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s a reason why approximately <a href="mailto:https://backlinko.com/email-marketing-stats">85% of B2B marketers have integrated email marketing into their campaigns</a> – because it works. In fact, <a href="mailto:https://www.superoffice.com/blog/b2b-email-marketing-report/">45% of B2B marketers say email is the most effective digital marketing channel</a>.</p>
<p>Email is a practical and feasible option for many B2B businesses looking to reach out to new leads, <a href="/how-to-nurture-leads-with-b2b-marketing-automation/">nurture existing prospects</a> and drive conversions.</p>
<p>There’s now a myriad of email software available and numerous ways to go about getting your message out to prospects.</p>
<p>So, which option is best? The answer isn’t as simple as you may think. When it comes down to it, the most effective <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> strategy for your business will depend largely on your distinct objectives.</p>
<p>In the following article, we’ll be exploring some of the key types of approaches to B2B email marketing we use here at the Lead Agency, while also running you through when their use will be most effective and impactful.</p>
<h2>Why B2B email marketing?</h2>
<p>There are plenty of reasons B2B email marketing should be on your business’ radar. It can not only help you get a leg up on your competition, but also drive real, measurable returns for your business.</p>
<p>When executed well, <a href="mailto:https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/knowledge-base/how-do-you-calculate-email-marketing-roi/">the return-on-investment from email marketing can be as high as 4400%</a>. This means that, for every dollar spent on email campaigns, companies would be making $44.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="mailto:https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">59% of survey respondents said that marketing emails influence their purchase decisions</a> &#8211; HubSpot</p></blockquote>
<p>But, what is at about email that makes this achievable?</p>
<p>With segmented audiences and value-driven content, companies can directly target individuals with information and resources they will actually be interested in – sent right to their inbox.</p>
<p>B2B emails are also a great way to keep leads in the <a href="mailto:/how-do-b2b-and-b2c-marketing-funnels-differ/">marketing funnel</a> so, when they are eventually ready to purchase a product or service like yours, they know where to go. On average, <a href="mailto:https://blog.hellostepchange.com/blog/the-industry-average-b2b-sales-cycle-length">B2B leads take 84 days to convert</a>, so managing this ongoing relationship and fostering meaningful interactions is crucial.</p>
<h2>Types of B2B email marketing</h2>
<p>If you’re ready to get started with <a href="mailto:/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a>, you first need to determine which option/s are for you. Here are three approaches commonly used by our team and when to use them.</p>
<h3>1. B2B newsletters</h3>
<p>By periodically sending <a href="mailto:/crafting-b2b-newsletters-that-drive-engagement/">B2B newsletters</a> to your contacts, you can highlight certain products or offerings, provide your audience with useful information, share exciting updates and more.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="mailto:https://sleeknote.com/blog/b2b-newsletter-ideas">During 2020, 81% of B2B brands were sending out newsletters</a> &#8211; Sleeknote</p></blockquote>
<p>When done right, there’s no denying that B2B newsletters can be a powerful strategy that drives real results for businesses. But, what does ‘done right’ mean in this case?</p>
<p>Here are some newsletter best practices and tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make sure you’re using a high-quality, up-to-date list;</li>
<li>Get your sending frequency right, which means getting an email out <a href="mailto:https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/knowledge-base/how-often-should-you-send-out-a-newsletter/">at least once a month, but no more than twice a week</a>;</li>
<li>Be direct and to-the-point;</li>
<li>Use subject lines that spark interest but won’t be mistaken for spam;</li>
<li>Focus on educating and informing, not selling;</li>
<li>Target the individual with personal, engaging storytelling;</li>
<li>Direct readers to a helpful and relevant resource of yours, such as a blog or whitepaper;</li>
<li>Monitor the ongoing performance of emails and make any necessary adjustments.</li>
</ul>
<h3>2. B2B marketing automation</h3>
<p><a href="/what-is-email-automation-and-why-should-you-use-it/">B2B marketing automation</a> is typically used to capture and nurture leads. For instance, if a prospect downloads a resource on your website like an eBook or whitepaper, and you get their email in the process, you can continue to reach out to them over time.</p>
<p>These emails are a bit different to newsletters, in that there’s usually an aspect of continuity and flow that needs to come into play. In the case of an eBook download, you could highlight a chapter a week and conclude with an exclusive offer at the end of your automation to encourage conversions. This keeps the content relevant to users, while also ensuring the automation’s messaging is consistent and driven by purpose.</p>
<p>When implementing email automation as a strategy for your business, make sure to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Map and plan your automation, rather than jumping in head first;</li>
<li>Find and get familiar with marketing automation software, such as that provided by Active Campaign;</li>
<li>Deliver content that’s targeted and relevant to your audience;</li>
<li>Understand your audience’s buying cycle and use this information to determine how often to email prospects;</li>
<li>Keep your content direct and to-the-point;</li>
<li>Use lead scoring to measure levels of engagement;</li>
<li>Include a call-to-action.</li>
</ul>
<h3>3. B2B email outreach</h3>
<p>Email outreach is a form of <a href="mailto:/auto-draft-2/">outbound marketing</a>, which is when you directly reach out to new customers to see if they’re interested in your product or service. A really important aspect of this is where you source your sending list from, as you want to make sure it’s up-to-date and that the potential leads you’re contacting are likely to have a real interest in your offering.</p>
<p>While marketing automation emails and newsletters are usually designed in a way that leverages graphics, such as through the use of a header image and brand-specific format, outreach emails are often made to look like they’re coming directly from a member of your company.</p>
<p>The email copy is short and direct, but in a different way to the other email options mentioned. An effective way to approach this is starting out by saying who you are and what you’re selling, why you’re contacting them and then asking to arrange a chat if they’d like more information. Personalisation is also key, and when possible (and the details you have allow for this), it’s a great idea to open the email by saying ‘hi’ to the recipient by name.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in building a strong <a href="mailto:/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> strategy or this article has brought up any questions, get in touch with the Lead Agency. We’re experts in B2B marketing, offering a range of services including <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">lead generation</a>, and <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-types-of-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns-and-when-to-use-them/">3 types of B2B email marketing campaigns and when to use them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should your B2B Organisation be Using QR Codes?</title>
		<link>/should-your-b2b-organisation-be-using-qr-codes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 22:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It would come as no surprise to marketers and non-marketers alike, that QR codes have been a notable part of 2020 as the coronavirus pandemic caused a world-wide health scare that prompted a mandatory check-in policy across Australia. Most people would agree they have never scanned as many QR codes as they did in 2020. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/should-your-b2b-organisation-be-using-qr-codes/">Should your B2B Organisation be Using QR Codes?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It would come as no surprise to marketers and non-marketers alike, that QR codes have been a notable part of 2020 as the coronavirus pandemic caused a world-wide health scare that prompted a mandatory check-in policy across Australia. Most people would agree they have never scanned as many QR codes as they did in 2020.</p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">A QR code, or a quick response code, is a code that is readable by a mobile phone, taking users directly through to a digital page. That page may be a website, a form or a social media page. It is a barcode which stores information as a <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/q/quick-response-qr-code.asp">series of pixels, in either a square</a> or rectangular shape. </span></p>
<h2><span data-preserver-spaces="true">A Brief History of QR Codes</span></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">For a short time, QR codes were recognised as the poster child of marketing and soon, became an overused marketing fad. Originating in Japan, QR codes were found everywhere and everywhere. Unlike Japan, QR codes did not gain much traction in Australia. You had to download an app for the technology to work, and as expected in a less technologically savvy world, most people did not know how to do this. Today, it is a built-in feature, connecting directly from your camera to a website. However, those countries that adopted the technology saw that the value of QR codes eroded overtime.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Recently, QR codes have experienced a resurgence while kickstarting a touchless world and recently, caught the attention of popular social media platform, Instagram. Instagram has brought QR codes to the app, allowing users to generate a unique code that will link back to their profiles. However, Instagram is not the only social media powerhouse to adopt this technology. Twitter, Facebook, Snapchat and Spotify all have QR code capabilities, providing a direct, contactless approach to reaching an individual or business profile. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Similarly, we have seen restaurants leverage QR codes beyond the mandatory coronavirus check-in systems. Many restaurants are using the technology to load their menus instead of using paper versions. Not only does this promote contactless dining, but it is also quicker and cheaper for updates to be made, with restaurants not having to invest in reprinting with menu changes and updates. So, in the B2C marketing world, QR codes are becoming commonly adopted, but what about B2B?</span></p>
<h2><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Why are QR Codes of Interest to B2B Marketers?</span></strong></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Many marketing professionals would argue that QR codes have always presented a valuable opportunity for businesses, even before the coronavirus pandemic. One of the technology&#8217;s primary benefits is that it connects non-digital mediums directly to <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">digital marketing</a> channels. For example, an advertisement in a print magazine will most likely have a call-to-action, leading readers to a website. At this stage, if the reader is interested, they would have to get their phone, open a web browser and proceed to enter the URL into the search bar. While this isn&#8217;t a difficult task for many, it can be time-consuming and frustrating if you make any spelling errors. However, with a QR code, the reader simply hovers their camera over the barcode, and they are taken directly to the webpage. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">From a business perspective, this is attractive for many reasons. Firstly, it improves the user experience by reducing the amount of time it would otherwise take to access a website. Secondly, using QR codes gives businesses the ability to report on some basic metrics, which non-digital mediums wouldn&#8217;t otherwise provide. You can access information on how many people scanned the code and what ad they have seen. Ultimately, you can report on what marketing is resonating and optimise future marketing efforts based on these insights. For optimal reporting, link your QR code with Google Analytics through Google&#8217;s free Campaign URL Builder. This will give you a holistic view of your marketing efforts and how everything is performing. </span></p>
<h2><strong><span data-preserver-spaces="true">Should my B2B Organisation be using QR Codes?</span></strong></h2>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">QR codes should only be adopted to provide potential customers with a beneficial move from offline to online communications. If the prospect is not deriving value, we do not recommend using QR codes. Consider the time, place and privacy of your offline marketing. Many years ago, an organisation in the UK had posters with QR codes in the London Underground when there was no Wi-Fi there at the time. Further, someone may not feel comfortable scanning a code in a busy underground. Ensure these factors are considered before implementing QR codes into your marketing.</span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">So, where are QR codes best utilised? As mentioned, only in offline marketing channels. Most B2B organisations use them in print advertising, or on products and packaging. Others <a href="https://blog.jdrgroup.co.uk/digital-prosperity-blog/how-to-use-qr-codes-for-a-b2b-business">include them on their business cards</a>. There are <a href="https://distribion.com/12-creative-b2b-ideas-for-qr-codes/">many ways you can use QR codes</a>. <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-efficiencies/">Depending on your goals</a>, whether it is <a href="/lead-generation/">lead generation</a>, brand awareness, or simply improving the user experience, ensure you identify what you are trying to achieve. Ultimately, they should be used as a <a href="/lead-generation-campaigns-the-importance-of-call-to-actions/">call-to-action</a>, so ensure that your corresponding marketing clearly outlines what you want the prospect to do. The code might lead an opportunity to a lead generation form to download a whitepaper or useful piece of content, or it might be an event registration form. Others use them so prospects can download and save business details such as a <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/digital-marketing-strategy/8-uses-qr-codes-measurable-marketing-campaign/">contact phone number or location</a>. This would be most useful at a tradeshow or expo. </span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">2020 has undeniably seen the unexpected return of the once eroded marketing fad. QR codes certainly have benefits for B2B organisations. The reporting aspect and ability to use Google&#8217;s URL builder to connect to <a href="/how-to-apply-google-analytics-to-increase-your-website-leads/">Google Analytics</a> is a great tool and subsequent tick on the pros and cons list. However, connecting offline media with digital channels is one of the most significant benefits; however, organisations need to address their B2B marketing goals before using technology unnecessarily. For more information on marketing trends, check out our blog: <a href="/b2b-marketing-2021-trends/"><em>B2B Marketing 2021 Trends.</em></a></span></p>
<p><span data-preserver-spaces="true">If you would like more information on this article and how your company can use QR codes or interested in any of our other <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/">B2B marketing services</a>, please contact one of our <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">digital marketing consultants</a>.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/should-your-b2b-organisation-be-using-qr-codes/">Should your B2B Organisation be Using QR Codes?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Create Buyer Personas to Boost Your B2B Marketing</title>
		<link>/how-to-create-buyer-personas-to-boost-your-b2b-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 01:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In order to optimise the performance of any marketing campaign, it is essential to know your target audience. This means going further than demographics to get a real sense of who your buyer is and what drives them. This can be done by building buyer personas. A buyer persona is a research-based profile that depicts [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-create-buyer-personas-to-boost-your-b2b-marketing/">How to Create Buyer Personas to Boost Your B2B Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In order to optimise the performance of any marketing campaign, it is essential to know your target audience. This means going further than demographics to get a real sense of who your buyer is and what drives them. This can be done by building buyer personas.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.socialmediatoday.com/news/what-is-a-buyer-persona-and-why-is-it-important/507404/">A buyer persona is a research-based profile that depicts a target customer.</a> Buyer personas describe who your ideal customers are, what their days are like, the challenges they face, and how they make decisions.</p>
<p>The buyer persona will outline certain features of the target audience, such as their demographics, behaviours, lifestyle, motivations, and challenges. In a B2B context, buyer personas should represent the buyers who are making the ultimate purchasing decision for a company, as well as influencers who have a say in this decision. As such, in many cases, B2B businesses will have more than one buyer persona to target.</p>
<h2>Steps to Creating a Buyer Persona in B2B</h2>
<p>The following are the steps to take to build detailed buyer personas that will help accelerate your marketing campaigns.</p>
<h3>Step 1: Identify Buyer Attributes</h3>
<p>The first step to creating an effective buyer persona is to research the customers that you want to target. When conducting this research, it&#8217;s important to try to get a deeper understanding of your audience in terms of their lifestyle, motivations, challenges, and goals.</p>
<p>There are certain categories that should be included in creating a B2B buyer persona profile:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Demographics:</strong> How old are they? Where is their company based? How big is their company? What industry do they operate in?</li>
<li><strong>Career: </strong>What is their position? How long have they been working in the industry? How long have they been working for their current company? What is their buying power, and how do they make buying decisions?</li>
<li><strong>Lifestyle:</strong> What are the primary duties and responsibilities of their role? Where do they look for information and networking opportunities?</li>
<li><strong>Motivations, Goals &amp; Objectives:</strong> What drives their buying decisions? What goals do they have for their role and the business as a whole?</li>
<li><strong>Pain Points &amp; Challenges:</strong> What work-related problems do they have that they are looking to solve? Are there particular challenges that they face in meeting their goals and objectives?</li>
<li><strong>Objections: </strong>What barriers will you have to overcome to reach a sale? Have they had frustrations with related products or services?</li>
</ul>
<h3>Step 2: Research Ideal Buyers on LinkedIn</h3>
<p>Once you know who your ideal buyers are, it’s time to start researching. <a href="https://www.streamcreative.com/blog/4-ways-marketers-can-use-linkedin-to-build-buyer-personas">LinkedIn is a great tool for online B2B buyer persona research</a>, as it provides an in-depth snapshot of a variety of companies, industries, and individuals. LinkedIn can be used to look up specific employee profiles and gain insight into them. It can be used to discover how long they’ve been in the business or the industry, their education and qualifications, their interests, any specific projects they have been working on, and more.</p>
<p>LinkedIn also gives businesses the opportunity to share articles, connect with others and communicate with other professionals in forums. Forums can also be used to pay attention to what people are saying, which can give your business direction as to their opinions, motivations and challenges.</p>
<h3>Step 3: Research Actual Customers</h3>
<p>Buyer personas are based on actual customers, so getting in touch with these people is important. You should approach your ideal customers one-on-one, asking questions through focus groups, surveys, and interviews. As they work so closely with current buyers, customer-facing employees and sales teams are often a great place to start for getting in touch with these people.In order to plan interview questions, consider the attributes that you want to include in your buyer personas. Try to ensure the interviews are professional and try not to make them too long, as you are speaking to business buyers who are likely to be time-poor.</p>
<h3>Step 4: Use Other Sources of Information</h3>
<p>In addition to interviews, there are a number of digital tools that can be used for data analysis. <a href="https://digitalagencynetwork.com/five-essential-google-analytics-reports-to-understand-your-website-traffic/">Google Analytics can provide a wealth of information, from keyword insights to audience information and data on how they interact with the website</a>. In addition to Analytics, other digital marketing platforms such as Google Ads, Facebook and LinkedIn have data available that provides valuable insights into user behaviour online.</p>
<h3>Step 5: Create the Buyer Personas</h3>
<p>Once the research stage is complete, you can start building your buyer personas. In analysing all of the data you have collected, you will start to see patterns of different buyer personalities. These should be segmented by defined characteristics to create 4-6 buyer personas for your marketing and sales team to work from. For B2B businesses, in particular, it is likely that personas will be segmented by their job title – this may help the marketing team get a better idea of each persona when it comes to creating the campaign.</p>
<p>Each buyer persona should be delivered in a visually appealing format, putting a face to the person you are targeting. It should also articulate key points in a format that is easy to digest for your teams. Further information can be stored in a separate document for those that are interested in diving deeper into the persona.</p>
<h3>Step 6: Adapt Your Marketing Strategies for Your Buyer Personas</h3>
<p>Now that the buyer personas have been created, they can be applied to marketing strategies. These personas should inform all marketing campaigns, and in particular, should <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/content-marketing-personas/290765/">inform content marketing strategies so that content is created based on each persona</a>, and which part of the buying funnel that that persona is at. In addition, your personas may inform the channels that the campaigns are running on and the format that it is delivered in.</p>
<p>Buyer personas can help your marketing team create messages and content that not only gets the attention of your audience but also converts them into buyers. For more information on creating buyer personas for your business, or for wider <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/">B2B marketing</a> help, get in touch with The Lead Agency. We’re experts B2B marketing, offering a range of services including <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">lead generation</a>, and <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-create-buyer-personas-to-boost-your-b2b-marketing/">How to Create Buyer Personas to Boost Your B2B Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should Your B2B Business be Giving Customers Free Content?</title>
		<link>/should-your-b2b-business-be-giving-customers-free-content/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 05:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Developing a competitive B2B content marketing strategy and supporting collateral often requires an investment of time, resources and money. With this in mind, it can be tempting for organisations to pass these costs onto potential or existing customers, such as through charging for access to eBooks or fact sheets. So, why is it then that [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/should-your-b2b-business-be-giving-customers-free-content/">Should Your B2B Business be Giving Customers Free Content?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Developing a competitive <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a> strategy and supporting <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">collateral</a> often requires an investment of time, resources and money.</p>
<p>With this in mind, it can be tempting for organisations to pass these costs onto potential or existing customers, such as through charging for access to eBooks or fact sheets. So, why is it then that so many businesses provide these valuable resources to consumers for free, when they could all too easily do otherwise?</p>
<h2>Free content &amp; the buyer journey</h2>
<p>To understand this, you first need to understand how the B2B buyer journey works. This process is long and complex, with purchases often having to be overseen and approved by a myriad of a business’ staff and/or management. There is usually a lot riding on the final decision and, ultimately, the wrong choice could cost the business greatly.</p>
<p>As such, it makes sense for those making these B2B buying decisions to be thorough when conducting research. By doing this, they can minimise any risks and gain greater confidence that their chosen product or service is in the best interests of the company.</p>
<p>All of this considered, it’s hardly surprising that <a href="https://martechtoday.com/b2b-buyers-consume-an-average-of-13-content-pieces-before-deciding-on-a-vendor-238540#:~:text=A%20mix%20of%20first%20and,required%20to%20seal%20the%20deal.&amp;text=The%20average%20B2B%20buyer's%20journey,from%20market%20research%20firm%20FocusVision.">the average B2B buyer consumes thirteen pieces of content during the purchasing journey</a>. This information provides a pretty clear indication of why so many organisations willingly give their customers and prospects free content, even though they could technically charge them.</p>
<p>An organisation’s key decision makers <em>want</em> to consume content.</p>
<p>When buyers are progressing through such a lengthy purchasing process, paying for the information and content that’s going to aid them in their decision will only act as a barrier. Instead, with useful free content, you can support key decision makers every step of the way, making the entire process easier for them.</p>
<h2>Gain a competitive edge</h2>
<p>When it comes to establishing a competitive advantage as a B2B business, <a href="https://www.businessknowhow.com/marketing/custexp.htm">developing an unmatched customer experience is the most powerful way to do just that</a>.</p>
<p>There are, of course, a plethora of factors that influence a <a href="/improving-the-b2b-customer-experience-with-interactive-content/">customer’s experience</a> with your brand. One aspect of this is how you market your product or service and the support you provide along the way.</p>
<p>The information customers need should be easily accessible and readily available, so that everything they’re after is just a click away. By making this process as seamless as possible, you can capture any initial interest in your offering and move customers through the <a href="/shortening-the-b2b-marketing-sales-funnel/">B2B buying funnel</a>.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>It’s also important to consider how much free content is now online, and whether this is something your competitors also have on offer. If your prospects could just as easily go to your competitors’ websites to find the answers or resources they need to make a final decision – why would they pay for your content?</p>
<h2>Add value to your brand</h2>
<p>Maybe you’ve just spent months writing an eBook, have hired a graphic designer to give it the finishing touches, and plan to invest in promoting it to your audience.</p>
<p>All of this takes time and costs your business money, but choosing not to sell your final product could actually be the best decision you make. While the revenue won’t be shown via a direct transfer of funds into your business’ account, the ongoing benefits you reap in other ways can be abundant.</p>
<p>By providing prospects and customers with this helpful content, you can nurture your leads and existing contacts to guide them through the buyer journey. This added value could be the difference between a potential customer disengaging from your brand or continuing to take in your content over time.</p>
<p>The buyer may still be uncertain, or they may not even need your product or service right now, but by ensuring you stay in touch and make a real impact, when they do eventually need an offering like yours – they’ll think of your business.</p>
<p>By providing free content, you can also reach a larger pool of customers, many of whom probably wouldn’t have downloaded your eBook, fact sheet or the like if there was a cost barrier. This means you can get more people spending longer amounts of time on your website, all of which helps with <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">search engine optimisation</a> and boosting your ranking in Google’s search results.</p>
<h2>Gain more than just sales</h2>
<p>While you may not be directly making revenue from your free content and resources, there’s so much more that you can gain if you leverage them strategically.</p>
<p>Even though you’re not charging money, you can use your eBook, fact sheet, infographic or the like to learn more about your audience. Before downloading your resource, users may need to fill out their details. This form would usually be relatively simple, with fields such as name, email address and company.</p>
<p>While at face value this information may seem insignificant, it can actually be invaluable when it comes to getting leads into the marketing funnel and nurturing them.</p>
<p>With this information, you can send consumers who have expressed clear interest in your product or service more content or communications that are relevant to them. If you have numerous resources targeting different groups, you can also segment your audience and create targeted campaigns, such as through <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">email automation</a>, which nurture consumers and ideally lead them to conversion.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in building a strong <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a> strategy or this article has brought up any questions, <a href="/contact-us/">get in touch with our team</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/should-your-b2b-business-be-giving-customers-free-content/">Should Your B2B Business be Giving Customers Free Content?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Ways to Increase Customer loyalty for B2B</title>
		<link>/7-ways-to-increase-customer-loyalty-for-b2b/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 23:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When we think of customer loyalty, we will typically think of B2C tactics such as points systems, promotions, stamp cards and exclusive offers. While the tactics may differ for B2B, we know how important it is to generate customer loyalty. Acquiring a new customer can cost up to 5 times more than retaining an existing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-ways-to-increase-customer-loyalty-for-b2b/">7 Ways to Increase Customer loyalty for B2B</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When we think of customer loyalty, we will typically think of B2C tactics such as points systems, promotions, stamp cards and exclusive offers. While the tactics may differ for B2B, we know how important it is to generate customer loyalty.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.outboundengine.com/blog/customer-retention-marketing-vs-customer-acquisition-marketing/">Acquiring a new customer can cost up to 5 times more than retaining an existing customer.</a></p>
<p>In addition, <a href="https://referralrock.com/blog/what-is-customer-loyalty/">loyal customers are also more likely to generate referrals</a>. Despite the clear value of customer loyalty, many B2B companies focus their marketing resources on generating leads and acquiring customers rather than keeping their existing ones happy and encouraging repeat purchases.</p>
<p>So we may now know the value of customer loyalty in B2B. But where do we start? The following are some of the most effective tactics for generating customer loyalty in the B2B space.</p>
<h2> 1. Conduct Exit Interviews</h2>
<p>An exit interview is a standard process employed by many B2B sales and marketing teams to reduce the number of lost clients. The two key objectives of an exit interview are to work out what went wrong with a client and make a last-ditch attempt to keep them. The person carrying out the interview should always remember these two objectives. In order to be best positioned for success, it’s important that the person conducting the interview knows the history of their business relationship as well as the person they are talking to and their role within the company. The conversation should be handled like a sales call to try to get the client to reconsider. In the event that this is impossible, the exit interview can be used to gather information and feedback that can be applied to future customers.</p>
<h2> 2. Use Content to Continually Educate Customers</h2>
<p>Customers are more likely to trust and recommend your business if they know more about it. When you are creating your content schedule, consider including content that is relevant to existing customers. For example, share content that describes how to get the most out of your business’ products or services, as well as guides for customers on using the products and services. This type of content is often overlooked in favour of content that addresses the earlier stages of the buyer journey, such as lead generation and customer acquisition.</p>
<h2> 3. Offer Discounts</h2>
<p>This is an often-used B2C loyalty tactic that can also be applied to B2B. B2B businesses also want to save money on their purchases, and as such, <a href="https://www.bigcommerce.com.au/blog/customer-discount/">offering discounts can encourage customers to make a repeat purchase</a>. Be wary that you don’t put your pricing strategy at risk with this tactic and ensure discounts are only offered after thoroughly evaluating how they would be of benefit to the business. If applied incorrectly, discounting products and services can devalue them in the eyes of the customer.</p>
<h2> 4. Superior Account Management</h2>
<p>At its core, customer loyalty comes down to excellent account management. <a href="https://www.tenfold.com/customer-success-reps">Ensuring your customers are happy</a> is what will set you apart from your competitors, which is particularly important if you are operating in a saturated market. In many cases, the business with the best reputation and performance in their niche doesn&#8217;t necessarily have the best product. Rather, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/blakemorgan/2019/12/20/the-10-most-customer-centric-companies-of-2019/?sh=411319187a58">the best performing businesses are the ones that are the most customer-centric</a>. These businesses ensure they are addressing their customers’ needs and problems from the moment they are on-boarded throughout the entire relationship.</p>
<h2> 5. Assign Dedicated Account Managers</h2>
<p>For many businesses, this may be hard to scale, but assigning dedicated account managers to clients will reap the rewards. Dedicated account managers should be assigned to key customers that boost your bottom line and have the potential to refer leads. Having a single person managing the account means that they can offer a completely personalised service that will delight these important customers.</p>
<h2> 6. Run Events for Existing Customers</h2>
<p>In-person or online events can help to generate customer loyalty. Events can be held to introduce product updates, showcase best-practice cases and product success stories, and ask customers for feedback. It can also give you an indication of which customers are most loyal to your business, as only the ones who are interested will attend.</p>
<h2> 7. Surprise Customers</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.canadianbusiness.com/innovation/how-to-surprise-and-delight-your-customers/">Customer loyalty is driven by moments where businesses delight and wow customers</a>. This can be done by surprising them with benefits and rewards that have not been previously advertised or communicated to them. When these things are completely unexpected, they will generate positive feelings that drive beneficial purchase behaviour. While we may not always think so, emotions play a big role in B2B purchase decisions. This is why surprising customers can be such an effective tactic.</p>
<p>These are just some of the ways for your business to get the most out of its existing customers. If you are interested in boosting the value of your customers, our <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B marketing consultants</a> can help. For more information, get in touch with The Lead Agency today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-ways-to-increase-customer-loyalty-for-b2b/">7 Ways to Increase Customer loyalty for B2B</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Email Automation and why should you use it?</title>
		<link>/what-is-email-automation-and-why-should-you-use-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 01:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Email marketing has, for a long time, been a prevalent part of B2B marketing campaigns. However since its inception, it has evolved tremendously. Email marketing technology today gives B2B organisations a platform to deliver relevant content based on customer behaviour and engagement. This is beneficial to both the customer and the business, as customers can [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-is-email-automation-and-why-should-you-use-it/">What is Email Automation and why should you use it?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">Email marketing</a> has, for a long time, been a prevalent part of <a href="/">B2B marketing</a> campaigns. However since its inception, it has evolved tremendously. Email marketing technology today gives B2B organisations a platform to deliver relevant content based on customer behaviour and engagement. This is beneficial to both the customer and the business, as customers can receive information that is relevant and is of interest to them, which in turn, increases their retention.</p>
<p>Given the long sales cycles in the B2B world, the majority of the leads received by any organisation are likely not ready to make a purchase decision. This is a very topical discussion for B2B organisations, as often <a href="/bridging-the-gap-between-b2b-marketing-and-sales/">gaps between sales and marketing teams</a> mean that these leads are never followed up or nurtured. So, how do we <a href="/how-to-nurture-leads-with-b2b-marketing-automation/">nurture those leads</a> to ensure that in 9 months-time, when they are ready, your business is front of mind? The answer is (unsurprisingly given the title of this blog), email marketing automation.</p>
<h2>What is Email Automation?</h2>
<blockquote><p><em>Email automation is a way to create emails that reach the right people with the right message at the right moment—without doing the work every time. When you link your website analytics with your email marketing platform, you can target people based on behaviour, preferences, and previous sales. Then you can personalize each customer’s experience and increase the relevance of your messaging &#8211; </em><em><a href="https://mailchimp.com/marketing-glossary/email-automation/#:~:text=Email%20automation%20is%20a%20way,%2C%20preferences%2C%20and%20previous%20sales.">Mailchimp</a></em><em style="color: #555555;"> </em></p></blockquote>
<h2>Why Your Business Should Use Email Automation</h2>
<h3>1. Increase customer retention by optimising your campaigns</h3>
<p>Email automation increases customer retention through personalisation, optimisation and effective lead nurturing. With email automation the personalisation aspect transcends beyond their first name. You can set up engagement metrics to determine what content particular individuals interact with so you can provide them with more of that information, preventing unsubscribes or unhappy customers. With automation, all of this would be done for you (once you set it up, of course), giving you more time to optimise the automation flows for continued success. Hubspot reported this year that <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">80% of business professionals</a> believe that email marketing increases customer retention. <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">59% of respondents</a> say marketing emails influence their purchase decisions. And finally, marketers who use segmented campaigns note as much as a <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">760% increase in revenue</a>.</p>
<h3>2. Deliver content for up-sell/cross-sell opportunities</h3>
<p>Email marketing and automation gives your organisation a platform to deliver newsletters with new and industry relevant case studies, blogs and other forms of content. This not only gives you a reason to reach out to your customer base, but an opportunity to maximise promotion activities around the content that your organisation is likely paying to produce and further, to position your organisation as a thought leader.</p>
<p>It is much easier and more effective to <a href="https://mailchimp.com/marketing-glossary/email-automation/#:~:text=Email%20automation%20is%20a%20way,%2C%20preferences%2C%20and%20previous%20sales.">sell to an existing customer</a> through <a href="/enhanced-customer-experience-cross-selling-b2b-marketing/">cross-sell or up-sell opportunities</a>, than to convert a new one. Many B2B organisations find it difficult to stay in touch with all of their customers effectively. With automation, organisations can rest easy knowing that their customers are being nurtured and further, they are doing so with information that is relevant and of interest to each customer.</p>
<h3>3. Make the most of your marketing team</h3>
<p>Automation is changing the way that B2B organisations do business. Marketing teams’ efforts are better placed in analysing customer behaviour for optimisation and managing other inbound activities, rather than the manual labour that is involved in setting up email campaigns. According to a 2017 survey of information workers, respondents said they believe email automation can improve employee productivity:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.smartsheet.com/content-center/executive-center/2017-automation-report">69% said automation</a> could help reduce wasted time.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.smartsheet.com/content-center/executive-center/2017-automation-report">59% said that they could save at least 6 hours a week</a> if the repetitive aspects of their job were automated.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.smartsheet.com/content-center/executive-center/2017-automation-report">72% said that they would use the time</a> they saved to focus on higher-value work.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">Email automation</a> is very topical right now in the B2B marketing world. With digital marketing at the forefront of B2B marketing strategies, given the effects of the pandemic, many marketers have turned to email to stay in touch with customers in a relevant and effective way. Beyond the opportunities to increase customer retention, it also represents a platform to maximise promotion on content syndication activities for cross-sell and/or up-sell enablement.</p>
<p>If you have any questions or would like more information on this article, please <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">contact one of our digital experts</a>. Most importantly, we hope you are staying safe and well during these tough times.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-is-email-automation-and-why-should-you-use-it/">What is Email Automation and why should you use it?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Steps to an Effective Guest Blogging Strategy</title>
		<link>/3-steps-to-an-effective-guest-blogging-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 23:50:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Guest blogging is a digital marketing tactic that can position a business as a thought leader by increasing brand credibility and awareness. It can also boost a website’s SEO. Guest blogging attracts traffic to a website and boosts domain authority as it generates external links from high-authority domains. Like other digital marketing strategies, guest blogging [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-steps-to-an-effective-guest-blogging-strategy/">3 Steps to an Effective Guest Blogging Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Guest blogging is a digital marketing tactic that can position a business as a thought leader by increasing brand credibility and awareness. It can also boost a website’s SEO. Guest blogging attracts traffic to a website and boosts domain authority as it generates external links from high-authority domains.</p>
<p>Like other digital marketing strategies, guest blogging has to be done well in order to be effective. <a href="https://komarketing.com/industry-news/creating-engaging-content-priority-challenge-b2b-marketers-2675/">57% of B2B marketers say they struggle with producing content consistently</a>, yet they know the value of having regular content posted to their site. So, more and more businesses are open to accepting guest blog posts. However, while blogs are open to accepting guest posts, <a href="https://blog.red-website-design.co.uk/2018/10/09/guest-blogging-stats-infographic/">56% of editors say that content they receive isn’t a fit for their blog readers</a> and <a href="https://www.impactplus.com/blog/ways-to-improve-your-content-pitches-to-editors">79% of editors say that guest posts they receive are too promotional</a>.</p>
<p>They key to effective guest blogging is to ensure the websites you approach are happy to showcase your content as it adds value to their audience. Follow our 3 steps to guest blogging to find out how.</p>
<h2>Step 1: Find Relevant Guest Blogging Opportunities<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>An effective guest blogging strategy starts with finding the right blogs to target. When looking for places to guest post, the main goal is to find sites relevant to your niche or industry.</p>
<p>The following are some ways to find the right kind of guest post opportunities.</p>
<h3>1. Conduct a Google Search</h3>
<p>Use any of the following keyword searches to find blogs that accept guest posts. Just replace ‘keyword’ with keywords on the industry topics that you want to write about.</p>
<ul>
<li>keyword “submit a guest post”</li>
<li>keyword “guest post”</li>
<li>keyword “guest post by”</li>
<li>keyword “accepting guest posts”</li>
<li>keyword “guest post guidelines”</li>
</ul>
<p>These searches should lead you to a blog’s guest post guidelines page, guest post submission page, or actual guest posts by other writers.</p>
<h3>2. Keep an Eye Out For Prolific Guest Bloggers</h3>
<p>If you read the blogs in your industry, you will start to see the same author names come up regularly. You can use this to find guest blogging opportunities by search for their name plus the phrase “guest post by”. This will give you a list of sites that these guest bloggers have posted on. You can then approach the site to ask for an opportunity to write a post for them.</p>
<h3>3. Investigate Competitor Backlinks</h3>
<p>Carrying out a backlink analysis of a competitor website is an effective method of discovering the backlinks they have received from the guest posts that they have written. Tools like Open Site Explorer &amp; Ahrefs are ideal for this. Alternatively, try a Google search for link:domain.com -domain.com “guest post,” replacing domain.com with your competitor’s domain name.</p>
<h3>4. Source Guest Blog Lists</h3>
<p>With a simple Google search, you may be able to find lists or websites that accept guest blogs. The following may be a good starting point:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.buzzblogger.com/500-places-to-syndicate-your-content/">500 places to syndicate content</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bestinau.com.au/guest-posting-sites/">100 sites to submit guest posts</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Step 2: Pitch a Guest Post</h2>
<p>Once you have a list of blogs to approach, the next step is to approach them with your pitch. Get to know your target blog’s content before getting in touch with the company. Look at other guest blogs they have posted for the type of content and the author, and try to identify which blogs are the most popular in terms of comments and interactions. This will give you an idea of what to pitch to them.</p>
<p>Best practices for pitching a guest post:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure you read the blog guidelines before getting in touch so that your pitch can follow the relevant guidelines.</li>
<li>Personalise the email by including their name and a comment on their specific content and why you should write for them.</li>
<li>Introduce yourself – let them know who you are and what value you can add to their blog.</li>
<li>Pitch a few different ideas and suggested blog titles so the blog owner has some options to choose from.</li>
</ul>
<p>If the person that you contact does not respond immediately, ensure you follow up on your original email. One or two follow up emails within a couple of weeks of the original email can be effective in prompting them to respond.</p>
<h2>Step 3: Write the Guest Post</h2>
<p>If you receive a positive response from the website owner, you have already done most of the hard work. Now, all you have to do is write the guest post. They will typically come back with a number of guidelines. It is important that you adhere to these guidelines, otherwise they are unlikely to post the blog.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure you follow any guidelines you have been given.</li>
<li>Try to include a few internal links back to some of their posts.</li>
<li>Include a call to action for comments to try to generate discussion.</li>
<li>Include your guest bio. This is one of the key elements of your guest blog and should</li>
<li>Include a link back to your website with your target anchor text</li>
<li>Add information for your social accounts</li>
</ul>
<p>Once your guest blog is posted, your website will receive a backlink and you can track any visits generated through the post using Google Analytics.</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we’re experts in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B Digital Marketing</a>. Contact Us for more information on guest blogging, or for advice on the most up to date <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO strategies</a> to boost your website’s ranking on the SERPs and ensure your business continues to drive traffic that turns into viable leads and sales.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-steps-to-an-effective-guest-blogging-strategy/">3 Steps to an Effective Guest Blogging Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Revising Your B2B Marketing Strategy Post-Pandemic.</title>
		<link>/revising-your-b2b-marketing-strategy-post-pandemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 03:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There is no denying that the COVID-19 pandemic has, and will continue to fundamentally change business behaviour as the way we live, work, and buy has been dramatically rewritten. While shifting demands inevitably pose a challenge for both businesses and marketers, it also represents an opportunity to learn and redesign marketing strategies to not only [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/revising-your-b2b-marketing-strategy-post-pandemic/">Revising Your B2B Marketing Strategy Post-Pandemic.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no denying that the COVID-19 pandemic has, and will continue to <a href="https://smallbusinessconnections.com.au/time-to-rewire-your-marketing-strategy-for-a-post-pandemic-world/">fundamentally change business behaviour</a> as the way we live, work, and buy has been dramatically rewritten. While shifting demands inevitably pose a challenge for both businesses and marketers, it also represents an opportunity to learn and redesign marketing strategies to not only optimise and adapt to changing business conditions, but to become more resilient and future-proofed for a post-pandemic world.</p>
<blockquote><p>Now more than ever, business-to-business (B2B) companies need to rethink their sales and marketing strategies for a post-coronavirus world, where “normal” is set to take on a new meaning. The ensuing approach must be agile and cost-effective to meet the demands of the future &#8211; <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescommunicationscouncil/2020/07/16/four-marketing-and-sales-strategies-for-the-post-pandemic-business/#2ab554cc5849">Forbes</a></p></blockquote>
<p>So, as we navigate the ‘new normal’, how can we power our <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B marketing</a> strategies for a post-pandemic world?</p>
<h3>Lead with Data</h3>
<p>We all understand that knowledge is power, so <a href="/leveraging-data-and-creativity-to-achieve-outstanding-b2b-digital-marketing-outcomes/">leading with data</a> is crucial to building and executing successful B2B marketing strategies. Data-driven marketing <a href="https://www.adverity.com/data-driven-marketing/">optimises brand communications based on customer information</a>. Marketers should leverage this insight to develop more personalised strategies for a higher return on investment. Further, <a href="/data-is-king/">data-driven marketing</a> builds credibility with customers as they are receiving information that is useful and relevant to their situation. Improved data and insight is crucial in business response and recovery, and with businesses finding themselves in unfamiliar waters, marketers must focus on data-driven marketing strategies to be able to provide value to customers.</p>
<h3>Importance of B2B Relationships</h3>
<p>COVID-19 has forced sales teams to maintain and build on their relationships with clients, and this should be the key priority for B2B organisations during this time.  Even businesses that have not been as significantly affected have had to change how they operate, to both protect the health of their employees and to be empathetic to their clients and partners.</p>
<p>Building trust and recognition with your customers is critical in your survival, post pandemic. 2020 has highlighted the importance of <a href="/leveraging-client-relationships-building-a-strong-referral-program/">managing and maintaining strong B2B relationships</a> and in many cases, has forced sales executives to reach out to their clients without a sales agenda. This shift in sales behaviour will, hopefully, transcend post-pandemic and give those individuals the opportunity to build on their relationships with their clients.</p>
<h3>Embracing Digitization</h3>
<p>As we move towards the next ‘normal’, it is crucial for B2B marketers to harness digital transformation strategies to secure their success. Digital centricity will be key to continuing the momentum, with a particularly strong focus on content and social media but further, to optimise your efforts and gain insight into customer behaviours and new audiences. COVID-19 has forced many marketers to shift their effort from primarily outbound saturated strategies towards inbound opportunities.</p>
<h3>Adapt to Shifting Customer Demands</h3>
<p>The way that we reach our customers has changed and may, in many cases, never be the same. Marketers have had to operate with a degree of sensitivity, recognising that many individuals and businesses are doing it tough. Subsequently, we have to re-evaluate our current <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategies</a> to firstly, ensure we are operating with compassion but secondly, to ensure they are a good fit for your customer. Further, post COVID-19, the messaging we use will need to understand the persona of the new customer, post pandemic. By tapping into your consumers’ purchase decisions today, businesses can gain actionable insight, develop a profitable sales strategy and adapt to the new hybrid consumer culture.</p>
<p>COVID-19 has shaken the world. The B2B culture has changed and may never be the same. Businesses have had to operate with sensitivity and compassion first and prioritise this over getting the next deal over the line. The last six months has been about maintaining and building strong relationships, operating with compassion and sensitivity, learning more about target audiences and their shifting demands and how we can meet our customers where they are. While the pandemic has left B2B organisations with no choice but to do so, all of these things should continue to form a significant and important part of our <a href="/b2b-marketing-2021-trends/">marketing and sales strategies in 2021,</a> regardless of where we stand in the pandemic. While this year has been tough on organisations and individuals alike, hopefully the way we have pivoted and operated informs how operate post-pandemic and that we continue to learn and grow to unlock our full B2B potential.</p>
<p>To learn more about this article, contact one of our <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">digital marketing specialists</a>. Most importantly, we hope you are staying safe and well during these tough times.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/revising-your-b2b-marketing-strategy-post-pandemic/">Revising Your B2B Marketing Strategy Post-Pandemic.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
