<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Technology Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/technology-marketing-blogs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 07:12:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Technology Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>3 Actionable Strategies for Marketing to the Technology Sector</title>
		<link>/3-actionable-strategies-for-marketing-to-the-technology-sector/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 23:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a technology company, you’re constantly working to get ahead of the game. In an industry flooded with competition and the ever-persistent need for innovation, it can be easy to get left behind. For your business to remain viable, you need to be continually striving for improvement, all the while finding new ways to surprise [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-actionable-strategies-for-marketing-to-the-technology-sector/">3 Actionable Strategies for Marketing to the Technology Sector</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a technology company, you’re constantly working to get ahead of the game. In an industry flooded with competition and the ever-persistent need for innovation, it can be easy to get left behind.</p>
<p>For your business to remain viable, you need to be continually striving for improvement, all the while finding new ways to surprise and delight customers. However, if the right people aren’t aware of your brilliant product and how it can benefit them, breaking through the clutter will likely be difficult. This is where constructing a comprehensive, effective <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a> strategy comes into play.</p>
<p>With <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a>, you can give your exceptional products the attention they deserve.</p>
<h2>1. Leverage Influencer Marketing</h2>
<p>When making a purchase from the technology sector, consumers often don’t have extensive, in-depth knowledge of different technical features of the product.</p>
<p>It’s for this reason that, before making a decision, prospects will usually research the technology that they’re interested in online, seeking out expert opinions. In fact, <a href="https://tubularinsights.com/64-percent-consumers-youtube-to-review-electronics-purchase/">64% of consumers</a> use YouTube to review electronics before making a buying decision, and after watching a video, <a href="https://tubularinsights.com/consumers-purchase-video/">73% of people complete a purchase</a>. By incorporating influencer marketing into your current strategy, you can capture this considerable purchase intent.</p>
<p>If you want to achieve exceptional results with influencer marketing, and importantly avoid undermining your brand’s integrity, choosing the right person to promote your offerings is crucial. Thus, you will need to carefully consider who you reach out to by ensuring they’re a well-known, reputable individual in your sector.</p>
<p>The influencer who partakes in the endorsement will likely be seen as a direct reflection on your brand, so ensuring they complement your core values is incredibly important. Similarly, if the individual isn’t perceived as being particularly established in the area, or it’s doubtful they would actually use the product, their promotion may be viewed as disingenuous. This may also be the case if you fail to disclose that your partnership is, in fact, an advertisement.</p>
<h2>2. Make an Impact with Event Marketing</h2>
<p><a href="https://blog.intellyo.com/content-marketing/content-marketingand-best-marketing-strategies-for-tech-companies">Event marketing</a> can be particularly effective in the technology sector, as individuals get to actually experience your product, which can help to lower any uncertainties that they have.</p>
<p>When hosting an event, you have the opportunity to make a lasting impression, all the while showcasing your expertise in an exciting way. In addition to this, you can introduce customers to the industry experts behind your brand, giving your thought leaders a platform to demonstrate their proficiency. This can also be a great chance for members of your organisation to network and develop valuable relationships with prospects and other specialists.</p>
<p>Technology can be highly advanced and difficult to understand, but with events, you can alleviate a layer of the complexity. Whether you’re shining a light on an incredible new product or delivering exclusive insights into future innovations, events can work wonders for your brand.</p>
<p>With events, you can display your true dedication to creating exceptional, forward-thinking technology products in a way that people will remember.</p>
<h2>3. Nurture Leads With Marketing Automations</h2>
<p>The buying process of B2B businesses is often long and complex. Typically, this is because there are numerous individuals involved in the decision-making process, and in large organisations, there’s a clear, extensive process that must be followed. In cases where the technology you’re selling is advanced, expensive or the like, this only prolongs the amount of time it takes for prospects to convert.</p>
<p>For this reason, it’s crucial that you effectively capture any initial interest in your offering and nurture leads during each stage of the sales cycle. This can seem overwhelming, as driving results can involve a significant time and a notable investment of resources. <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">Marketing automations</a> can be a great way to keep prospects engaged and interested in your brand, without breaking the bank.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://digitalmarketinginstitute.com/en-au/blog/the-ultimate-guide-to-marketing-automation"><em>44% of marketing leaders</em></a><em> believe automation will become more important as a skill in 2020.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>By integrating <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">marketing automation</a> capabilities into your <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a> strategy, you can optimise your processes; improving efficiencies, and giving you more time to focus on qualified leads. In addition to this, regularly emailing those in your sales funnel gives you the opportunity to further educate potential consumers on your offering, which can reduce doubts that may otherwise deter them from following through with a purchase.</p>
<p>That being said, it’s important to get the frequency of your emails right. When overwhelmed with an excessive number of emails, <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/294162">69% of users unsubscribe</a>. However, if individuals only hear from you once every six months, your offering may no longer be relevant to their current needs. Of course, the number of times you email will depend on your unique brand circumstances and context, but as a general guide, scheduling one email each week will likely suffice.</p>
<p>With targeted, strategic marketing automations in place to nurture prospects at every stage of the buyer journey, your technology business can drive leads and optimise your sales funnel.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in improving the effectiveness of your technology marketing strategy, get in touch with the Lead Agency today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-actionable-strategies-for-marketing-to-the-technology-sector/">3 Actionable Strategies for Marketing to the Technology Sector</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Marketing Strategies to Help Your B2B Technology Business Make a Lasting Impact</title>
		<link>/3-marketing-strategies-to-help-your-b2b-technology-business-make-a-lasting-impact/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 22:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The technology sector is incredibly fast-paced, with new innovations and opportunities surfacing daily. This rapid progression is forecast to continue and, thus, it is vital that you are prepared to evolve as required. It’s no surprise that organisations that accurately define their target audience’s needs and are responsive to the shifting market will most probably [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-marketing-strategies-to-help-your-b2b-technology-business-make-a-lasting-impact/">3 Marketing Strategies to Help Your B2B Technology Business Make a Lasting Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The technology sector is incredibly fast-paced, with new innovations and opportunities surfacing daily. This rapid progression is forecast to continue and, thus, it is vital that you are prepared to evolve as required.</p>
<p>It’s no surprise that organisations that accurately define their target audience’s needs and are responsive to the shifting market will most probably be those who excel.</p>
<p>In a bid to remain relevant in an ever-changing business landscape, you’re likely working diligently to improve and advance your offering. But, while this is undeniably important, it’s also crucial to consider whether you are backing your marketing efforts with the same dedication.</p>
<p>The sales funnel is at the centre of a technology business’s success. If a company is unable to reach promising members of their target audience in meaningful ways, they will experience great difficulty when trying to achieve their organisational goals. <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/279643">More than 50%</a> of B2B technology start-ups experience ongoing difficulty when trying to generate more leads. If you can overcome this challenge, you have the opportunity to outperform competitors and take your business to new heights.</p>
<p>As a technology business, you need to engage your audience in new, exciting ways, differentiating your brand and leaving a memorable impact. A systematic, comprehensive <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a> can help you do just that.</p>
<p>Accomplish your goals, and maybe even surpass them, by giving these exceptional <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a> strategies a try today.</p>
<h2>1. Share Engaging Video Content</h2>
<p>Video <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content</a> is becoming an increasingly prevalent component of many business marketing strategies &#8211; but why?</p>
<p>While reading an entire document may seem tiresome, often, watching a short video can appear far less daunting. This is because audio visual content requires little effort to view and is generally perceived as captivating or entertaining, which attracts a customer’s attention.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“73% of B2B marketers report positive ROI results from video content.” &#8211; </em><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/video-marketing-statistics"><em>HubSpot</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>Research suggests that <a href="https://synecticsmedia.com/7-powerful-benefits-of-video-content-marketing">74% of the users who watch explainer videos</a> go on to purchase the product they viewed. Thus, content of this form has the potential to generate exceptional results for your business when done right.</p>
<p>When incorporating video content in your marketing strategy, there is an abundance of variations you can decide between. This isn’t a one size fits all approach, so while you can gain inspiration from other companies, it’s crucial that you still convey your business’s <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branding</a> and core message clearly. At the end of the day, it’s all about delivering real value to prospects in an interesting, easily comprehendible way.</p>
<p>Not sure where to begin? Why not give one of the following a try:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing great stories that inspire;</li>
<li>Fun videos that convey your brand’s personality;</li>
<li>Informative, useful content;</li>
<li>Client testimonials;</li>
<li>Animated infographics and explainer videos.</li>
</ul>
<h2>2. Boost Your Credibility With Influencer Marketing</h2>
<p>If you advocate for your brand, assuring prospects you’ve created a phenomenal offering that they’ll love, what’s going to make them believe you?</p>
<p>When companies market a product, it’s highly unlikely they’ll make a point of highlighting its downfalls. Customers get this, so when organisations endorse their own product or service, they’ll often take what’s being said with a grain of salt. This is where influencer marketing comes into the picture.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://business.linkedin.com/content/dam/business/sales-solutions/global/en_US/c/pdfs/n/linkedin-the-new-formula-for-connecting-with-b2b-buyers.pdf"><em>72% of technology buyers</em></a><em> look to industry peers while researching relevant content for B2B purchase decisions.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>By effectively integrating influencer marketing techniques into their strategy, businesses can establish greater credibility, all the while generating more brand awareness. For this approach to reap exceptional results, however, it’s vital that you carefully consider which influencers your business works with.</p>
<p>When determining which influencer is right for your brand, you may benefit from asking yourself the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Is the individual respectable in your area of expertise?</li>
<li>Who makes up the individual’s target audience?</li>
<li>Does the individual have a strong, positive reputation?</li>
<li>Are you happy to be associated with their actions and beliefs?</li>
<li>How much are you willing to spend?</li>
<li>Where is the individual located and how expansive is their reach?</li>
</ul>
<h2>3. Incorporate Interactive Tools and Experiences</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7524" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" />Interacting with customers is a great way to boost engagement and build connections that are both personal and memorable. This can, in turn, assist your technology business in acquiring high-quality leads that are actually invested in your brand and what you’ve got to offer.</p>
<p>For instance, you may create a quiz on your website where consumers identify their particular needs and priorities. Then, once submitted, participants receive an evaluation of which of your offerings would likely be best suited to their needs. You’re giving prospects an individual experience that’s tailored to them, while also aiding them in the decision-making process.</p>
<p>In many cases, interactive content can be a valuable point of differentiation that encourages potential customers to consider a brand further, or even make a purchase.</p>
<p>Want to find out more about marketing in the technology sector? At the Lead Agency, we can get your business up-to-date on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, so you can proactively plan for future success. Take your <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a> strategy to new heights by speaking with one of our <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> experts today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-marketing-strategies-to-help-your-b2b-technology-business-make-a-lasting-impact/">3 Marketing Strategies to Help Your B2B Technology Business Make a Lasting Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimise Your Website For Mobile Devices</title>
		<link>/optimise-your-website-for-mobile-devices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 06:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With over 17 million smartphone users Australia-wide, if you’re yet to optimise your website for mobile, now is the time. The mobile market is expanding at speed and, if you’re unresponsive to this change, you’ll likely lose an abundance of potential leads. “When someone is mobile, they’re expecting an entirely different experience from the one [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimise-your-website-for-mobile-devices/">Optimise Your Website For Mobile Devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With over <a href="https://www.bankmycell.com/blog/how-many-phones-are-in-the-world">17 million</a> smartphone users Australia-wide, if you’re yet to optimise your website for mobile, now is the time. The mobile market is expanding at speed and, if you’re unresponsive to this change, you’ll likely lose an abundance of potential leads.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“When someone is mobile, they’re expecting an entirely different experience from the one they’ll get on your standard website” – </em><a href="https://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/9-tips-for-optimizing-your-website-for-mobile-users/"><em>Social Media Examiner</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>When navigating your website on a mobile device, people do so in an entirely different way than those using a desktop. This is because, typically, a mobile visitor is searching for the core information about your business, such as a click-to-call phone number or store location.</p>
<p>While lengthy content delving into the intricacies of your product, service or people may be sought after by desktop users, often, when converted onto the small screen of mobile this text can become overwhelming. It’s important that, when optimising your website for mobile, you keep this in mind and ensure your layout and formatting is user-friendly.</p>
<p>Improving the accessibility of your digital domains across numerous devices that all have different screen sizes doesn’t have to be difficult. In fact, by following a few core tips you can get your website up and running on mobile devices and start reaping the benefits in no time.</p>
<h2>Get Your WordPress Theme Right</h2>
<p>It’s important that, when designing your website, the WordPress theme you select is responsive to mobile devices.</p>
<p>Although most available themes are now optimised for use across numerous screen variations, this is still a crucial step in creating your website. It’s a simple way for you to form a reliable foundation and ensure that your content can be properly rendered, regardless of the device being used. When deciding on a WordPress theme you can also preview how your website will appear on each device and make any required adjustments.</p>
<p>After selecting a secure, responsive theme, you’ll be able to customise your website as you please. While designing an appealing and stylish online domain should, of course, be a priority it’s also essential to consider how your layout and content will adapt on different devices. When it comes to mobile, focus on minimising clutter and maximising functionality.</p>
<p>Finding the right responsive theme for your business may take some time but, in the end, having an optimised, high-quality website will likely benefit you immensely.</p>
<h2>Keep Your Site’s Loading Times Low</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7592" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Site-Loading-Time.png" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Site-Loading-Time.png 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Site-Loading-Time-450x185.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Site-Loading-Time-768x316.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>Generally, smartphones don’t have the same loading capabilities as desktops. A delay that is hardly noticeable on a desktop could be <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jaysondemers/2018/04/06/the-7-most-important-factors-for-mobile-optimization/#20016cd21f25">significantly magnified</a> on a mobile device. Even though a loading interruption of a few seconds may not seem like much, it may be all it takes for users to abandon their efforts.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“There are 3 billion people with smartphones, and 1.3 billion who own computers” – </em><a href="https://www.dreamhost.com/blog/how-to-optimize-your-site-for-mobile/"><em>DreamHost</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>With such a large proportion of today’s consumers turning to smartphones, if your website takes an excessive amount of time to load on mobile devices, this could be detrimental to your success. By reducing the amount of content on your loading pages, using a reliable caching plugin and the like, you can improve loading capabilities. In doing this, you’ll be removing potential barriers from the consumer experience that may have otherwise deterred them from inquiring further.</p>
<h2>Feedback is Key</h2>
<p>Once your website has been finalised, testing its functionality is crucial. You need to determine whether it is, in fact, optimised for usage across several different devices, and there are various ways that you can do this.</p>
<p>Typically, the simplest and quickest approach is to navigate the website using your own mobile device. By doing this, you can efficiently and effectively identify any obvious mistakes or flaws in your current website’s compatibility with mobile screens. However, to ensure that your website is reliably responsive it would be suggested that you take further precautions.</p>
<p>When determining whether your site is optimised for smartphone usage, Google’s mobile-friendly tool can come in particularly helpful. This free resource is dedicated to testing your website’s responsiveness across screens. All you need to contribute is your URL, and this tool will explicitly identify any issues that are preventing your website from being optimised on mobile.</p>
<p>Is your text too small to read, or are your clickable elements too close together? With Google’s mobile-friendly tool, you can find out.</p>
<p>Your business’ prospects and consumers are the people who will actually be viewing your website so, even if it appears to be completely functional, you should seek their feedback. This will provide you with ongoing confirmation that your website’s performance is satisfactory, while also allowing you to improve the customer experience.</p>
<h2>Optimise Your Website For Mobile Today</h2>
<p>In an increasingly competitive and volatile market, improving the accessibility of your website on mobile devices has never been more important. At the Lead Agency, we have extensive experience building secure, responsive digital domains. For more information, or to speak with a <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> expert, <a href="/contact-us/">get in touch</a> with our proficient team today.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget to check out the other industries that we operate in at The Lead Agency: <a href="/education-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimise-your-website-for-mobile-devices/">Optimise Your Website For Mobile Devices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Ways to Market Your Tech Company</title>
		<link>/4-ways-to-market-your-tech-company/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital innovations are transforming businesses across industries; changing the way they operate and reshaping the economy. According to IDC, businesses are entering a future dominated by the &#8220;digital transformation economy&#8221;. The premier global provider of market intelligence and advisory services, IDC predicted that by 2020, half of the top 500 companies in Australia will become [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/4-ways-to-market-your-tech-company/">4 Ways to Market Your Tech Company</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital innovations are transforming businesses across industries; changing the way they operate and reshaping the economy. According to <a href="https://www.idc.com/">IDC</a>, businesses are entering a future dominated by the &#8220;digital transformation economy&#8221;.</p>
<p>The premier global provider of market intelligence and advisory services, IDC predicted that <a href="https://www.arnnet.com.au/slideshow/613709/idc-top-10-it-industry-predictions-australia/">by 2020, half of the top 500 companies in Australia</a> will become part of the digital transformation economy, as they see the majority of their business depend on their ability to create digitally enhanced products, services, and experiences.</p>
<p>With such focus on the products and services that tech companies provide, it is vital that companies in the sector position their brand in a way that stands out from the competition.</p>
<p>Tech companies use <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing</a> tactics to build their brand and generate demand for their products and services. But with heavy competition in the sector, it is vital that technology marketers differentiate their products and services from their competitors.</p>
<h2><strong> </strong><strong>Why IT Marketing is so Difficult<br />
</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>Standing out in the Crowd</strong></h3>
<p>Barriers to entry in the IT sector are getting lower and as such, the technology marketplace is becoming crowded. Growth in the sector is showing no signs of slowing down, so having a strong brand, good positioning and clear value proposition is vital.</p>
<p>In order to differentiate themselves, IT marketers have to find a way to communicate how they <a href="https://blog.goldenspiralmarketing.com/prove-your-problem-solving-ability-first-impressions-of-a-technology-website-part-3">solve consumer problems</a>, rather than simply promoting a product. As such, they have to match the features of their product with the needs of the market to show how their products and services can add value to the customer.</p>
<h3><strong>Getting Noticed by Decision Makers</strong></h3>
<p>As mentioned above, the crowded marketplace is creating major problems for IT marketers. Not only do they have to find a way to differentiate their product but they also have to get the message out there. With such high competition, this can require a significant marketing budget. In order to get noticed, tech marketers have to drive awareness and demand for their technology solutions through a range of channels such as Search Engine Marketing, Display Advertising, Remarketing, Social Media Trade Shows, and PR efforts.</p>
<h3><strong>Mastering Marketing Technology Tools</strong></h3>
<p>Today’s companies use <a href="https://www.leadspace.com/challenges-facing-b2b-martech/">an average of 16</a> different marketing technologies and tech marketers typically need to stay ahead of the curve. Your competitors are doing it and you don’t want to be left behind, so it’s important to ensure you are active on the important channels for your business. IT marketing teams have to be technology-savvy and find the right tools and solutions to meet their objectives.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Solve Tech Marketing Challenges</strong></h2>
<p>As a technology marketer, there are numerous channels, strategies and tactics available to help you overcome these challenges. The most effective strategies for your company will, of course, depend on your unique goals and objectives as well as your team’s skills and resources. However, the following are some best practices for an IT marketing campaign.</p>
<h3><strong>Develop a Content Marketing Program</strong></h3>
<p>For each dollar spent, content marketing produces <a href="https://www.oracle.com/marketingcloud/products/marketing-automation/index.html">three times more leads</a> than paid search.</p>
<p>Content marketing helps you to create, nurture, and grow your customer base by influencing buyer behaviour and ultimately motivating action. Effective content marketing will help you establish relevance and build relationships with your target market. It also allows you to communicate your brand and value proposition, which can help you differentiate your offering and stand out in the crowded market.</p>
<h3><strong>Leverage Marketing Automation</strong></h3>
<p>Marketing automation is a software program that can automate repetitive marketing tasks in order to generate leads for your tech business more efficiently. It incorporates email marketing, CRM, lead nurturing, lead scoring, and contact management, and has been proven to significantly increase a company’s performance. According to Forrester Research, B2B marketers who implemented marketing automation software increased their sales pipeline by <a href="https://www.forrester.com/The+Forrester+Wave+LeadToRevenue+Management+Platform+Vendors+Q1+2014/fulltext/-/E-RES95221">an average of 10%</a>. Another study conducted by Forrester reported that companies that excel in lead nurturing generated <a href="http://blog.autopilothq.com/marketing-automation-statistics/">50% more sales-ready leads</a>.</p>
<p>IT marketers should understand the impact that marketing automation can have on their lead generation campaigns and take steps to leverage this tactic.</p>
<h3><strong>Engage with Social Media</strong></h3>
<p>Social media is one of the most effective ways of communicating with your target market as it helps to share your message and culture, and articulate the value of your products and services. The real beauty of Social Media is that, unlike most other channels, it gives your audience the opportunity to interact with you and have a two-way conversation.</p>
<h3><strong>Ensure Your Marketing is Integrated </strong></h3>
<p>IT marketing is complex as technology companies typically experience long sales cycles. As such, your marketing strategy has to engage them for a prolonged period of time. In order to do this, your strategy should incorporate many touch points and make use of multiple channels. An <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/traffic-building-strategy/integrated-marketing-communications/what-is-integrated-marketing/">integrated marketing</a> strategy ensures your business presents a consistent brand image and user experience across all the channels that you use.</p>
<p>An integrated marketing approach keeps you in contact with current customers and prospects from beginning to end. Forrester Research reported that <a href="http://www.sitecore.net/en/resources/index/analyst-reports/forrester-multichannel-maturity-mandate">86% of marketing professionals</a> believe their long-term success is dependant on successfully integrating multiple channels under a single integrated marketing strategy.</p>
<p>The above best practices are just some of the things that you can do to improve your <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing</a>, however, the list of strategies, tactics and channels is exhaustive. If your business doesn&#8217;t have the resources or staff in house to be across them all, it can be useful to get in touch with a specialist <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">marketing consultant</a>. Contact the experts at The Lead Agency today for more information.</p>
<p>And make sure that you check out the other industries that we operate in; <a href="/education-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<div class="blog-share text-center"></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/4-ways-to-market-your-tech-company/">4 Ways to Market Your Tech Company</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
