<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Manufacturing Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/manufacturing-marketing-blogs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:04:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Manufacturing Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Your Guide to Manufacturing Marketing that Drives Results</title>
		<link>/your-guide-to-manufacturing-marketing-that-drives-results/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 01:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manufacturing Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the manufacturing sector, many businesses are still yet to fully embrace modern marketing, and because of this, could very well be stunting their organisational growth. If like so many of today’s manufacturing businesses, you’re relying on out-dated practices and promotional activities, this can reflect poorly on your organisation. Your target audience may gain a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/your-guide-to-manufacturing-marketing-that-drives-results/">Your Guide to Manufacturing Marketing that Drives Results</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the manufacturing sector, many businesses are still yet to fully embrace modern marketing, and because of this, could very well be stunting their organisational growth.</p>
<p>If like so many of today’s manufacturing businesses, you’re relying on out-dated practices and promotional activities, this can reflect poorly on your organisation. Your target audience may gain a perception of your brand that completely contradicts your true organisational identity, negatively impacting performance. With effective marketing, however, you can overcome such inaccurate representations and their consequences.</p>
<p>Modern techniques can be far more effective in the contemporary business environment, thus, exploring new types of approaches, such as digital campaigns, is crucial. By integrating such strategies, you can ensure your marketing efforts remain relevant and competitive in the manufacturing sector.</p>
<h2>The Importance of Manufacturing Marketing</h2>
<p>While improving your marketing may appear costly and time-consuming, in the long term it can actually be incredibly beneficial.</p>
<p>Manufacturing companies often have a particularly long and complex buyer journey, thus, you need to ensure they’re given adequate guidance at each stage of your sales funnel. If potential customers aren’t provided with the right information when they need it, they’ll likely seek out someone who better satisfies their needs.</p>
<p>The general public’s opinions of the manufacturing sector are varied and, in many cases, people will view your business as they do any other in the industry. While manufacturing companies can be known to conduct relatively similar operations, each organisation still has its own strengths, challenges, processes and culture. However, it’s not uncommon for those who lack a strong understanding of the intricacies of this sector to simply <a href="https://www.precisionmarketinggroup.com/b2b-manufacturing-marketing">lump all such businesses together</a>.</p>
<p>Barriers of this nature can be overwhelming and, for many, are almost instantaneously placed into the ‘too hard basket’. Regardless of how accurate an individual’s perception of your brand is it can play a strong role in the purchasing decisions they go on to make.</p>
<p><em>So, how can you make your business known in the manufacturing sector, all the while leaving a lasting, positive impact?</em></p>
<p>With a strong <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">manufacturing marketing strategy</a>, you can conquer this hurdle and those that follow, helping you achieve organisational success well into the future.</p>
<h2>How to Build a Manufacturing Marketing Strategy (that works)</h2>
<h4>1. Create Audience Personas</h4>
<p>Which distinct groups of individuals make up your target audience and what are their defining characteristics? By understanding exactly who you’re trying to reach through <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">manufacturing marketing</a>, you can improve your targeting and the overall effectiveness of your efforts.</p>
<p>It’s likely that your business is interested in targeting more than one customer persona. By segmenting members of your target audience based on their similarities, you can gain valuable insights into their specific motivations, expectations and the like.</p>
<p>This, in turn, gives you the opportunity to tailor your marketing strategy to these different core groups of consumers, ensuring that the content buyers are exposed to resonates with them.</p>
<h4>2. Set Realistic Goals</h4>
<p>What do you want to achieve at the conclusion of your manufacturing marketing campaign, or after a certain period of time?</p>
<p>By setting <a href="https://blog.thomasnet.com/ultimate-guide-marketing-for-manufacturers">SMART objectives</a>, you can establish clear, shared direction organisation-wide. For your objectives to be considered “SMART”, they must be:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>S</strong>pecific</li>
<li><strong>M</strong>easurable</li>
<li><strong>A</strong>ttainable</li>
<li><strong>R</strong>elevant</li>
<li><strong>T</strong>ime-Bound</li>
</ul>
<p>With targeted, realistic goals guiding all of your <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">manufacturing marketing</a> efforts, you can get a better idea of what’s working, all the while identifying any areas that require improvement.</p>
<h4>3. Review &amp; Refine Your Website</h4>
<p>Your business’ online hub is, of course, your website. Thus, it’s crucial that your digital domain accurately reflects your organisation’s identity, expertise and the value you can offer prospects.</p>
<p>With a comprehensive, visually appealing website that has been optimised for search, you can drive more relevant traffic and ensure that, once individuals reach your website, they aren’t left confused or uninterested.</p>
<p>When reviewing or creating your website, it’s important to include the following key design features:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>A Responsive Design:</strong> During 2018, <a href="https://www.perficientdigital.com/insights/our-research/mobile-vs-desktop-usage-study">58% of all site visits were from mobile devices</a>. If your website isn’t compatible with mobile devices, its usability and accessibility will drop significantly. As a result of this, you’ll likely miss out on a significant number of potential leads from individuals who simply can’t navigate or view your content on their device of choice.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Clutter:</strong> When designing your website, it’s important to keep your layout and colour pallet clean and purposeful. Don’t go overboard, as this will likely negatively impact the overall usability of your domain. If users have difficulty navigating your website, or the design is overwhelming, they may struggle to find the information they’re searching for.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on Creating Valuable Content: </strong>When it comes to attracting, engaging and delighting prospects, content is crucial. By sharing different types of collateral that offer real value to customers, you can build ongoing, meaningful relationships that promote brand loyalty and advocacy. The content you share can include informative blog posts, eBooks, case studies, product videos and the like.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Lead Agency has worked with clients across a range of industries, one of which is the manufacturing sector. If you’re interested in developing an effective <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">manufacturing marketing strategy</a> that gets results, get in touch with our team today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/your-guide-to-manufacturing-marketing-that-drives-results/">Your Guide to Manufacturing Marketing that Drives Results</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boost Your Manufacturing Marketing with these Actionable Tips</title>
		<link>/boost-your-manufacturing-marketing-with-these-actionable-tips/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manufacturing Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The number of manufacturers in Australia has fallen from 96,000 10 years ago, to nearly 84,000 last year. According to an ABC news report, just under half of local manufacturers are innovating, which means they are using improved products, services, processes or methods. However, with tough global competition and disruptive new technologies, it is vital [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/boost-your-manufacturing-marketing-with-these-actionable-tips/">Boost Your Manufacturing Marketing with these Actionable Tips</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The number of manufacturers in Australia has fallen from <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-07-30/manufacturing-industry-told-to-innovate-or-perish/10053016">96,000 10 years ago, to nearly 84,000 last year</a>. According to an ABC news report, just under half of local manufacturers are innovating, which means they are using improved products, services, processes or methods. However, with tough global competition and disruptive new technologies, it is vital that businesses within the industry start to change in order to keep up with the trends. The industry has been warned: innovate or face shutting down completely over the next 5 years.</p>
<p>For businesses in Australia’s manufacturing industry, it’s not just their processes that need to be updated but their marketing tactics do too. While most industries have been using social media, email marketing, SEO and other digital marketing tactics for years, manufacturing businesses have lagged behind. As such, marketers in the sector now have to learn these platforms and methods of communication that are completely new to them. To add to the complexity, as more companies in the industrial space are becoming aware of these strategies, advertising channels are becoming crowded and manufacturing marketers have to ensure their company stands out. Some of the other things that make <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">manufacturing marketing</a> so difficult are outlined below.</p>
<h2><strong>Common Problems with Manufacturing Marketing</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>Identifying the Target Market</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/2018/11/manufacturing-content-marketers/">Only 39% of manufacturing marketers surveyed have buyer personas.</a></p>
<p>Without knowing exactly who you want to target, you can’t create an effective marketing strategy. Identifying target customers can be difficult for manufacturing marketers, who often don’t fully understand the motivations and pain points of their audience. Without a comprehensive understanding of this, it’s impossible to write blog posts or emails, or create social media posts or digital marketing ads that will move customers through the buying process to conversion.</p>
<h3><strong>Creating a Content Marketing Strategy</strong></h3>
<p>Content Marketing is one of the most important marketing strategies today. No campaign can exist without content as it is a vital part of landing pages, ad messaging, and social media posts, to name just a few. Despite this, content marketing is a relatively new concept for many manufacturing marketers. Most manufacturing marketers are unsure exactly what a content marketing strategy is, and how to action it. They are unfamiliar with editorial calendars and <a href="https://www.industrialmarketingtoday.com/unique-challenges-of-manufacturing-content-marketing-in-2019/">most don’t have a content marketing strategy in place</a>. It can also be difficult for manufacturing marketers to get buy-in from across the organisation in order to implement a content marketing strategy.</p>
<h3><strong>Tracking Marketing ROI</strong></h3>
<p>When you ask manufacturing marketers how they track the success of their campaigns, they will most often tell you that they don&#8217;t have a defined strategy. This means that they can’t identify how well a campaign is going, what channels are working for them, or what messaging is most effective in driving customer action. Furthermore, many industrial companies won&#8217;t have a CRM in place, so tracking leads and sales can be problematic.</p>
<h2><strong>Ways to Solve Manufacturing Marketing Challenges</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>Define Your Buyer Persona</strong></h3>
<p>By taking the time to identify the individuals that purchase from your manufacturing business, you can gain a deeper understanding of their buyer journey. Consider the following for example; do customers most often first find you through a Google search, on Social Media or through word of mouth? How do customers move from the awareness stage to the consideration and intent stages of the buying process, and what communications help them do that? When does a prospect become a ‘hot lead’ that should be passed on to the sales team for converting? Once you know the answers to these questions, you can focus your marketing activities on the channels and strategies to use for effective communication at each stage of the buyer journey.</p>
<h3><strong>Implement Technical Solutions</strong></h3>
<p>Ensuring your business is properly tracking all marketing activities will help you monitor the ROI of each channel, which helps you better assign your marketing budget. A CRM can help your business keep track of sales activity by helping you track your touch points with clients and leads. In addition, having analytics properly configured for your digital marketing will allow you to see what is working or your business online. In order to effectively implement both of these things however, will require a commitment to learning a range of tracking tools, as well as a CRM. Rest assured, the pay off in terms of monitoring leads, strategies and sales will be worth it.</p>
<h3><strong>Work on a Content Marketing Strategy</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/2018/11/manufacturing-content-marketers/">Only 21% of manufacturing marketers report that they have a documented content marketing strategy.</a></p>
<p>The first step in creating an effective content marketing strategy is to define your audience, including developing <a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/2016/05/buyer-personas-essential-parts/">personas</a> as mentioned above. This allows you to understand what content they need at each stage of their journey. Having a dedicated content strategy in place also helps you to align content around the business’ objectives and makes it easier to determine which types of content to develop and which topics will be most effective in converting your leads to sales.</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we’ve worked with a number of firms across the manufacturing sector to boost their marketing campaigns and generate leads for their business. If you need help with your <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">manufacturing marketing</a>, don’t hesitate to get in touch with us today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/boost-your-manufacturing-marketing-with-these-actionable-tips/">Boost Your Manufacturing Marketing with these Actionable Tips</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
