<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Insurance Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/insurance-marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 07:51:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Insurance Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>3 Fundamental Components of Your Insurance Marketing Strategy</title>
		<link>/3-fundamental-components-of-your-insurance-marketing-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insurance Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to developing their marketing strategy, many insurance providers don’t know where to start. Even though they’re confident in the quality of their service, they struggle to clearly communicate their expertise with prospects. By building your marketing strategy on strong foundations, you can develop highly targeted promotional efforts that are consistent and effective. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-fundamental-components-of-your-insurance-marketing-strategy/">3 Fundamental Components of Your Insurance Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to developing their <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">marketing strategy</a>, many insurance providers don’t know where to start. Even though they’re confident in the quality of their service, they struggle to clearly communicate their expertise with prospects.</p>
<p>By building your marketing strategy on strong foundations, you can develop highly targeted promotional efforts that are consistent and effective. With members across all organisational levels working towards a shared vision, you will have the ability to <a href="/lead-generation/">drive more relevant leads faster</a>.</p>
<h2>Challenges Faced by Those in the Insurance Sector</h2>
<p>Insurance providers often encounter difficulty when trying to differentiate their brand and offering from that of competitors. In many instances, your target audience won’t have a strong understanding of the technical elements of your product. Thus, they may struggle to identify how it’s any different to the next, let alone better.</p>
<p>When dealing with insurers, consumers want a seamless, streamlined experience that’s personalised to their individual needs. If prospects are left waiting for an extended period of time, are supplied confusing information, or don’t feel like a valued client, they’ll likely look elsewhere.</p>
<p>A contributing factor to this barrier is the fact that insurance is, of course, an <a href="https://yourbusiness.azcentral.com/challenges-insurance-marketing-14874.html">intangible product</a>. Often, individuals find it difficult to invest in an offering that doesn’t give them immediate or guaranteed benefits, fulfilment or enjoyment. Thus, you need to market your product in a way that reassures prospects of its value. For many consumers, the peace of mind and financial security that comes with insurance can be invaluable. When constructing your <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">insurance marketing strategy</a>, this is a key proposition you may choose to focus on.</p>
<p>With <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">insurance marketing</a>, you can gain an enhanced perception of your ideal audience and their distinct expectations. By leveraging this information, your company can create targeted marketing campaigns that leave a lasting impact and further refine your existing products and services.</p>
<p>Marketing can, in this way, be an incredibly powerful way for insurers to overcome the unique challenges of the sector, grow their business and achieve continued organisational success.</p>
<h2>1. Launch a Brilliant Website</h2>
<p>Whether you’re yet to build a website or you have an online domain that needs updating, the sooner you take action, the sooner you’ll start seeing results.</p>
<p>When designing your website, finding the ideal balance between aesthetically pleasing visuals and functionality is crucial. In addition to this, while your design may look fantastic on desktops, if it isn’t compatible with mobile devices, you may lose interest from a significant portion of your target audience.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://www.bluecorona.com/blog/insurance-marketing-ideas-strategies"><em>More than 50% of searches</em></a><em> for insurance happen on mobile devices.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>It’s not uncommon for individuals to go overboard when adding features to their website. While they may seem exciting, an excessive number of pop-ups, moving sections and the like can overwhelm and disengage prospects.</p>
<p>Ultimately, when building your website, if you ensure it’s fast, secure and mobile-friendly, you’ll be setting yourself up to achieve the best results.</p>
<h2>2. Leverage Email Marketing</h2>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">Email marketing</a> can be an incredibly effective way for insurance providers to not only nurture prospects, but also to stay in touch with existing clients.</p>
<p>By sending a monthly newsletter, you can keep contacts informed and share value-driven content that directly applies to them. This can, in turn, assist you in maintaining an ongoing relationship with recipients, all the while staying relevant in the client’s mind.</p>
<p>Your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">email marketing</a> campaigns can be highly targeted and personalised and, often, this is achieved without the need for a substantial financial investment. In fact, for every $1 spent on email marketing, businesses achieve an <a href="https://au.oberlo.com/blog/email-marketing-statistics">average return of $32</a>. As such, this approach can be a cost-effective way to keep your contacts informed and engaged.</p>
<h2>3. Create &amp; Share Marketing Collateral</h2>
<p>As mentioned previously, prospects aren’t always going to have a comprehensive understanding of the different insurance products that are available to them.</p>
<p>When it comes to deciding which policy is right for them, they may be incredibly doubtful as to whether they’re making the right choice. However, by providing potential clients with insightful, informative resources, in the form of <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">marketing collateral</a>, you can overcome this hurdle.</p>
<p>There are numerous types of <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">marketing collateral</a> and, while you certainly don’t have to use them all, integrating multiple materials can help keep your resources exciting and engaging.</p>
<p>For instance, you may start by adding a blog to your website and contributing to it regularly. But, as time goes on, you can build on this collateral with:</p>
<ul>
<li>eBooks</li>
<li>Case studies</li>
<li>Testimonials</li>
<li>Product catalogues</li>
<li>Brochures</li>
<li>Infographics</li>
<li>Monthly Newsletters</li>
</ul>
<p>Want to build an exceptional <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">insurance marketing strategy</a>? Get in touch with the Lead Agency today. With extensive experience in the insurance sector, our <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">marketing consultants</a> know the industry and can help your business drive more valuable leads.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-fundamental-components-of-your-insurance-marketing-strategy/">3 Fundamental Components of Your Insurance Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Making These Insurance Marketing Mistakes?</title>
		<link>/are-you-making-these-insurance-marketing-mistakes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 05:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insurance Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The insurance sector is incredibly competitive, and if you fail to build on your consumer base, you’ll likely struggle to maintain a viable business. Digital capabilities are a driving force for change in the sector, with insurers now being put up against an extensive selection of providers online. In many cases, consumers are looking beyond [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-making-these-insurance-marketing-mistakes/">Are You Making These Insurance Marketing Mistakes?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The insurance sector is incredibly competitive, and if you fail to build on your consumer base, you’ll likely struggle to maintain a viable business.</p>
<p>Digital capabilities are a driving force for change in the sector, with insurers now being put up against an extensive selection of providers online. In many cases, consumers are looking beyond their local options, searching the Internet for the policy that will be best suited to their needs.</p>
<p>Insurance providers are focusing on integrating more <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">automation capabilities</a> into their operations, which can improve efficiencies and allow them to manage growth more effectively. Seamlessly <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/global/en/pages/financial-services/articles/gx-insurance-industry-outlook.html">automating tiresome tasks</a> also frees up more time for skilled workers to focus on strategic responsibilities, business challenges and high-level projects. This is just one strategy that a growing number of insurers are actioning.</p>
<p><em>So, how do you plan on making your insurance business a competitive force in the market? </em></p>
<p>With effective <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">insurance marketing</a>, your business can build a trusted reputation. In the insurance industry, this is particularly important. A recent survey found that in Australia, the majority of survey participants believed that <a href="https://www.insurancenews.com.au/local/insurers-not-trusted-with-data-survey-finds">successful claim rates were 60% or less</a>. In reality, insurers pay <a href="https://www.insurancewatch.com.au/insurance-claims-statistics.html">more than 90% of all claims</a>.</p>
<p>Many providers have a rough idea of what they <em>should</em> be doing in terms of marketing, but they’re not always able to identify why their current efforts aren’t getting the results they desire.</p>
<p>There are various reasons why this may be the case, and by becoming familiar with them, you can critically analyse where exactly your <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">insurance marketing strategy</a> needs to change.</p>
<h2>1. Your Branding Isn’t Consistent</h2>
<p>While a logo and comprehensive colour scheme are, of course, crucial in <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">building a strong brand</a>, if your business wants to make a real impact, you’ll need to go beyond the surface level.</p>
<p>The average customer can struggle to clearly differentiate between different insurance products, as often the defining components of policies are complex and packed with industry jargon. In fact, a mere <a href="https://www.surfly.com/blog/top-sales-challenges-insurance-companies-face-today">45% of consumers</a> understand insurance terms such as “copay” and “deductible”. Because of this, an individual’s perception of your brand will likely play a significant role in whether or not they choose your product over your competitor’s.</p>
<p>A truly great brand represents who you are, leaving audiences with a lasting vision and clear understanding of your business’ image, personality and values. An inconsistent brand message will likely have the opposite effect, with consumers becoming confused and drawing little valuable information from your efforts.</p>
<p>It’s counterproductive to send one set of signals on your website, another on your social media, and another in every email your audience receive. Keeping your colour selection, fonts, style of language, tagline and the like consistent can help you construct incredibly powerful, memorable <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branding</a>.</p>
<h2>2. Poor Website Design</h2>
<p>Your website is the online hub of your business and, thus, it needs to represent your carefully constructed branding, while also acting as a reliable point-of-reference for clients.</p>
<p>If your website is out-dated, it’s unlikely that it’ll be driving the results you desire. Your website may have been fantastic at one point in time, but if it now lacks the capacity to meet the changing needs and expectations of clients and prospects, you’re not alone.</p>
<p>Many insurers fail to regularly update their digital domains, even though it’s suggested that businesses redesign and refine their website <a href="https://www.firstpagemarketing.com/blog/how-often-should-website-rebuilt-updated/">every 3-4 years</a>.</p>
<p>As an insurance provider, it’s also incredibly important to cater to users of different devices, making sure your website design is compatible with mobiles and tablets. With <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/277125/share-of-website-traffic-coming-from-mobile-devices/">almost 50% of all global website traffic</a> coming from mobile devices, failing to reach these users with a functional website will significantly reduce your audience size.</p>
<p>It comes as no surprise that a website that loads slowly, is poorly designed and difficult to navigate isn’t going to <a href="/lead-generation/">generate leads</a>. Taking the time to ensure your online presence accurately represents who you are as a brand, all the while providing valuable information to users, is crucial.</p>
<h2>3. Lack of High-Quality Written Content<strong> </strong></h2>
<p>As mentioned, prospects typically have little understanding of the technicalities of your product. With value-driven, informative <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content marketing</a>, you can educate consumers on the policies you offer. When consumers are actually familiar with your product and its features, they’ll be far more confident in their final policy decision.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency specialises in B2B digital marketing, with extensive experience working in a diverse range of industries. If you’re interested in improving your <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">insurance marketing</a>, our team can help. Get in touch with one of our marketing professionals and start <a href="/lead-generation/">generating more valuable leads</a> today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-making-these-insurance-marketing-mistakes/">Are You Making These Insurance Marketing Mistakes?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Challenges of Insurance Marketing &#038; How to Overcome Them</title>
		<link>/the-challenges-of-insurance-marketing-how-to-overcome-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Insurance Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The insurance industry is constantly changing. Businesses in the industry have to navigate a range of advances in technology and changing consumer behaviours to stay relevant. Insuretechs, the Internet of Things and advancements in mobile have disrupted the insurance landscape. Not to mention the more stringent compliance requirements and consumers’ raised expectations for individualised insurance [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-challenges-of-insurance-marketing-how-to-overcome-them/">The Challenges of Insurance Marketing &#038; How to Overcome Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><a href="https://www.theceomagazine.com/business/finance/evolution-australias-insurance-industry-2017/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">insurance industry is constantly changing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Businesses in the industry have to navigate a range of advances in technology and changing consumer behaviours to stay relevant.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Insuretechs, the Internet of Things and advancements in mobile have disrupted the insurance landscape. Not to mention the more stringent compliance requirements and consumers’ raised expectations for individualised insurance programs. Insurance businesses have to keep up with these changes and adapt their strategy in order to stay relevant in today’s insurance market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketers in these businesses not only have to keep up with these trends, but they also have the difficult job of trying to sell insurance products.  </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the marketing tactics and channels used in insurance marketing are similar to other industries, the way insurance marketers have to create ads and write copy is highly specialised and specific. </span></p>
<p><a href="/insurance-marketing-2/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Insurance marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> isn’t easy. The following are some of the reasons for this.</span></p>
<h2><b>Why is Insurance Marketing so Difficult?</b></h2>
<h3><b>Perceptions of Insurance Products</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First and foremost, insurance is an intangible service, and an intangible product may as well be invisible.  As an intangible product, it is very difficult for prospects to assess the quality or value of their insurance policy.  In addition, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">customers who are looking to purchase insurance products are not just looking to purchase a financial program, but they want a sense of financial security and protection.  These intangibles are invaluable to the consumer, but they’re not easy to market. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">To add more complication to the process, insurance is often perceived as a “</span><a href="https://www.broadbench.co.uk/2018/07/02/feel-good-about-insurance/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">necessary evil</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” and customers may never really know the true value of the product if they never have a claim.</span></p>
<h3><b>Similar Products</b><b><br />
</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The goal of most marketers is to differentiate their offering from the competition. In the insurance industry, this is extremely difficult as the insurance programs on the market are very similar, if not exactly the same. The differences in policies often come down to the specific policy wordings, where policies will vary in what may be included and excluded. These variations can be very specific and also complex so it can be difficult for those outside the industry to understand. As such, communicating these differences is unlikely to be a major selling point.  As an insurance marketer, you have to dig a lot deeper to find ways to separate yourself apart from the competition. </span></p>
<h3><b>Reaching the Consumer</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In most industries, marketing communications go from the company directly to the target audience – whether that is a business or an end customer.  With insurance marketing, the path is slightly more complex. Many consumers purchase their insurance through a middle man such as an underwriter or an insurance broker.  In addition, they may also be recommended insurance services from someone else that they work within the financial services industry, such as their financial planner. As a result, insurance marketers often have to create messages that not only engage the user, but also the other segments that influence the decision. </span></p>
<h3><b>Writing to Compliance</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compliance regulations are becoming more stringent across financial services and insurance is no exception. This means that it is vital to ensure all of your marketing content, from your website to your brochures and newsletters, is compliant with current standards.  If your content does not comply, your company could face significant legal penalties. Non-compliant content can also mislead or confuse potential clients, which can damage their trust in your brand.</span></p>
<h2><b>How to Overcome the Challenges In Insurance Marketing</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The key to successfully selling an intangible product like insurance is to differentiate your offering from your competitors. This comes from fully understanding your client’s motivation and buying behaviour to identify your unique selling proposition, which you then communicate with clients and prospects through your marketing communications.</span></p>
<h3><b>Know your Target Audience</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">clients expect personalisation at every step of their </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">buying</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> experience</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your message isn’t relevant, they’ll likely just ignore it. As such, it is vital to segment your audience so that you can send them targeted communications. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a number of tools available that can help you do this, like data management systems and Google Analytics.  By using in-depth insights into your consumers, you can develop a more complete picture of your target customer and segment them into target audiences that receive tailored, personalised messages accordingly. If you target your audience you’ll get a much greater return on your marketing investment.</span></p>
<h3><b>Get Technical</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adapting to technology is no longer optional, it’s essential.  Your clients are online, searching for your products and services and researching and evaluating your business based on what they find.  Today’s consumers assume that a company’s online experience reflects the offline experience, so ensuring your online experience is positive is vitally important. Having consistency between online and offline experiences builds trust with clients.  In addition, incorporating online tools and features that make doing business with you easier will increase your client retention, so digital marketing is a must.</span></p>
<h3><b>Stay Compliant</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your marketing materials are not compliant, you risk damaging clients’ trust and ending up in legal trouble. In a regulated industry, it is vital that everything you produce falls within the stipulated guidelines. In order to do this, you have to get involvement from executives and your legal department.  You can then set up the right processes to create and share content that is compliant.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the Lead Agency, we’ve worked in the Insurance sector for more than 15 years. In that time have helped a range of businesses, including Insurance Brokerages, Underwriters, Online Insurance providers, Authorised Representative Networks and Insurers. If you need help with your </span><a href="/insurance-marketing-2/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">insurance marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, get in touch with us today. And don&#8217;t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-challenges-of-insurance-marketing-how-to-overcome-them/">The Challenges of Insurance Marketing &#038; How to Overcome Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Allstate Insurance: Project Aware Share</title>
		<link>/allstate-insurance-project-aware-share/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 04:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Insurance Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“The best way to get your point across is to make someone laugh”  Allstate Insurance&#8217;s &#8216;Project Aware Share&#8217; uses humour to educate people about sharing safely on social media and emphasizes the importance of having the right home protection. The advert addresses an important issue that is very relevant to today&#8217;s insurance market, and highlights [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/allstate-insurance-project-aware-share/">Allstate Insurance: Project Aware Share</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>“The best way to get your point across is to make someone laugh” </strong></p>
<p>Allstate Insurance&#8217;s &#8216;Project Aware Share&#8217; uses humour to educate people about sharing safely on social media and emphasizes the importance of having the right home protection.</p>
<p>The advert addresses an important issue that is very relevant to today&#8217;s insurance market, and highlights behaviours that put customers at risk. It stands out because it does so in a way that is light-hearted, creative and memorable for viewers.</p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_YL0HzCCJg</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/allstate-insurance-project-aware-share/">Allstate Insurance: Project Aware Share</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
