<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Industrial Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/industrial-marketing-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 07:54:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Industrial Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Does Your Industrial Marketing Strategy Incorporate These 3 Tactics?</title>
		<link>/does-your-industrial-marketing-strategy-incorporate-these-3-tactics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 02:32:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industrial Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The industrial sector is incredibly established, with businesses operating in this industry contributing significantly to the global economy. In fact, the Australian manufacturing industry, which makes up just one component of the industrial sector, is valued at 385.9 billion dollars. This figure is forecast to grow in the years to come, and if you’re an [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/does-your-industrial-marketing-strategy-incorporate-these-3-tactics/">Does Your Industrial Marketing Strategy Incorporate These 3 Tactics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The industrial sector is incredibly established, with businesses operating in this industry contributing significantly to the global economy. In fact, the Australian manufacturing industry, which makes up just one component of the industrial sector, is valued at <a href="https://www.ibisworld.com.au/industry-trends/market-research-reports/manufacturing">385.9 billion dollars</a>.</p>
<p>This figure is forecast to grow in the years to come, and if you’re an industrial business that wants to remain competitive and reap the benefits, establishing yourself in the market is crucial.</p>
<p>How is your product superior to similar offerings, or in other words, why should prospects choose you? With a comprehensive marketing strategy, you can determine your unique value proposition, clearly communicate it with the right people, and effectively differentiate your organisation. When doing this, gaining a sound understanding of who makes up your target audience is vital. If you fail to reach potential customers who have a real interest in what you’re offering, you will likely struggle to drive conversions, regardless of how brilliant your product or promotional efforts are.</p>
<p>You’re a B2B organisation and, thus, the way you systematically target your audience will be vastly different from a B2C company. While B2C marketing strategies typically aim to reach a large pool of consumers in a certain group, <a href="https://www.industrial.marketing/2019/06/seo-for-manufacturers-everything-you-need-to-know/">B2B industrial businesses</a> are more focused on making sure these individuals are the <em>right </em>consumers. It’s not so much about the volume of sales, but the value of them. Securing relatively large, return customers is essential, so your marketing efforts need to be highly targeted and ongoing.</p>
<h2>1. Build a Strong Brand Position in the Industrial Market</h2>
<p>An organisation’s positioning is at the heart of everything they do. By effectively positioning themselves in the business landscape, organisations are able to convey to potential consumers how they can meet their needs like no one else.</p>
<p>The need to determine your unique value proposition and pinpoint your target audience was touched on before, and when positioning your brand, this is made all the more important.</p>
<p>Developing customer personas that define and categorise the different characteristics of your ideal consumers will give you a clear idea of who your best prospects are. This can help your business create campaigns that are tailored to the distinct preferences of each group, giving your marketing efforts direction. In addition to this, you’ll be able to dedicate more resources towards attracting people who have high purchase intent and are actually interested in your offering.</p>
<h2>2. Create an Exceptional Website</h2>
<p>Your website is the <a href="https://www.gorilla76.com/the-7-core-elements-of-an-industrial-marketing-and-sales-strategy">online face of your business</a>. If an individual is searching for your brand online or the type of product you offer, they’ll likely end up at your website. The chances of people who are met with a confusing, poorly designed website sticking around are slim.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://www.sweor.com/firstimpressions"><em>75% of consumers</em></a><em> admit to making judgements on a company’s credibility based on the company’s website design.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>When creating your business’ website, or reviewing your current online domains, consider the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Is your website compatible with desktops and mobile devices?</li>
<li>Is the content you’ve included useful, easy to comprehend and relevant?</li>
<li>Have you included <a href="https://blog.hivedigitalstrategy.com/website-must-haves-in-2019">call-to-actions</a> that encourage conversions?</li>
<li>How user-friendly is the design and layout of your website?</li>
<li>Have you included internal and external links?</li>
<li>Is your website visually appealing and engaging?</li>
</ul>
<p>If there are any points you’re unsure of, feel free to get in touch with our marketing experts. We’ve had extensive experience building and updating online domains and can do everything from designing to writing the content for your website.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7518" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Lead-Generation-Management.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Lead-Generation-Management.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Lead-Generation-Management-450x210.jpg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<h2>3. Lead Generation &amp; Management</h2>
<p>Typically, a prospect needs to come in contact with a brand <a href="https://www.rainsalestraining.com/blog/how-many-touches-does-it-take-to-make-a-sale">eight times before they convert</a> into a valuable sale. In the B2B industrial industry, buyers progress through a long and complex consumer journey, so it’s not uncommon for this figure to rise even higher.</p>
<p>Customers are generally making bulk purchases, and if the supplier is unreliable or sells them a product that doesn’t meet their quality standards, this will negatively impact their business. Thus, numerous decision-makers are involved in the discussions required to reach and approve a final verdict. This in itself adds time to the purchasing journey and, inevitably, introduces another layer of difficulty.</p>
<p><em>So, how can your industrial business overcome this challenge?</em></p>
<p>In most cases, simply being made aware of a particular offering isn’t going to make a prospect decide to convert. To truly optimise your <a href="/industrial-marketing/">industrial marketing strategy</a>, you need to employ purposeful strategies that effectively nurture leads at each stage of the buyer journey.</p>
<p>By delivering continued, relevant value to potential customers, you can build ongoing relationships with prospects that reinforce exactly why you have the ideal solution for their needs. Whether you share eGuides, write blogs, keep subscribers updated with a monthly newsletter or the like, staying in touch is crucial.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“B2B marketers receive </em><a href="https://www.bluecorona.com/blog/2017-seo-statistics/"><em>67% more leads</em></a><em> if they have a blog.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>You’re an industrial business, so it’s likely that you rely heavily on return customers who consistently make large purchases. This means your post-sale marketing strategies are just as important as those you integrated to convert leads, so your value-driven efforts need to be ongoing.</p>
<p>For professional assistance in building your <a href="/industrial-marketing/">industrial marketing strategy</a>, speak with an expert from the Lead Agency today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/does-your-industrial-marketing-strategy-incorporate-these-3-tactics/">Does Your Industrial Marketing Strategy Incorporate These 3 Tactics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 4 Most Effective Strategies for B2B Industrial Marketing</title>
		<link>/the-5-most-effective-strategies-for-b2b-industrial-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industrial Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>B2B industrial marketing has significantly changed in recent years. The industrial market has become more saturated with products, and technological advancements have made competition much fiercer. The rise of globalisation has meant that industrial marketers now have to compete with not only local manufacturers, but manufacturers from all over the world. In addition, more and [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-5-most-effective-strategies-for-b2b-industrial-marketing/">The 4 Most Effective Strategies for B2B Industrial Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>B2B industrial marketing has significantly changed in recent years. The industrial market has become more saturated with products, and technological advancements have made competition much fiercer. The rise of globalisation has meant that industrial marketers now have to compete with not only local manufacturers, but manufacturers from all over the world. In addition, more and more <a href="https://vendors.trustradius.com/millennial-b2b-buyers-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-new-wave-of-decision-makers/">B2B buyers are in the 25-34-year-old age group, which makes them the biggest decision making demographic</a> in the B2B sector.</p>
<p>This new generation of B2B decision-makers grew up with the existence of the Internet. As such, targeting these ‘digital natives’ means building a strong online presence. This is vastly different from traditional B2B industrial marketing techniques, which primarily involved attending trade shows and putting print ads in relevant trade publications.</p>
<p><a href="/industrial-marketing/">B2B industrial marketing</a> has been revolutionised by the Internet. Your customers are online, and you need to make sure that your business is too; otherwise, they are likely to find a competitor. Creating a strong presence online means more than simply setting up a website and posting to social media. In order to be successful with your B2B industrial marketing online, you need to take a strategic approach. The following are some of the best things you can do to ensure your B2B industrial marketing strategy gets results for your business.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h3><strong> Communicate Your Unique Value Proposition</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Before you start any marketing strategy, you have to know the customers that you are targeting. If you don’t have a clearly defined picture of your target audience, you won’t know which tactics, messaging, and promotional channels to use for your marketing efforts.</p>
<p>The first step in understanding your customer is to <a href="/creating-buyer-personas-for-better-b2b-marketing/">create a buyer persona for them</a>. This involves putting together ideas about your customer’s demographics, goals, motivations, pain points and thought processes. Your buyer persona should also outline where they obtain their information, how they research products and services, and the content that they are most likely to engage with.</p>
<p>You can then match up the target customer’s needs and challenges to the products and services that your business provides in order to create your industrial business’ <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/business-value-proposition/">value proposition</a>. Once developed, the value proposition should be incorporated into all communications between your business and the customer.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<h3><strong> Develop a Comprehensive Content Marketing Strategy<br />
</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>According to a recent report from Accenture, <a href="https://www.accenture.com/t20150624t211502__w__/us-en/_acnmedia/accenture/conversion-assets/dotcom/documents/global/pdf/industries_15/accenture-b2b-procurement-study.pdf">94% of B2B buyers say they conduct some form of online research before purchasing a business product</a>. It’s important that they can find information on your business and its products and services when they are in this research phase. The best way to do this? Content marketing.</p>
<p>91% of B2B marketers use content marketing to reach customers. This is an extremely effective way of communicating with the target audience, as <a href="https://www.themarketingblender.com/statistics-every-b2b-company-know-boost-sales/">80% of business decision-makers prefer to get company information from a series of articles rather than an advertisement</a>. Your content marketing can help get your business in front of your target audience early on in the research phase of the purchasing process. With effective content, you can communicate your relevance to them, build trust and demonstrate how your business can add value to them to move them further through their buyer journey.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7530" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Add-Video-Into-Your-Strategy.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Add-Video-Into-Your-Strategy.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Add-Video-Into-Your-Strategy-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Add-Video-Into-Your-Strategy-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<h3><strong> Incorporate Video Into Your Strategy<br />
</strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/05/22/have-you-adjusted-to-these-three-changes-in-the-b2b-buying-process/#71a6c710c445">70% of B2B buyers and researchers watch videos on their path to purchase</a>. As such,</p>
<p>videos are gaining more prominence as a content format, with <a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/2017_B2B_Research_FINAL.pdf">72% of B2B marketers using video</a>. It’s proven to be an effective strategy for them. According to Aberdeen Group, marketers who use video get 66% more leads per year.</p>
<p>Video content is ideal for communicating with your target audience by delivering a unique experience, helping them solve a problem, creating personal and emotional connections, and sharing timely insights. More and more social media platforms are supporting and prioritising video. However, marketers, particularly in the industrial sector, are a little slower at adopting this technology. Industrial marketers who can master the medium will stay one step ahead of the competition in engaging their customers.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<h3><strong> Dedicate Budget to Digital Paid Advertising </strong></h3>
</li>
</ol>
<p>There are a number of paid digital advertising options available to today’s B2B industrial marketers, from Pay-Per-Click (PPC) ads on search engines to Display Ads, social media ads and promoted social media posts. <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/digital-marketing-strategy/100-must-see-marketing-stats/">Search engine marketing is the highest-ranking channel among paid marketing options in terms of efficacy at 52%, while promoted social media posts come in second at 39%</a>. As more marketers take note of this trend and the success that other businesses are seeing from it, paid advertising is likely to continue to grow.</p>
<p>B2B industrial marketers should be taking advantage of digital advertising and its ability to target a very specific audience so that they can reach their customers and increase their ROI.</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/industrial-marketing/">B2B industrial marketing</a>, get in touch with the <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> experts at The Lead Agency.</p>
<p>Want to proactively plan for future success? Start developing your business&#8217; strategy for next year with our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-5-most-effective-strategies-for-b2b-industrial-marketing/">The 4 Most Effective Strategies for B2B Industrial Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tactics to Boost Your Industrial Marketing Strategy</title>
		<link>/tactics-to-boost-your-industrial-marketing-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industrial Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Accurately identifying and reaching your target audience in the industrial sector can be a long and complex process. To ensure that your efforts don’t go unnoticed, it’s essential for your business to develop a strong industrial marketing strategy. “Over 80% of sales are made after the 5th contact” As such, it’s not only essential to [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tactics-to-boost-your-industrial-marketing-strategy/">Tactics to Boost Your Industrial Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Accurately identifying and reaching your target audience in the industrial sector can be a long and complex process. To ensure that your efforts don’t go unnoticed, it’s essential for your business to develop a strong <a href="/industrial-marketing/">industrial marketing</a> strategy.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Over 80% of sales are made </em>after the 5th contact<em>”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>As such, it’s not only essential to attract valuable new leads to your business but also, critically, retain their interest. Does your business want to gain long-term success in the industrial sector, reach organisational goals and remain competitive long into the future?</p>
<p>Your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/">B2B marketing strategy</a> is central in doing this and, if implemented effectively, can assist your business in achieving exceptional outcomes.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Get on Board with Chatbots</strong></h2>
<blockquote><p><em>“Statistics from Facebook indicate that Messenger handles </em><a href="https://www.industrialmarketer.com/6-customer-engagement-trends-industrial-brands/"><em>more than two billion</em></a><em> business-related messages between customers and clients every month”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>In the industrial industry, it’s crucial to have a comprehensive website that will leave a lasting impression. If your business’ online domains are outdated or poorly constructed, convincing potential customers that your offerings are any different will become a difficult task. Chatbots display responsiveness to advances, showing that your organisation is making the changes needed to provide exceptional service and operate at the frontier of the industrial industry.</p>
<p>With a Chatbot, if customers navigating your website have any queries, they can efficiently contact you directly and get answers fast. Any confusion or questions that may have otherwise deterred them from considering your brand further are addressed promptly, increasing your chances of translating their initial interest into a sale.</p>
<p>Customers get to speak with a real person and, in the majority of instances, avoid having to wait an excessive period of time to have their concerns addressed. With Chatbots your B2B industrial company can build a convenient, personalised experience that your consumers will value.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Optimise For Mobile Use</strong></h2>
<p>How many people do you know who don’t own a mobile phone?</p>
<p>In recent years mobile devices have become exceedingly popular, and it seems that their demand will only continue to grow in times to come. Organisations operating within the industrial sector don’t always respond promptly to modern advances and, a lot of the time, creating a website is a relatively new endeavour. If your online domains aren’t yet optimised for mobile usage, then it’s definitely something your B2B industrial company should consider.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“In 2018, </em><a href="https://www.stonetemple.com/mobile-vs-desktop-usage-study/"><em>58% of site visits</em></a><em> were from mobile devices”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>When optimising your online domains on mobile you’ll need to ensure that the content you post, including both images and text, can be reformatted onto smaller screens. This is vital, as if your content is altered when viewed on a different device, this may affect its readability.</p>
<p>Making your digital platforms compatible for mobile devices can assist your industrial business in implementing an integrated B2B marketing strategy.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Integrate Video</strong></h2>
<blockquote><p><em>“Global internet traffic from videos will make up </em><a href="https://www.industrialsage.com/industrial-marketing-in-2018/"><em>80% of all internet traffic</em></a><em> by 2019”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>If your industrial organisation is yet to integrate video into your B2B marketing strategy, now is the time. The effective use of video can act to leverage your message delivery, with imagery acting to engage customers in an exciting way.</p>
<p>In recent years, many organisations in the industrial sector have started to recognise video content as a top priority. High-quality videos can be particularly beneficial to industrials as they’re able to showcase their business’ capabilities with visual evidence. Although written content is essential online, videos help to enhance engagement and <a href="https://www.weidert.com/whole_brain_marketing_blog/industrial-marketing-trends-and-challenges">reinforce the authenticity</a> of your claims.</p>
<p>Creating video content such as product demonstrations or exclusive behind the scenes of your industrial business operations can help to deliver new value to customers. These visuals aren’t restricted to only being shared on platforms like YouTube that are purely dedicated to such content. Videos can also be highly effective when integrated into other social media platforms like Facebook, or even on your company website.</p>
<p>The demand for visual mediums is growing rapidly, offering an option to market to consumers in a way that can be both informative and enjoyable at the same time.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Data Analytics are Key</strong></h2>
<p>To succeed in the modern industrial sector, it’s essential to invest in data analytics and truly understand the market you’re operating in. <a href="https://www.manufacturing.net/article/2018/05/using-big-data-analytics-improve-production">67 per cent</a> of manufacturing executives are planning to invest in big data analytics, and if you’re not one you’ll be forfeiting access to valuable insights and opportunities.</p>
<p>We’re now living in a data-driven economy and, to remain competitive, it’s crucial to truly make the most of the information available to you. By effectively integrating data systems, you can measure the accuracy and consistency of machines, <a href="https://www.weidert.com/whole_brain_marketing_blog/industrial-marketing-trends-and-challenges">leveraging technology</a> to boost efficiencies. Data analytics can assist your industrial business in closely monitoring processes, identifying areas of potential improvement, driving innovation and reducing financial costs.</p>
<p>In addition to this, you’re able to gain an enhanced understanding of your market’s distinct needs and how best to meet them. These valuable insights can then be strategically applied to effectively target your customers and gain a competitive edge through highly relevant B2B industrial marketing efforts.</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p>Interested in boosting your <a href="/lead-generation/engage-your-targets/">customer engagement</a> through <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a>? At the Lead Agency, we’ve work in the sector for the past 20 years. Our experienced team can provide you with the professional advice and guidance you need to reach your marketing goals. To find out more, please do not hesitate to <a href="/contact-us/">contact us</a> today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tactics-to-boost-your-industrial-marketing-strategy/">Tactics to Boost Your Industrial Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
