<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Marketing Automation Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/marketing-automation-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:01:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Marketing Automation Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Why Your Company Should be Using B2B Marketing Automation</title>
		<link>/why-your-company-should-be-using-b2b-marketing-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 23:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>B2B marketers are increasingly using marketing automation to provide value to their leads and to educate and onboard users. According to a report from Adestra, marketers say that the biggest benefits of marketing automation are time-saving (74%), increased customer engagement (68%), more timely communications (58%) and increased opportunities such as up-selling (58%). When carried out effectively, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-your-company-should-be-using-b2b-marketing-automation/">Why Your Company Should be Using B2B Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>B2B marketers are increasingly using marketing automation to provide value to their leads and to educate and onboard users. According to a report from <a href="http://www.adestra.com/resources/downloadable-reports/marketer-vs-machine/">Adestra</a>, marketers say that the biggest benefits of marketing automation are time-saving (74%), increased customer engagement (68%), more timely communications (58%) and increased opportunities such as up-selling (58%).</p>
<p>When carried out effectively, marketing automation can generate significant results. It has been found to drive a <a href="http://nucleusresearch.com/research/single/marketing-drives-crm-roi/">14.5% increase in sales productivity and a 12.2% reduction in marketing overhead</a>. The bottom line is that <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B marketing automation</a> generates ROI, revenue, and results.</p>
<h2>What is B2B Marketing Automation<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>The term ‘marketing automation’ refers to a platform that is pre-programmed to send campaigns automatically to customers and prospects, based on rules defined by marketers.</p>
<p>Technology that can be provided by or integrated with marketing automation programs includes the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>email marketing software</li>
<li>website, content management systems (CMS), or e-commerce platforms such as WordPress and Shopify</li>
<li>landing page builders and form builders</li>
<li>social media publishing tools</li>
<li>customer relationship management (CRM) systems such as Salesforce and ZoHo</li>
<li>Campaign Management tools such as Pardot and Hubspot</li>
<li>analytics tools</li>
</ul>
<p>“Customer journeys” are at the heart of marketing automation. A typical marketing automation campaign will lead the recipient through their buyer journey to sale by sending relevant communications based on their interactions with the company. These journeys typically start with a trigger, such as downloading an ebook, signing up for a newsletter, or making a purchase. The following is an example of a typical marketing automation campaign:</p>
<ol>
<li>A prospect downloads your business’ ebook by giving you some basic personal information including their email address</li>
<li>Your automation campaign sends out an email thanking them for their download with a link to download the book</li>
<li>A few days later, your system follows up with a link to a related article that contains interesting content tailored to the recipient. In another few days, you send another email with different content that is also relevant to them and so on.</li>
<li>As the recipient engages with your content, they are assigned points that qualify their position as a lead.</li>
<li>Once the recipient reaches a pre-defined ‘lead score’, the automation forwards their information to a member of the sales team, along with the specifics of what content they have interacted with so that the sales team can take further actions.</li>
</ol>
<p>This type of marketing is valuable as it helps businesses have ongoing conversations with prospects and subscribers, which helps build brand loyalty. In addition, with marketing automation, buyer journeys only have to be set up once, so after the initial setup, campaigns can be left to run with minimal input from marketers.</p>
<h2>How Marketing Automation Works For B2B</h2>
<p>According to a survey from Campaign Monitor, <a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/guides/marketing-technology-report/">82% of marketers are using best-of-breed tools when it comes to marketing automation</a>. This means that they are taking the time to find the best B2B marketing automation resource to meet their specific needs, whether that’s email marketing, landing pages, or social media. After choosing the ideal tool to meet their needs, B2B marketers set automated processes so that they can regularly stay in touch with contacts.</p>
<p>While the specifics of your marketing automation strategy will be unique, there are certain ways to segment your current list. You can start to shape your marketing automation goals and strategy around the following three groups.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Not-Engaged Prospects</strong>: These are prospects that are on your list but have not engaged with your business for a while. The best way to design a campaign for this segment is to provide subscribers with personalised content that helps educate them about your products and services, and build trust and credibility in your brand. This is particularly relevant in B2B marketing, where the buying cycle is longer and requires more touch points.</li>
<li><strong>Engaged Leads</strong>: These subscribers are actively interested in your business and have engaged with your website, emails or social media. Your marketing automation campaign for this segment should focus on their specific point in the buyer journey and how to move them further through to sale.</li>
<li><strong>Current Customers</strong>: Marketing automation can help to keep your current customers engaged by following up with them post-purchase to maintain their loyalty, or cross-sell and upsell your business’ other products and services that are related to the ones they already use.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Why Use B2B Marketing Automation?</h2>
<p>The #1 benefit of marketing automation, according to B2B marketers, is the ability to generate more and better quality leads. – Pepper Global, 2014</p>
<p>Adopting marketing automation can provide the edge a business needs to increase its B2B sales pipeline, even after prolonged periods of inactivity.</p>
<p>In 2015, <u>80% of businesses using marketing automation </u>reported generating more leads, and more importantly, 77% saw an increased number of conversions. However, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">marketing automation</a> is not a ‘silver bullet’ that will solve all of your marketing problems at the touch of a button. It takes work, but when you get it right, marketing automation is a <u>B2B marketing strategy for long-term growth</u>. Some of the benefits you’ll see from developing an effective marketing automation process are as follows.</p>
<h3>Improve Prospect and Customer Experience</h3>
<p>When someone interacts with your company, it’s important to continue to engage that person moving forward. This involves tracking individuals through the sales and marketing process to ensure a relationship is maintained. Doing this without marketing automation can be difficult.</p>
<p>According to CMO, 30% of consumers had a <u>positive experience with retargeted ads</u>. These are ads that are customised to show them specific content that is relevant to them, based on how they have interacted with the business’ digital efforts. With marketing automation, it is easier to personalise your offerings, which can lead to a higher conversion rate.</p>
<h3>Pinpoint Flaws in the Marketing and Sales Process</h3>
<p>Marketing automation provides access to a huge amount of data that your business can analyse to give more insight into your relationship with your customers and their buyer journey. Automation can also help you to qualify leads, which you can pass on to your sales team to close. If you are not making sales, you can look at the data to see if there is a problem with the sales team closing leads, or if the marketing team isn’t qualifying them well enough before they are being passed on. Once you fix this problem, you will likely see an increase in B2B sales.</p>
<h3>Segmentation and Personalisation</h3>
<p>Segmentation is vital for making B2B sales as it allows you to send personalised marketing messages that move prospects through the sales funnel. Marketing automation lets you segment your company data without a huge amount of effort. Your marketing automation platform can help you identify segments and opportunities with factors from simple demographics, to how they have interacted with your site and the calls to action that they have responded to.</p>
<h3>Generating ROI</h3>
<p>Focus research reported that <a href="https://www.callboxinc.com/marketing-automation/lead-generation-stats-that-prove-marketing-automation-works/">75% of companies using marketing automation see ROI within 12 months</a>, and 44% within the first 6 months. This is because marketing automation is scalable. It continues to run and doesn’t burn out, like employees do when carrying out tasks manually. In addition, as you start to analyse your data and optimise your campaign, you can increase the performance of your campaign to generate more leads and conversions.</p>
<h3>Time &amp; Manpower Efficiencies</h3>
<p>Marketing automation limits the number of repetitive tasks that your employees have to carry out, such as emailing prospects according to a predefined schedule. In addition, with lead scoring functionality, your team can focus on quality leads, which increases their efficiency.</p>
<h2>Should Your Company Consider B2B Marketing Automation?</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7598" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/marketing-automation-strategy.png" alt="marketing automation strategy" width="850" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/marketing-automation-strategy.png 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/marketing-automation-strategy-450x106.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/marketing-automation-strategy-768x181.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>Any task that can be carried out by a software program instead of an employee, without diminishing the quality of the work, can increase your business’ efficiency. As such, businesses of all shapes and sizes, and across industries can benefit from incorporating marketing automation into their strategy. That being said, companies that see the most success from their marketing automation campaigns already have the processes and infrastructure in place to effectively deal with their incoming sales leads. If you don&#8217;t currently have these processes in place, do that before you start your marketing automation campaign.</p>
<p>Once your sales processes are in place, your company is in a position to take advantage of the lead generation, nurturing, and sales performance that marketing automation offers.</p>
<p>When set up effectively and backed by an efficient sales team, your marketing automation strategy is likely to generate the following returns for your business.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Time: </strong>By automating social media posts and advertisements, your company could <a href="https://www.impactbnd.com/blog/save-time-and-money-marketing-automation-infographic">save 6 hours a week</a><strong>.</strong> In addition, companies using an automated tool to set their appointments save 80% of their time.</li>
<li><strong>Benefits of Personalisation:</strong> Marketing automation helps businesses personalise emails much easier and quicker, which leads to a <a href="http://marketingland.com/study-70-brands-personalizing-emails-missing-higher-transaction-rates-revenue-73241">6 times higher return</a>.</li>
<li><strong>More Sales:</strong> B2B marketers reported to have 20% more opportunities from nurtured leads when using marketing automation to nurture their leads.</li>
<li><strong>Increased Conversion Rates:</strong> Once a lead has been labelled a ‘Marketing Qualified Lead’, they are reported to have a 53% higher conversion rate than initial prospects. This increases overall revenue across the business.</li>
<li><strong>Analytical Data: </strong>65% of companies using marketing automation report having greater insights into their audience, which means that they can optimise their campaigns for improved performance.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B Marketing Automation</a>, get in touch with the <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> experts at The Lead Agency.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget to check out the other industries that we operate in; <a href="/education-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<div class="blog-share text-center"></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-your-company-should-be-using-b2b-marketing-automation/">Why Your Company Should be Using B2B Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Automation, B2B Marketing &#038; the Future</title>
		<link>/marketing-automation-b2b-marketing-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 21:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In business you constantly search for your panacea. You are well-versed with what your pain points are – from lack of customer insight, to a lack of time – but the solutions that are sought do not always yield the results that are needed. In business you constantly search for your panacea. You are well-versed [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-b2b-marketing-future/">Marketing Automation, B2B Marketing &#038; the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In business you constantly search for your panacea. You are well-versed with what your pain points are – from lack of customer insight, to a lack of time – but the solutions that are sought do not always yield the results that are needed.</p>
<p>In business you constantly search for your panacea. You are well-versed with what your pain points are – from lack of customer insight, to a lack of time – but the solutions that are sought do not always yield the results that are needed.</p>
<p>But then came <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/"><strong>marketing automation</strong></a>. Perhaps it’s far from a panacea per se, but marketing automation has wedged itself within many B2B companies, assisting and addressing many marketers’ pain points.</p>
<p>Here we’ll discuss some of the most common problems with traditional <a href="/">B2B marketing</a>, and how marketing automation addresses those, reaffirming why marketing automation is indeed, the future of B2B marketing.</p>
<h2>Selarketing</h2>
<p>One of the biggest problems with <a href="/b2b-marketing-sydney/"><strong>B2B marketing</strong></a> is that there can be a lack of market focus – businesses, especially start-ups, can try to be all things to different markets.</p>
<p>They refuse to focus on just one key segment. This can be a contributing factor to the rift between sales and marketing – they’re just not aligned. Marketing automation can help tear down those silos.</p>
<p>Since most marketing automation solutions can integrate into CRM packages like Microsoft Dynamics, and both can be dynamically updated simultaneously, creating new sales alerts within the marketing automation solution is possible.</p>
<p>Communication between the two teams is can be maintained more effectively with one central location for all information. Visitor reports are also a great way for sales to get a better idea of the engagement that is happening on the sites.</p>
<h2>Better campaign control</h2>
<p>Marketing automation solutions simplify otherwise technical campaign components such as creating web-pages and HTML emails, forms and automated lead-nurturing programs.</p>
<p>You no longer need to rely solely on IT professionals to assist with creation and execution of these elements. Marketing automation software such as Act-on, Pardot and Marketo, have simplified tooling with which users can easily create these components. Then, within the same system, you can continue to tweak, manage, track and set goals.</p>
<p>For instance, <a href="http://mktg-matters.blogspot.com/">Marketing Matters</a> points out that, “Marketing automation generates a record of the first time a visitor views a product on your web-site, and then follows-up with further data when their interest is converted into purchase.”</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4671" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/google-analytics-.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="380" /></p>
<p>Furthermore, you can also connect the system with other tools such as Google Analytics, Adwords and social media channels and pull the data from all these diverse sources to get a truly integrated and 360 view of customers.</p>
<p>Marketing automation has the ability to remove silos so that campaigns can be managed and measured as part of one cohesive campaign.</p>
<h2>Personalisation, not generalisation</h2>
<p>In a recent <a href="http://contentmarketinginstitute.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/B2B_SMB_2014_CMI.pdf">survey</a> about the current challenges that B2B marketers face, it was unearthed that 45% of marketers don’t produce enough of the content that really engages.</p>
<p>The missing element here is extensive knowledge about your customers. Without intimate knowledge about your customers, your content efforts are going to attract the wrong audience or be far too generalised.</p>
<p>Marketing automation can assist in this instance, too.</p>
<p>For example, Darin Brown, ExactTarget Marketing Cloud Vice President of eXcelerate, shared an <a href="http://www.exacttarget.com/au/products/marketing-automation/marketing-automation-trends">example</a> where marketing automation is expert at personalisation. He explains that a major retail brand personalised their support calls and scripts with marketing automation.</p>
<p>This was possible because the company aggregated all of their interaction data so when a customer called the support centre, the company is able to identify exactly where the individual falls in the customer journey and trigger a relevant phone script for the operator.”</p>
<p>Marketing automation empowers marketers in many aspects.</p>
<p>Why is it the future of B2B marketing? It’s because it pushes the message that the concepts behind B2B or B2C are irrelevant, at the end of it all, it’s H2H – Human to Human.</p>
<p>Customers want to engage with your business. Marketing automation and its available tooling is paving the path for B2B marketing to a destination which puts the customer in-front of all else, effectively engaging with them.</p>
<p>Contact us today to find out how our <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/expertise/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a>, can add value to your business.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-b2b-marketing-future/">Marketing Automation, B2B Marketing &#038; the Future</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Things You Should Know About Marketing Automation</title>
		<link>/7-things-know-marketing-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 23:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Marketing Automation programs have been around for a while now, but marketers and business owners alike still struggle to understand the concept; commonly asking ‘what exactly is marketing automation’ and ‘how can it help grow my business?’ 1. So, What Exactly is Marketing Automation? Marketing Automation is a software solution that helps businesses track a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-things-know-marketing-automation/">7 Things You Should Know About Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marketing Automation programs have been around for a while now, but marketers and business owners alike still struggle to understand the concept; commonly asking ‘what exactly is marketing automation’ and ‘how can it help grow my business?’</p>
<h4><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">1. So,</strong> <strong style="line-height: 1.5;">What Exactly is Marketing Automation?</strong></h4>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">Marketing Automation</a> is a software solution that helps businesses track a prospect’s interactions with across their various web properties such as their website social media channels and any email campaigns.  In doing this, the program builds a robust series of dynamic lists that allow businesses to automatically tailor their marketing messages to the prospects’ individual needs and stage in the buyer journey.</p>
<h3><strong>How Can it Grow Your Business?</strong></h3>
<h4><strong>2. Marketing Automation Programs Help With Lead Qualification</strong></h4>
<p>Most Marketing Automation programs include lead scoring programs that help businesses determine where a prospect is in the buying cycle. This is done by awarding ‘points’ to the prospect depending on their interactions with the business.</p>
<p>For example, a visitor could be given 5 points for visiting a certain website page, 10 points for downloading an eBook, and 30 points for giving their details in an enquiry form. Personalised marketing material can then be sent to each prospect based on their stage in the buying cycle, which is determined by the number of points that they have accumulated.</p>
<h4><strong>3. You Can Use Marketing Automation to Reach Prospects at the Best Times</strong></h4>
<p>With Marketing Automation in place, you can send communications to prospects as soon as they have completed a desired action. For example, if a customer signs up to your email newsletter, they may receive a welcome email straight away, or a soon as they hit a pre-defined number of points, they may be sent a money-off voucher to encourage purchase. Furthermore, if your Marketing Automation platform offers ‘real time’ notifications, you may even be able to see a visitor looking at a certain page on your website so that you can make a sales call as they browse.</p>
<p>Simply put, Marketing Automation gives marketers the opportunity to take action as soon as they see a prospect with a high level of engagement with the brand.</p>
<h4><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">4. Marketing Automation Makes Closing Sales Quicker and Easier</strong></h4>
<p>A smart marketer can apply all of the tools and features offered by Marketing Automation programs to significantly reduce the effort it takes to close a deal.  With well executed campaigns and lead-scoring, the amount of time wasted on ‘window-shoppers’ can be considerably reduced, as all sales and marketing efforts can be dedicated to potential customers that have already demonstrated interest in and engagement with the brand. This adds up to result in a more efficient and profitable marketing campaign.</p>
<h3><strong>Things to Bear In Mind</strong></h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4671 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/expensivecost.png" alt="Bear in Mind" width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h4><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">1. Marketing Automation Can Be Expensive</strong></h4>
<p>Marketing Automation software suites contain several powerful marketing tools, and many are very expensive. There are a wide range of Marketing Automation products on the market, and the cost of each is dependant on the features it has, from several thousand dollars a month to several hundred dollars.</p>
<p>A Marketing Automation platform is also a significant investment in manpower, so before investing in Marketing Automation, you should weigh up the costs against the potential benefit. If you do decide to go ahead, make sure you should do it right, or it could be a costly misadventure for your company.</p>
<h4><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">2. But It Can Also Reduce Your Sales Force</strong></h4>
<p>Despite the expense of a Marketing Automation platform, it can potentially save on a number of other costs such as reductions to your sales force.  This is because a well-executed Marketing Automation program can reduce the number of man hours necessary for closing sales, which may save your business a salary, as well as benefits, time off and turnover costs of employees.</p>
<h4><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">3. Marketing Automation Programs Don’t Work For Every Business</strong></h4>
<p>Whether or not <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">Marketing Automation</a> is appropriate for your business will depend on a number of factors such as the shape and health of your sales cycle, the size of your average sale, the advertising channels you use, your business’s ability to use technical programs and how much time you have to devote to implementation.</p>
<p>Marketing Automation programs don’t come cheap, so before investing in the platform, it’s important to understand exactly how it will impact your business and take time to research the different programs available and their various features in order to decide which of the systems would be a good fit for you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we’ve worked with a number of Law Firms to boost their marketing campaigns and generate leads for their business. If you need help with your <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a>, get in touch with us today. And don’t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-things-know-marketing-automation/">7 Things You Should Know About Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Automation: The Future of B2B Marketing</title>
		<link>/marketing-automation-the-future-of-b2b-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 22:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[b2b marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered if Facebook has been reading your mind? Since that one day you searched for DIY wedding invitations, there have been advertisements popping up all over the place with tips and tricks for getting married on a budget. Your feed is full of low-price wedding dresses and sales on honeymoon destinations. You [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-the-future-of-b2b-marketing/">Marketing Automation: The Future of B2B Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered if Facebook has been reading your mind? Since that one day you searched for DIY wedding invitations, there have been advertisements popping up all over the place with tips and tricks for getting married on a budget. Your feed is full of low-price wedding dresses and sales on honeymoon destinations. You knew Facebook was all-powerful, but you didn’t know it was all-knowing too. Thank goodness, it is not. It is simply making brilliant use of Marketing Automation.</p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ciocentral/2011/09/27/customers-dont-want-to-talk-to-you-either/">Forbes</a>, our interactions with the companies with whom we have a relationship is decreasing so much that in just five years, we will likely have no human interaction with them at all. The value of quick and accurate responses to customer questions/complaints has only gone up over the years. And if a business can provide the right solution before the consumer even starts looking, so much the better.</p>
<h2>Marketing Automation Improves Everyday Marketing</h2>
<p>Marketing Automation allows for all of these things. It takes much of the guesswork out of strategising new marketing plans and finding new clients. Those businesses that use it are 25% more likely to know the right clients to approach, and how to approach them, than those with no automated system. Companies that employ Marketing Automation have shown up to an incredible <a href="http://www.b2bmarketing.net/blog/posts/2014/06/10/marketing-automation-facts-speak-themselves">451% rise in qualified leads</a>.</p>
<p>Marketing Automation software designers such as <a href="http://www.marketo.com/about/">Marketo</a> believe that automated market research in the digital age is best done through channels that the average person uses every day: social media, news websites, blogs, and search engines. The marketing team is then responsible to practice engagement marketing, building relationships with the client in order to ensure continuing business and genuine connection.</p>
<h2>Marketing Automation Improves B2B Marketing</h2>
<p>Marketing Automation saves considerable amounts of time and money that can then be used to make stronger, more effective marketing plans. As an added bonus, the automated system performs the necessary tasks with more efficiency and accuracy. Win, win, and win. Rather than replacing the need for people on the job, Marketing Automation exists to perform the boring, time-consuming tasks of market research and information acquisition, freeing up the minds of marketing professionals to be creative and develop positive relationships with clients.</p>
<p>While convenient enough for Business-to-Consumer marketing, Marketing Automation is practically a necessity for contemporary Business-to-Business marketing. Businesses represent a much wider range of needs, demographics, and preferences. They produce a greater amount of data that must be collected and analysed in order to form an accurate idea of how they can be successfully marketed to. Businesses thrive when the market can be predicted, and the solution is simpler than ever.</p>
<p>Leave the mind-reading to the computers, and open up your marketing team to build meaningful relationships with the clients you know are looking.</p>
<p>How do you feel about <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B Marketing Automation</a> and its effects on the future of <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing</a>? Do you miss the human interaction, or do you prefer to be in control of your relationship with a business?</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B Digital Marketing</a>, please get in contact with the <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/">Business to Business Marketing</a> experts at the Lead Agency today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-the-future-of-b2b-marketing/">Marketing Automation: The Future of B2B Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Automation &#038; Your Business</title>
		<link>/marketing-automation-your-business/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 22:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Part of the reason behind the slow uptake of Marketing Automation is that many companies still don’t really know what Marketing Automation is or how it can benefit their business, and as such, do not know how to implement it effectively. Businesses who can master the platform now are positioning themselves for future success, that’s [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-your-business/">Marketing Automation &#038; Your Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part of the reason behind the slow uptake of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">Marketing Automation</a> is that many companies still don’t really know what Marketing Automation is or how it can benefit their business, and as such, do not know how to implement it effectively.</p>
<p>Businesses who can master the platform now are positioning themselves for future success, that’s why we’ve put together a guide to Marketing Automation, which aims to explain the platform and its features to give you a basic understanding and ensure you stay ahead of the curve.</p>
<h3><strong>So, What is Marketing Automation?</strong></h3>
<p>Marketing Automation is often described as a sophisticated software solution that focuses on tools to nurture customer leads from the moment they enter the top of the marketing funnel.</p>
<p>However Marketing Automation is more than just software. Marketing Automation is a system of processes that is designed to communicate regularly based on their interactions with your business, their stage in the buying process and their understanding of your product / service.</p>
<p>When used correctly, Marketing Automation allows companies to build a relationship with their prospects through highly personalised, useful and relevant content. It helps convert prospects to customers and turn customers into delighted advocates; and as such has the ability to generate significant new revenue for companies.</p>
<h3><strong> </strong><strong>But, What Exactly does Marketing Automation Do?</strong></h3>
<p>An effective Marketing Automation program can considerably increase your marketing output with little increase in your marketing efforts. It is designed to help prioritise and execute marketing tasks in a more streamlined and efficient way to make the most of your marketing initiatives and help you reach your goals faster.</p>
<p>In order to generate more revenue for your company, you need to consider the entire sales funnel and how you can move prospects through. From acquiring prospects or interested people, convert them into sales leads and close those leads into customers. Marketing Automation can assist this entire process.</p>
<h3><strong>Consider this Example…</strong></h3>
<p>Today, many marketers rely on email marketing to generate results by sending blast email after blast email to the abyss of their prospect and customer lists. They hope that the message they have chosen will resonate with some of the audience and drive them toward a desired action; measuring the effectiveness of the campaign based on quantifiable metrics such as open rates, sales or leads.</p>
<p>While this is not necessarily a bad tactic, there are some flaws in this tried and tested method that Marketing Automation can help to overcome.</p>
<p>Using a Marketing Automation system allows you to market smarter. It allows you to nurture your leads through the entire buying process and deliver highly-targeted, personalised messages that address their specific barriers to purchase:</p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> You send an email invitation to download your latest whitepaper to a targeted list of contacts</p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> You send a thank you note to all the people that downloaded the offer. You send a different email or message to those that didn’t download the paper.</p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> A week later, you send a follow up email to the list of people who downloaded the whitepaper, offering them a case study relating to that topic</p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Finally, when someone downloads that case study, your sales team will get a notification so they can follow up with them (this person is now much more qualified and is likely farther down the buying process)</p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Those who did not download the eBook become another segment and receive a reminder about it, or an alternative offer such as an invitation to a free seminar.</p>
<p>The above example demonstrates a personalised approach to Marketing that is much more effective. The customer is more likely to respond to your offerings as they are receiving information that is relevant and tailored to their interactions with your business.</p>
<p>By making the marketing conversation more personalised, Marketing Automation makes the customer more likely to trust your company, and ultimately, more likely to buy.</p>
<h3><strong>The Rise of Marketing Automation</strong></h3>
<p>In today’s business environment, buying power has shifted to the hands of the consumer and the one-to-many approach no longer works. This is particularly prevalent in the B2B industry, where consumers are increasingly well-informed, with the ability to choose from a multitude of different companies.  It has become essential to market to the individual consumer. Despite the common misconception that B2B buyers only care about logical, financial benefits, it’s important to remember that buyers are inherently emotional beings and base their decisions on characteristics such as warmth, humour, trust, and like-ability.</p>
<p>The future of <a href="/the-key-elements-of-the-b2b-marketing-mix/">B2B marketing</a> is consequently moving toward a “Relationship Era”, where the entire customer experience must be carefully considered.  Fostering a long-term relationship with the customer rather than just focusing on the end goal (sales) is key in this modern marketing environment. From a B2B viewpoint, this means extending conversations with your customers past the first or second impression to strengthen their relationship with your brand.</p>
<p>That’s where Marketing Automation comes in. As Marketing Automation considers the stages of the buying cycle, it lets you align your marketing to the buyer’s journey.  With the ability to plan your interactions to what is most important to the buyer in each stage, marketing automation technology knows when to give customers space and then pro-actively contact them at just the right time.</p>
<p>Put simply, with marketing automation you have the ability to better segment customers for greater relevancy, send customers content they are actually interested in, interact with buyers who are engaged in sales, and deepen relationships with existing customers. In order to do this, Inbound Marketing techniques are often employed.</p>
<h3><strong>Inbound Marketing and Marketing Automation</strong></h3>
<p>The customer acquisition tactic that is built on one-on-one human relationships, ‘Inbound Marketing’ goes hand in hand with Marketing Automation.</p>
<p>Inbound Marketing is central to the digital age. It focuses on providing the information your prospects need when they are researching or considering your product or service. The idea is that if they are looking for the information you have, they’re ready to read it and consider it. Inbound Marketing is the practice of attracting users through quality content that pulls people toward your company and product naturally.</p>
<p>By closely aligning your content and marketing materials with your customers’ interest, your brand is best positioned to attract, delight, and engage customers over time.</p>
<p>Marketing Automation can facilitate the timely distribution of a company’s inbound marketing efforts.</p>
<h3><strong>The Elements of Inbound Marketing</strong></h3>
<p>The following are the main elements of Inbound Marketing and how they tie in to Marketing Automation:</p>
<p><strong>Content Marketing: </strong>The B2B brand-customer relationship is no longer based on one-way communication, but rather focuses on two-way brand engagement. That’s why smart B2B businesses are effectively using content marketing to create a valuable conversation with their customers. By sharing content that is relevant, timely, and addresses their prospects’ needs, B2B marketers can nurture their customer relationships and ultimately increase the likelihood of the prospect buying their products or services. Marketing Automation can assist in the distribution of this content as well as tracking your prospect’s engagement with it.</p>
<p><strong>Conversion Funnel Targeting: </strong>Marketers must pay attention to the different stages prospects go through as they interact with the company; from becoming aware of the business and its products / services, to becoming more interested in the business and what it has to offer, and finally committing to purchase from that business. An aggressive call to action too early in the relationship can put a prospect off. That’s why each stage of the buyer’s journey requires different marketing and communication needs, which can be addressed by tracking their interactions through Marketing Automation.</p>
<p><strong>Personalisation:</strong> Personalisation and relevance are essential in marketing communications with prospects and leads. As you build out your Inbound Marketing and Marketing Automation strategy, you learn more about your leads. This learning process will empower your company to re-invest that data into refining your marketing strategy. Marketing Automation software can help you streamline this process and build one to one connections with hundreds of thousands—and even millions—of users.</p>
<p><strong>Cross Channel Integration: </strong> With Inbound Marketing, multi-channel marketing strategies connect all touch points in the customer journey. Nowadays it is extremely common for users to engage with your business across channels such as email, social, advertising, direct marketing and content before deciding to engage in a sale. Analytics are crucial to this framework, which Marketing Automation can facilitate by ensuring marketing and analytics software can communicate effectively with each other. This integration helps to ensure that your brand is delivering the right marketing messages to the right audiences at the right time in their buying journey.</p>
<h3><strong>Benefits of Using Marketing Automation</strong></h3>
<p>When used correctly, Marketing Automation is a fantastic tool for businesses small and large. For small businesses with limited staff, Marketing Automation can assist in running complex campaigns and free up employees’ time so that they can work more efficiently. Marketing Automation is also useful for bigger companies as it allows them to connect with each of their customers in a highly personalised way that is difficult to do manually on such a large scale and align with sales teams and objectives.</p>
<p>Some of the main benefits of Marketing Automation are:</p>
<p><strong>It Saves Time<br />
</strong>With the ability to create multiple campaigns and posts ahead of time and schedule them, you can create an entire lifecycle of posts in one day and set them to post throughout the month without having to keep checking back, freeing up your time to concentrate on other tasks.</p>
<p><strong>It Allows for Precise Segmentation<br />
</strong>Marketing automation allows you to reach each one of your customers with targeted content that is relevant to them. Rather than having to manually segment customers based on their needs and preferences, effective marketing automation solutions allow you to create restrictions that automatically categorise customers.</p>
<p><strong>It Increases Resourcefulness<br />
</strong>With an automated solution, a single staff member can execute complex and ongoing campaigns and can connect with many more customers than would be possible manually.</p>
<p><strong>It Aids Reporting<br />
</strong>With Marketing Automation you can easily create detailed reports. Marketing Automation solutions can keep track of each email sent, every Social Media post, and every piece of content you release, providing detailed graphs, statistics and other report data that you can easily analyse to inform future campaigns.</p>
<p><strong>It Increases Brand Presence<br />
</strong>Because it saves time and resources, Marketing Automation makes it possible for businesses to create a consistent brand presence on multiple channels. By automating your marketing, you are able to expand your campaigns across multiple channels.</p>
<p><strong>It Simplifies Lead Nurturing<br />
</strong>Marketing Automation makes lead nurturing easier as you do not have to connect with each lead manually. With an automated marketing solution, you can reach out to a potential lead right from the beginning of their interaction and track each interaction with your brand over the entire relationship.</p>
<h3><strong>Where Marketing Automation Falls Short</strong></h3>
<p>Marketing Automation is an extremely sophisticated processes and software solution. But like all software, its only as good as the people behind it. In order to get the most out of the platform, your business should set out clear objectives and benchmark your ROI.</p>
<p>If your business does decide to embark on Marketing Automation there are a few things to bear in mind.</p>
<p><strong>A Marketing Process is Essential</strong><strong><br />
</strong>In order to use Marketing Automation, you have to have a marketing process to automate in the first place. The process has to be well thought through, and consistent, otherwise your investment in a Marketing Automation won’t generate significant return on investment.</p>
<p><strong>Leads are Vital</strong><br />
Marketing Automation is useless unless you have enough leads. While Marketing automation can help qualify leads, and nurture leads, most of it’s tools and benefits do not acquire these leads for you.</p>
<p><strong>Content is Key</strong><br />
In order to be successful with Marketing Automation, it is necessary to have relevant content to distribute. This content has to be in the correct form, for example it shouldn’t simply be a collection of web pages, but rather a series of articles, e-Books, whitepapers and other things that people are interested enough in to hand over their contact details for.  Marketing Automation devours content – if you don’t feed it, it dies.</p>
<p><strong>Sales and Marketing Alignment</strong><br />
In order for Marketing Automation to work effectively, it is necessary to have a shared understanding of the buying process between marketing and sales. Both teams should know what messages they are in charge of communicating. When you have a streamlined process, it is clearer for both departments to qualify leads and pass them through to for sales to action and close.</p>
<p><strong>Training Requirements<br />
</strong>Once Marketing Automation is set up, it will save your business time and resources, however the reward does not come straight away. In order to effectively use Marketing Automation, you will have to dedicate a significant amount of time into training staff on how to use it properly and get the most out of the software. For example, if sales don’t contact a lead until they are fully qualified. If you are not willing to do this, you may as well invest in other initiatives.</p>
<h3><strong>Is Marketing Automation Right for Your Business?</strong></h3>
<p>There’s no simple way to determine whether Marketing Automation software is a good investment for your business.  However the following considerations may help you decide whether it might be right for you.</p>
<p><strong>Marketing Tools Used</strong>: The more marketing tools you use, the more difficult it is to effectively track your customer’s journey to sale. A business with a lot of different tools is more likely to see benefit in combining them to one platform. If you don’t use many tools and consistently deliver great results from your marketing – you’re not likely to need Marketing Automation.</p>
<p><strong>The Customer Journey: </strong>If your customer takes a short and simple path from awareness to action, Marketing Automation may be an unnecessary expense. The longer and more complex the path, the more likely it is that marketing automation would be useful. Furthermore, Marketing Automation is useful for repeat customers.</p>
<p><strong>Willingness to Adapt: </strong>Marketing Automation will only work for you if your business is willing to dedicate energy, time, money and resources into ensuring it will be successful.</p>
<p>When customers are thoroughly nurtured throughout the whole buying process, they are more likely to develop a relationship with your brand and keep coming back.  As with any relationship, you get out what you put in, so if you go down the route of Marketing Automation make sure you’re willing to give it the time and effort it deserves.  Not only will you reap the rewards of a highly satisfied client base, but you’ll earn kudos as one of the B2B brands staying ahead of the curve.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Need a <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/">B2B Marketing Consultant Melbourne</a>? then contact the team at the Lead Agency today! And make sure you don’t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-your-business/">Marketing Automation &#038; Your Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Automation Strategies For Successful Lead Conversion</title>
		<link>/marketing-automation-strategies-for-successful-lead-conversion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 03:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lead Generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The term “Marketing Automation” has become a buzz-word, with many marketers under the impression that all digital marketing tools, including those specific to lead generation and overall growth, fall under the category of Marketing Automation. This misconception often leads to unsuccessful automated marketing efforts that do not speak to specific prospect needs and challenges. It [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-strategies-for-successful-lead-conversion/">Marketing Automation Strategies For Successful Lead Conversion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The term “Marketing Automation” has become a buzz-word, with many marketers under the impression that all <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">digital marketing</a> tools, including those specific to <a href="/lead-generation/">lead generation</a> and overall growth, fall under the category of Marketing Automation. This misconception often leads to unsuccessful automated marketing efforts that do not speak to specific prospect needs and challenges.</p>
<p>It is a common misconception, but let me assure you, that Marketing Automation is not just a fancy name for email marketing! Marketing Automation is any trigger-induced action in a campaign and can take place across all channels – from direct mail and phone campaigns to online and social initiatives.</p>
<p>Marketers must realise that Marketing Automation does not do the lead generation and conversion for you. Genuine prospects must be fed into the marketing funnel in order to see benefits and conversions from automated marketing efforts. Feeding a pre-purchased database of emails the same automated content will only be thought of as spam and isn’t likely to result in genuine leads and customers. Successful automated marketing must draw insights from the myriad of systems available to your company, including Customer Relationship Management (CRM) systems, lead management systems and web analytics to name a few.</p>
<p>The following <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-marketing-strategies/">strategies</a> can help you to utilise Marketing Automation properly:</p>
<h2><strong>Drip Marketing</strong></h2>
<p>Drip marketing solves the problem faced by using email newsletters. Whilst email newsletters are a great way to send out your latest announcements, new subscribers only ever see new emails and may never get exposure to your earlier content.</p>
<p>Drip Marketing is a strategy whereby a constant flow of marketing material is sent out to customers over a period of time. The aim being to create sales through long-term, repeat exposure of goods or services that engage, nurture and build loyalty.</p>
<p>These marketing messages often take the form of emails but it is important to note that social media posts, postcards, phone calls, brochures, and printed newsletters are also forms of drip marketing. All of which can, and arguably should, be automated to ensure efficient use of your marketing teams time.</p>
<p>Drip Marketing can be based off a predetermined timeline whereby certain content is fed to the customer at certain times after their initial sign-up, or it can be trigger-induced whereby certain actions will prompt automated marketing materials to be sent i.e. signing up for a service, downloading content or making a purchase could result in certain emails being sent or phone communication being initiated.</p>
<p>Many forms of drip marketing rely on the &#8220;Law of 29&#8221;, which states that most prospects will not buy something until they see an ad for it at least 29 times [Investopedia, 2015]. Ensuring 29 interactions are made with each prospect would be a huge task for any marketing team! Automating the process makes for efficient promotion and higher conversion likelihood.</p>
<h2><strong>Segmentation</strong></h2>
<p>By dividing your contact list for <a href="/lead-generation/lead-nurturing/">lead nurturing</a> based on behaviour, position, industry, company size, geography or any other useful variables you gain the ability to tailor your automated content so that it is more relevant to who you are contacting. One way to determine how you will segment your contacts is to first define a buyer persona, or in other words, who your ideal customer would be. Actionable buyer personas reveal insights about your buyers’ decisions — the specific attitudes, concerns and criteria that drive prospective customers to choose you, your competitor or the status quo. The more personalised your content is to your customer, the higher your chances of interaction and future <a href="/lead-generation/engage-your-targets/">conversion</a>.</p>
<p>Lead scoring is a great way to segment your contacts for your sales team! Scoring is done by determining a ranking for each contact based on certain variables, such as those listed above, the higher the score the better quality the prospective lead and thus the higher chance that nurturing will result in a conversion. Among companies that implemented scoring techniques to better target their marketing, 38% experience higher conversion rates of qualified leads into opportunities, while 31% saw boosts in productivity within their sales department and reduced sales cycles. [SocialGarden, 2015]
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B Marketing Automation</a> is just one component in the middle of a successful sales funnel, but if it is done well, it can mark the difference between lapsed or converted leads.</p>
<p>Want to know more about <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">email marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">b2b adwords</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">b2b SEO</a>? Then contact the experts at the Lead Agency today for more details.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/marketing-automation-strategies-for-successful-lead-conversion/">Marketing Automation Strategies For Successful Lead Conversion</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 Marketing Automation Statistics Your CEO Should Know</title>
		<link>/9-marketing-automation-statistics-your-ceo-should-know/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 03:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The latest buzzword in B2B marketing; marketing automation is a sophisticated software solution that focuses on nurturing customer leads. From the moment the consumer enters the top of the marketing funnel, marketing automation helps guide them through to purchase. As the uptake of Marketing Automation increases, The Lead Agency looks at the statistics behind the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/9-marketing-automation-statistics-your-ceo-should-know/">9 Marketing Automation Statistics Your CEO Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest buzzword in B2B marketing; marketing automation is a sophisticated software solution that focuses on nurturing customer leads. From the moment the consumer enters the top of the marketing funnel, marketing automation helps guide them through to purchase.</p>
<p>As the uptake of Marketing Automation increases, The Lead Agency looks at the statistics behind the marketing platform that shouldn&#8217;t be ignored.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/9-Marketing-Automation-Stats-You-Should-Know.png"><img class="alignnone wp-image-2458 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/9-Marketing-Automation-Stats-You-Should-Know.png" alt="9 Marketing Automation Stats You Should Know" width="1280" height="2000" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/9-Marketing-Automation-Stats-You-Should-Know.png 1280w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/05/9-Marketing-Automation-Stats-You-Should-Know-192x300.png 192w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/05/9-Marketing-Automation-Stats-You-Should-Know-655x1024.png 655w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /></a></p>
<p>If your company is interested in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B marketing automation</a> for better business outcomes, get in touch with The Lead Agency today. We are a team of skilled <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/">B2B marketing consultants</a> who assist companies like yours in developing effective, measurable, and feasible <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategies</a> that will help you remain competitive in today&#8217;s market.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/9-marketing-automation-statistics-your-ceo-should-know/">9 Marketing Automation Statistics Your CEO Should Know</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Common Mistakes with Marketing Automation</title>
		<link>/5-common-mistakes-with-marketing-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 04:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2258</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Marketing Automation is being adopted by organisations at faster rates than ever before [Sirius Decisions B-to-B Marketing Automation Study 2014]. When implemented well it can drive significant growth in businesses both large and small, but get it wrong and it can prove a costly misadventure. 42% of CRM users are planning to increase their marketing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-common-mistakes-with-marketing-automation/">5 Common Mistakes with Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marketing Automation is being adopted by organisations at faster rates than ever before [Sirius Decisions B-to-B Marketing Automation Study 2014]. When implemented well it can drive significant growth in businesses both large and small, but get it wrong and it can prove a costly misadventure.</p>
<p>42% of CRM users are planning to increase their marketing automation spending in 2015 [<a href="http://www.softwareadvice.com/au/crm/">Software Advice</a>: ‘Customer Relationship Management Software Userview’ (2014)]. If you’re one considering implementing marketing automation as part of your strategy please take heed and avoid the most common marketing automation blunders.</p>
<h2><span style="line-height: 1.5;">1. </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">Lack of Strategy</strong></h2>
<p>With the buzz surrounding marketing automation and its promises of more, better quality leads, it’s easy to be drawn in by the hype. However, investing in marketing automation should be a carefully considered decision. In order to be successful, it must fit in to your company’s overall goals and larger growth strategy.</p>
<p>You should think about the costs involved in running and maintaining the platform in terms of staff and resources. Marketing automation is only as good as the person behind it, so ensure you have the time and dedication to properly set up and monitor the platform. Learn more about <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B marketing automation</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="line-height: 1.5;">2. </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">No Segmentation &amp; Targeting</strong></h2>
<p>Marketing automation provides a way to communicate tailored content to an appropriate audience. Take the time to segment and target your leads properly in order to communicate more effectively with them.</p>
<p>Segment your database based on relevant factors such as demographics, interests, behaviors and interaction with your company. Putting in this extra effort will lead to innumerable rewards when it comes to sales.</p>
<h2><span style="line-height: 1.5;">3. </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">Lack of Good Content</strong></h2>
<p>Content marketing is at the heart of marketing automation. Many companies make the mistake of producing content to fill quotas as opposed to content that truly engages their audience. Sending out bad content is worse than sending out no content at all.</p>
<p>The content you send out can be used to gauge interest, generate engagement and capture leads, so it’s imperative to spend some time developing your strategy. Define your buyer persona and what will interest them at each stage of buyer readiness and you’ll be able to produce high quality content that your prospects enjoy. Find out how <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a> strategies can help you yield better leads.</p>
<h2><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">4. Being Too Sales-Focused</strong></h2>
<p>The end goal of marketing automation is to send more sales-ready leads to your sales team for conversion. However the buying process can be a long one and leads need to be nurtured, rather than sold to along the way.</p>
<p>During the nurturing phase, you should send useful content that will have value for your customers.   News articles, industry trends and reports that are relevant to your brand should be crafted for your audience. Once your lead is engaged, you can start sending more product-related content, but don’t undo the hard work you’ve done to get them there by being too sales-focused. Discover the different steps in the <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B lead generation</a> process.</p>
<h2><strong style="line-height: 1.5;">5. Not Paying Enough Attention</strong></h2>
<p>Don’t set up your marketing automation system and leave it to run. To get the most out of your system, you should review and refine your strategy regularly to optimize your results.</p>
<p>Test different ideas and find the approach that best works for you and your customers. The more you test, the more you will learn, and the more successful your efforts will ultimately be. Remember that in such a dynamic marketing environment, your strategies can always be improved upon.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Marketing automation is one of the fastest growing sectors in today’s marketing technology sector, which isn’t surprising considering 75% of companies using it see ROI in just 12 months [Focus Research (2013)]. But as with any marketing strategy, you get what you put in. So if you do go down the route of marketing automation make sure you’re willing to give it the time and effort it deserves. To learn more about <a href="/the-key-elements-of-the-b2b-marketing-mix/">B2B marketing</a>, get in touch with The Lead Agency today.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-common-mistakes-with-marketing-automation/">5 Common Mistakes with Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Now Is the Time To Embrace Business Marketing Automation</title>
		<link>/embrace-business-marketing-automation-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 12:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Business marketing is at the crux of any company’s success. As imperative B2B marketing is, it is dauntingly complicated. Many companies invest fairly in various kinds of marketing but they fail to assess the return on investment. Without assessing the returns, investments in business marketing can never be deemed a success or a failure. It [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/embrace-business-marketing-automation-now/">Now Is the Time To Embrace Business Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Business Marketing" href="/">Business marketing</a> is at the crux of any company’s success. As imperative <a href="/the-key-elements-of-the-b2b-marketing-mix/">B2B marketing</a> is, it is dauntingly complicated. Many companies invest fairly in various kinds of marketing but they fail to assess the return on investment. Without assessing the returns, investments in business marketing can never be deemed a success or a failure.</p>
<p>It is this primary or basic need that makes marketing automation unavoidable for most businesses.</p>
<p>There are various kinds of marketing and with new mediums and platforms evolving with each passing year, the competition is going to get fiercer and it would be more complicated to determine the budget for business marketing and how exactly one should go about executing the various strategies. A company needs deft marketers and the right marketing technology is also just as significant.</p>
<p>Before delving into why 2015 is the year when businesses should embrace marketing automation, let us briefly discuss what it does. Business marketing automation involves systemically automating as many repeatable or systematic tasks that are being done manually. But that is not where its utility ends. <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B marketing automation</a> encompasses every aspect of marketing. It monitors all marketing content so the subsequent impact can be assessed and adjusted.</p>
<p>Automation takes care of capturing and using crucial data pertaining to how leads are generated, what kinds of leads are generated and how they are being worked on. Through the automation of regular communications with prospects and leads, marketing departments can turn cold prospects into hot leads for the sales department to close. Even greater, using agreed lead scoring criteria, sales versus marketing arguments can be reduced as both sides agree what is an actionable lead.</p>
<p>From lead to sale conversion rates to repeat purchases, measuring overall customer experience to highlighting the loopholes or the effective practices in an entire <a href="/b2b-marketing-sydney/">B2B marketing</a> campaign or strategy, automation sheds light on every aspect of business marketing.</p>
<p>Contact management, lead scoring and lead nurturing, list segmentation, email marketing, content performance measurement and its subsequent reporting and even trials or tests of website pages and various kinds of promotions or offers; everything can be managed, assessed and inferred upon using marketing automation.</p>
<p>Now, it is estimated that in the year 2015 the industry of automation marketing will grow to be worth US$4.8 billion globally. At a time when businesses are pressed for time and resources because of the increased activity in the virtual sphere which one cannot ignore, business marketing automation is imperative.</p>
<p>Get in touch with <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B marketing consultants</a> at The Lead Agency today to learn more about how business marketing can benefit your company.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/embrace-business-marketing-automation-now/">Now Is the Time To Embrace Business Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Difference Between Email Marketing &#038; Marketing Automation</title>
		<link>/the-difference-between-email-marketing-marketing-automation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 04:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Automation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The latest buzzword in B2B marketing, marketing automation is a sophisticated software solution that focuses on nurturing customer leads. Email marketing is one of the most commonly used platforms within the wider marketing automation strategy, which often leads to confusion between the two. The main difference between B2B email marketing and B2B marketing automation is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-difference-between-email-marketing-marketing-automation/">The Difference Between Email Marketing &#038; Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest buzzword in <a href="/the-key-elements-of-the-b2b-marketing-mix/">B2B marketing</a>, marketing automation is a sophisticated software solution that focuses on nurturing customer leads. Email marketing is one of the most commonly used platforms within the wider marketing automation strategy, which often leads to confusion between the two.</p>
<p>The main difference between <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B marketing automation</a> is intelligence. With email marketing, you send a blast and analyse clicks and open rates. Marketing automation records every touch your company makes with a prospect, telling you not only who opened and clicked through your email but also which pages they viewed on your website and for how long, whether they’ve read your social media, filled out your survey or read your blog post.</p>
<p>Marketing automation provides superior functionality than email marketing alone.</p>
<h2><strong>Lead Scoring</strong></h2>
<p>With email marketing, best practice is to send an email blast, track click through and open rates and pass warm leads to your sales team to close. Many of these leads however are not fully qualified. As they are not ready to buy, the sales team often fails to see the results they hoped for.</p>
<p>Marketing automation scores leads based on how they engage with your campaigns and content across a number of platforms, as well as demographic statistics and characteristics. Once your leads reach a threshold score they are qualified as ‘sales ready’ and can be passed on to your sales team, who are likely to see a higher success rate.</p>
<h2><strong>Lead Nurturing</strong></h2>
<p>It can be difficult to keep your leads engaged with email marketing alone. Typically, marketers send email blasts to a huge database of leads, with little idea as to where they are in the buying cycle, or whether the content is truly resonating with them.</p>
<p>Marketing automation employs lead scoring which allows you to deliver content that’s relevant to your lead depending on the stage they are at in the buying cycle. With a better understanding of your consumer’s situation, you are able to tailor content that really speaks to them and moves them through the buying cycle to sale. Learn more about <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B lead generation</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Scalability</strong></h2>
<p>Basic email marketing can be difficult to scale for growing companies. The more leads you have in your database and the more content you want to send out, the more time consuming the task can be.</p>
<p>Marketing automation is more ready to meet the demands of a growing customer base. 36% of Marketers who have adopted marketing automation stated the biggest benefit to be taking repetitive tasks out of marketers’ hands, so they can work on other projects [<a href="https://www.redeye.com/insights/white-papers">Redeye</a> and TFM&amp;A Insights &#8220;The Marketing Automation Report 2014&#8221; (2014)]. The functionality of marketing automation allows you to efficiently run a number of campaigns at once and create lead nurturing programs and lead scoring to attribute revenue directly to each marketing program.</p>
<h2><strong>Analysis</strong></h2>
<p>It can be difficult to show how email marketing contributes to your bottom line revenue. Marketing automation provides functionality that tracks your efforts and provides in depth analytics for each campaign. You can also sync up your marketing automation system with your CRM to get even more in-depth data.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The case for marketing automation has never been stronger with 75% of companies that implement it seeing considerable ROI in just 12 months [Focus Research, 2013]. Email marketing remains a valuable tool in any marketing strategy, and marketing automation has demonstrated that when it’s an integral part of a well thought-out marketing plan, results can be astounding.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B Email Marketing</a> read our article on <a href="/thank-emails-important-b2b-marketing-strategy/">Thank-You Emails Are The Most Important B2B Marketing Strategy </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-difference-between-email-marketing-marketing-automation/">The Difference Between Email Marketing &#038; Marketing Automation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
