<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Law Firm Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/law-firm-marketing-blogs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:03:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Law Firm Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Build Your Client Base Through Effective Law Firm Marketing</title>
		<link>/how-to-build-your-client-base-through-effective-law-firm-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 05:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Law Firm Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>During 2017, 63% of Australian law firms identified securing new clients as one of their top business challenges. In an increasingly competitive and dynamic sector, attracting and winning high-quality leads is incredibly important. If you’re serious about doing just that, it’s crucial that you establish a strong, unanimous understanding of your business’ target audience company-wide. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-build-your-client-base-through-effective-law-firm-marketing/">How to Build Your Client Base Through Effective Law Firm Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During 2017, <a href="https://www.lawyersweekly.com.au/biglaw/21770-law-firms-top-5-business-challenges-revealed">63% of Australian law firms</a> identified securing new clients as one of their top business challenges.</p>
<p>In an increasingly competitive and dynamic sector, attracting and winning high-quality leads is incredibly important. If you’re serious about doing just that, it’s crucial that you establish a strong, unanimous understanding of your business’ target audience company-wide.</p>
<p>What are your consumers’ distinct needs and defining characteristics? By building a comprehensive profile of your ideal customer, you can cultivate strategic direction that’s embraced across all organisational levels.</p>
<p>Prospects are expecting the same professional service they’ve always demanded, but are now pushing more than ever before for it to be delivered at a price that they believe is justified. If your law firm is unable to clearly and convincingly communicate the value of your legal assistance, you’ll likely struggle to grow your business and clientele.</p>
<p>If you’re not sure where to begin, but want to drive results, optimising your <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm’s marketing strategy</a> is a great place to start. By doing this, you can build a strong brand presence in the legal sector, helping you define and accurately represent what sets your company apart from the rest.</p>
<p>Discover the power of exceptional <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a> and start reaching more, valuable members of your target audience with strong purchase intent.</p>
<h2>Invest in Local Search Engine Optimisation</h2>
<p>When deciding on a law firm to represent them, your target audience will likely be <a href="https://www.lyfemarketing.com/blog/law-firm-marketing-ideas/">looking for professionals in their general area</a>.</p>
<p>By seeking legal assistance from a local law firm, individuals give themselves the ability to meet and communicate with their lawyer easily. If your online domains aren’t optimised to attract such clients, you may be stunting your overall growth in the market.<em> </em></p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/local-seo-stats"><em>92% of searchers</em></a><em> will pick businesses on the first page of local search results.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>There are various strategic steps you can take to increase your ranking in the local search engine results pages (SERPs) and, consequently, drive more relevant leads.</p>
<p>When it comes to local <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">search engine optimisation</a>, <a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2018/10/12/local-seo">establishing a presence on Google My Business</a> is crucial. Claiming and verifying your company is cost-free and relatively straightforward, but can boost your ranking significantly. Your business will be displayed on Google Maps and, in most cases, listed above the organic search results.</p>
<p>By optimising your website in this way, you can make it more accessible to prospects who are searching for the distinct services you offer in their area. This can, in turn, assist your business in driving more relevant traffic to your website, all the while attracting individuals with clear purchase intent.</p>
<p>To truly excel in your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">local SEO</a> efforts, there are numerous measures your law firm can take. These include the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>When setting up Google My Business, include your logo, hours of operation, and images that accurately reflect your branding;</li>
<li>Ensure the information you provide is accurate, up-to-date and consistent;</li>
<li>Encourage clients to share reviews and, of course, make sure to include a sincere response;</li>
<li>Conduct keyword research that targets terms that relate to both your business and the area within which you operate. When doing this, using long-tail keywords can be particularly effective, as they’re highly specific;</li>
<li>Optimise your website for mobile devices.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/local-seo-stats"><em>88% of consumers</em></a><em> who do a local search on their smartphone visit or call a store within a day.”</em></p></blockquote>
<h2>Leverage Case Studies &amp; Testimonials to Build Trust</h2>
<p>Often, those seeking your assistance are fighting incredibly personal cases and, in some instances, they may incur significant penalties if their efforts are unsuccessful. Thus, if your prospects don’t trust you, it’s highly unlikely that they’ll decide to proceed with your guidance.</p>
<p>In this way, sharing <a href="https://www.atlantalegalmarketing.com/case-studies-build-credibility-trust-law-firms-need-grow-client-base/">case studies and testimonials</a> from previous, satisfied clients can be an incredibly compelling and persuasive way to build greater trust with prospects. Essentially, you can highlight past successes and demonstrate your expertise, all the while establishing credibility.</p>
<p>You can advocate tirelessly for your law firm; however, without case studies and powerful testimonials from past clients to back up your claims, such endorsement may hold little value. With the support of your previous or existing clients, you can assure members of your target audience that your legal services are as brilliant as you say they are.</p>
<p>Case studies and testimonials paint a picture of the type of experience clients can expect from your law firm, lowering or completely alleviating doubts that may be holding prospects back.</p>
<p>By including content of this nature across your website and promotional material, you can also further differentiate your law firm from competitors. Through the incorporation of case studies and testimonials, you have the opportunity to share accounts from real people that highlight your expertise. In doing this, you can clearly articulate what makes your legal services different and establish your firm as a leader in the sector.</p>
<h2>Speak With an Expert<strong> </strong></h2>
<p>If you’re interested in building a strong <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a> strategy, get in touch with the Lead Agency today. Our marketing professionals can help your law firm drive more relevant leads and grow your clientele, all the while establishing a strong <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">brand</a> in the legal sector.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-build-your-client-base-through-effective-law-firm-marketing/">How to Build Your Client Base Through Effective Law Firm Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Build an Exceptional Law Firm Marketing Website</title>
		<link>/how-to-build-an-exceptional-law-firm-marketing-website/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 05:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Law Firm Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When prospects are searching for you or the service you offer online, they’ll likely end up at your website. Thus, your digital domains will often contribute significantly to potential consumers’ first impression of your law firm. This can be both a blessing and a demise, depending on the overall message that your website conveys to [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-build-an-exceptional-law-firm-marketing-website/">How to Build an Exceptional Law Firm Marketing Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When prospects are searching for you or the service you offer online, they’ll likely end up at your website. Thus, your digital domains will often contribute significantly to potential consumers’ first impression of your <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm</a>. This can be both a blessing and a demise, depending on the overall message that your website conveys to consumers.</p>
<p>Having a poorly designed, difficult to navigate website is arguably going to leave you worse off than no website at all. While lacking an online presence altogether is unfavourable, the bad impression left by a confusing, unappealing website can be difficult to come back from.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://johnkramer.marketing/blog/20-statistics-about-website-design-in-2019/"><em>88% of online consumers</em></a><em> are less likely to return to a site if they’ve had a bad experience.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>If you’ve decided to build your brand presence online, or you’ve already created a website that isn’t meeting performance objectives, the time to take action is now.</p>
<p>Does your online domain accurately and effectively display the legislative expertise of your team, the exceptional service you offer and your ability to meet user’s needs better than competitors? If not, you may struggle to reach your organisational goals, <a href="/lead-generation/">generate more valuable leads</a> and remain competitive in an increasingly volatile market.</p>
<p>Your law firm’s current (or non-existent) website could be holding you back from reaching your full potential. Want to drive conversions and boost consumer’s engagement with your brand? If so, this article is for you. Find out how to revitalise your online presence and create a website that aids in your law firm’s growth, rather than hindering it.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7516" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Consistency-Website-Wide.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Consistency-Website-Wide.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Consistency-Website-Wide-450x210.jpg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<h2>Consistency Website-Wide</h2>
<p>Having a consistent design across your entire website is crucial, and there’s more than one reason why this is the case.</p>
<p>For starters, think about an inconsistent website from the user’s standpoint. The domain’s usability is considerably lowered, making it confusing for individuals to navigate.</p>
<p>It’s no surprise that, if prospects have difficulty finding what they’re searching for on your website, they’ll more than likely look elsewhere.</p>
<p>When designing your website, finding the balance between a layout and design that’s consistent and straightforward but still creative and engaging is crucial. This can be difficult, so if you’re not sure where to begin, we’d suggest getting in touch with a professional to discuss your options.</p>
<p>After just <a href="https://conversionxl.com/blog/first-impressions-matter-the-importance-of-great-visual-design/">17milliseconds on your website</a>, users will form an opinion on its layout and style, which, of course, contributes to their perception of your <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm</a>. Ensuring that your online domains accurately and clearly convey your <a href="https://practice.findlaw.com/law-marketing/top-ten-usability-tips-for-your-law-firm-website.html">brand identity</a> is key when it comes to making a great first impression. A consistent website design makes sure that this message isn’t lost as individuals continue to navigate your online domain.</p>
<p>By maintaining consistency website-wide, you can also reinforce your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branding</a>. In doing this, you’ll be able to effectively communicate the same brand message and theme across all of your webpages. In turn, this allows for you to reinforce who you are, the service you offer, and why your law firm’s service is superior to alternative providers.</p>
<h2>Optimised Contact Forms</h2>
<p>When a consumer decides to fill out a contact form on your website, they are, of course, showing clear purchase intent. By <a href="https://business.tutsplus.com/articles/top-law-firm-website-design--cms-31046">simplifying the process</a>, you can avoid overwhelming and, ultimately, deterring prospects from completing and submitting your form.</p>
<p>Essentially, you’re aiming to lower barriers that may otherwise prompt potential customers to stop writing their enquiry. For instance, if the form is overly lengthy and time-consuming, includes confusing questions or has coding issues that prevent users from entering their details into certain fields.</p>
<p>As mentioned, any forms on your website should be relatively straightforward. They’re a way for consumers to lodge enquiries and request more information, while simultaneously giving you the opportunity to wean out any cases that aren’t suited to your firm. In the long run, this can save you both time and money, as you’re not wasting resources on cases that aren’t actually relevant to your legal practice.</p>
<p><em>So, what fields should you include?</em></p>
<p>In most cases, law firms only need to ask for the user’s name, email address, phone number and the purpose of their enquiry. Once you’ve determined that a particular enquiry seems legitimate and applicable to the services you offer, you can simply reach out to the individual and schedule a meeting to get more details.</p>
<p>Want to find out more about <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a>? If you’re interested in taking your law firm’s website to the next level, get in touch with the Lead Agency today. With extensive experience building advanced, effective digital domains, you can rely on our team to deliver exceptional results. Contact us for professional assistance in developing your <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing strategy</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-build-an-exceptional-law-firm-marketing-website/">How to Build an Exceptional Law Firm Marketing Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Website Design Tips to Generate Leads for Law Firms</title>
		<link>/website-design-tips-to-generate-leads-for-law-firms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 01:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Law Firm Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The legal industry can be a competitive one to operate in, so it’s important to ensure your law firm stands out to attract clients. In order to do this, you need a solid law firm marketing strategy. 81% of people will perform some type of online research before making a large purchase, so your website is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/website-design-tips-to-generate-leads-for-law-firms/">Website Design Tips to Generate Leads for Law Firms</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The legal industry can be a competitive one to operate in, so it’s important to ensure your law firm stands out to attract clients. In order to do this, you need a solid <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a> strategy.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.breezyhillmarketing.com/10-helpful-seo-stats-for-2017-planning">81% of people will perform some type of online research before making a large purchase</a>, so your website is the obvious starting point. Your website is your online ‘storefront’ that can show prospective clients what you have to offer. It should demonstrate that your law firm has the skills and the knowledge to take on their case, and win.</p>
<p>The following are some of the elements that will help to make your site more visible in search engines in order to drive traffic to it, and generate more leads for your business.</p>
<h2><strong>Create a</strong><strong> Google My Business Listing</strong></h2>
<p>This is one of the quickest and easiest things that you can do to ensure your law firm website is findable on Google. Creating a listing on Google My Business is free and requires minimal marketing or technical knowledge. All you have to do is set up an account and enter basic business information such as your name, location, website, and industry.</p>
<p>You also have the option of adding more in-depth information about your business, such as your business hours, a description of what you do, reviews, and images. With a Google My Business Listing, you are more likely to be found when someone performs a Google search for lawyers near them.</p>
<h2><strong>Use Search Engine Optimisation on the Website</strong></h2>
<p>SEO is vital for ensuring your website is as visible as possible on the search engine results pages. If your site is built on WordPress, there are some built-in SEO features that you can make use of, as well as some SEO plugins that allow you to optimise your website and your content for search engines. There are also a number of <a href="https://business.tutsplus.com/articles/best-lawyer-wordpress-themes--cms-29537">lawyer WordPress themes</a> available that have been optimised for SEO.</p>
<p>In addition to choosing a theme that is optimised for SEO, the following are some of the other things that you can do to improve SEO on your site:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use relevant keywords on the page, but don’t stuff your posts and pages with keywords as search engines may see this as spam and penalise your website.</li>
<li>Ensure images have appropriate alt tags and names so that search engines can better understand them.</li>
<li>Format your text so that it is easier to read. This means that both search engines and users can easily identify what your pages and posts are about.</li>
<li>Add relevant internal links to important pages and posts. Ensure that the text for the hyperlink contains relevant keywords, rather than words like ‘click here’ as this helps search engines determine that the links are pointing to relevant sources.</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-7544" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/testimonials-1024x538.png" alt="" width="1020" height="536" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/testimonials-1024x538.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/testimonials-450x236.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/testimonials-768x403.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1020px) 100vw, 1020px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Share Testimonials and Achievements </strong></h2>
<p>Testimonials are one of the most powerful forms of content marketing. In fact, <a href="https://searchengineland.com/88-consumers-trust-online-reviews-much-personal-recommendations-195803">88% of consumers trust online reviews as much as personal recommendations</a>. Testimonials from clients that you’ve worked with help to build trust and credibility in your business from other prospective clients. As such, when website visitors see that you have taken on and won cases that are similar to theirs, they will be more inclined to schedule a consultation. Testimonials can be used in a number of places, for example, on the homepage, on campaign landing pages, on a dedicated testimonial page on the site or on the individual profiles of the lawyers involved in the case.</p>
<p>Listing any awards and achievements of the company or lawyers within the firm is another great way to build credibility and trust with potential clients, while also promoting your skills as a firm. These achievements can be added to the individual profile of the lawyers that were awarded them, as well as on the homepage and landing pages.</p>
<h2><strong>Use Calls-to-Action</strong></h2>
<p>The main goal of your website is to move visitors through the stages of the buyer journey to conversion. Put simply, you want them to go from being aware of your firm and the services that it provides to requesting a consultation or getting in touch with you. To ensure they do this, you need to lead them through the website using compelling content and calls-to-action that facilitate them getting in touch with you.</p>
<p>Calls-to-action should be used on every page of your site, from the homepage to the about page and lawyer’s profile pages. You can also include a call-to-action on any blog pages that you have.</p>
<p>For more information on creating a law firm website, or for help with your wider <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a> strategy, get in touch with the <a href="/">B2B marketing</a> experts at the Lead Agency.</p>
<p>Want to proactively plan for future success? Start developing your business&#8217; strategy for next year with our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/website-design-tips-to-generate-leads-for-law-firms/">Website Design Tips to Generate Leads for Law Firms</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Optimise Your Law Firm Marketing Strategy</title>
		<link>/how-to-optimise-your-law-firm-marketing-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Law Firm Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Like many other industries, Australia’s legal landscape is constantly evolving. In order to stay relevant, law firms have to keep on top of the external factors that impact their industry and the overall environment that shapes consumer behaviour. The innovation of technology has lead to humans collaborating with machines, manual tasks becoming automated and a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-law-firm-marketing-strategy/">How to Optimise Your Law Firm Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like many other industries, Australia’s legal landscape is constantly evolving. In order to stay relevant, law firms have to keep on top of the external factors that impact their industry and the overall environment that shapes consumer behaviour.</p>
<p>The innovation of technology has lead to humans collaborating with machines, manual tasks becoming automated and a change in traditional career paths, as well as new jobs being created. For the legal sector, this has been particularly difficult as <a href="https://home.kpmg/au/en/home/insights/2018/07/future-of-work-legal-sector.html">law firms are typically very traditional</a> in terms of hierarchies and operational factors such as manual research and time-based billing.</p>
<p>It is more important than ever for these companies to innovate and make the most of the technologies that are available to them. The same can be said for their marketing strategy.</p>
<p>Law firm marketers have to master the same range of platforms, channels and strategies as other marketers to run their campaigns. In addition, they have to sell legal services, which is extremely challenging for a number of reasons.</p>
<h2><strong>Why Is Law Firm Marketing So Difficult?</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>Educating the Client</strong></h3>
<p>Educating consumers is necessary for every industry, but is particularly important when it comes to legal services, where clients have something at stake, such as their money, freedom or reputation. If the client doesn’t fully understand their situation and the legal services that they need, it can have catastrophic consequences.</p>
<p>As such, it’s important for law firms to develop content that is educational and distribute it as part of their overall marketing strategy. This can help set the foundation for developing healthy long-term relationships with clients.</p>
<h3><strong>Resistance to Marketing Tactics</strong></h3>
<p>It can be difficult to get the whole business on board with a <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a> strategy. Traditional law firm marketing is very dependent on networking, so convincing lawyers that any marketing strategy is worthwhile can be challenging. Many lawyers are still stuck in their ways and think that their tried and tested networking tactics are the only way to bring in new clients. As such, any marketing strategy that is proposed should be well considered and targeted with outlined KPIs that will help the C level executives measure its success.</p>
<h3><strong>Lawyer Reputation</strong></h3>
<p>A Pew Research Study <a href="http://www.pewforum.org/2013/07/11/public-esteem-for-military-still-high/">showed that lawyers were considered to contribute the least to society</a>, of the occupations listed. This is, of course, completely inaccurate as lawyers spend their time fighting for rights and laws. However, as they were traditionally aggressive marketers, the industry got a reputation as an ego-based profession, with consumers viewing lawyers as arrogant and self-centred.</p>
<p>The best way to overcome this is to be transparent with marketing and clearly define the types of cases and clients you want. This ties into educating your clients.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Overcome Marketing Challenges in Legal Marketing</strong></h2>
<p>The key to any successful marketing strategy is to differentiate your offering from your competitors through your unique selling proposition. This comes from understanding your client’s motivation and buying behaviour to identify the most effective marketing communications.</p>
<h3><strong>Ensure Your Marketing Is Measurable</strong></h3>
<p>As mentioned above, you will likely have to convince your managers that your campaigns are working. Without metrics, this is not possible. Measuring the performance of all of your campaigns also helps you assign your budget effectively between channels and optimise campaigns that are working well.</p>
<p><a href="https://analytics.google.com/analytics/web/">Google Analytics</a> is a free tool that can give you access to all the data you could need to inform your online campaigns. The program can arms marketers with advanced metrics and data about website traffic. It gives granular information about how users interact with your site and the channels that got them there, which is invaluable in informing wider marketing strategies as well as specific changes to pages and elements on your site that can impact results.</p>
<h3><strong>Create a Content Marketing Strategy</strong></h3>
<p>High-quality content is vital for an effective law firm website. This can be in the form of both written content such as articles, blogs and white papers are well as visual content such as infographics and video. All content should be informational and aimed to educate clients on the services you provide so that they can evaluate whether you are a viable option for them.</p>
<p>Content should also be written in a way that engages readers and moves them further through the buyer journey. In order to define content that is most effective in doing this, you can look at the current articles and pages on your website to see which are working best for you. Going forward, you can then use this knowledge to create a range of content around the topics and themes that are of interest to your audience.</p>
<h3><strong>Encourage Referrals &amp; Up Sell to Existing Clients </strong></h3>
<p>It&#8217;s much <a href="https://www.larrybodine.com/articles.asp?Action=GetOneArticle&amp;ArticleID=70">easier to open a new file from a current client than it is to attract a new client</a>. It&#8217;s also easier and more cost effective to get a referral from a satisfied client than it is to generate leads through advertising.</p>
<p>In terms of getting more work from existing clients, this comes down to cultivating the relationship and regularly communicating with them – not just getting in touch when you’re doing work for them.</p>
<p>Generating referrals is slightly more difficult but a referral strategy can help with this. Clients are the best place to start. If they are happy with the work that you’re doing, they are likely to refer you to someone else in their network that may be looking for your services. If you want them to do this, you have to tell them. Get in touch with them and let them know the type of work you are looking for and ask if they know someone who may be interested. In addition to clients, you can look to people you have connections with, in other professions to generate referrals for your business. For example, investment brokers, accountants, and bankers you have dealt with are likely to be happy to send business to you as long as you’ve done a good job for them.</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we’ve worked with a number of Law Firms to boost their marketing campaigns and generate leads for their business. If you need help with your <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">law firm marketing</a>, get in touch with us today. And don&#8217;t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-law-firm-marketing-strategy/">How to Optimise Your Law Firm Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
