<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Education Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/b2b-education-marketing-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Education Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>4 Essential Components of Your Higher Education Marketing Strategy</title>
		<link>/4-essential-components-of-your-higher-education-marketing-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 23:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7622</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The modern business landscape is continually evolving, adjusting to the forever changing needs of society. The higher education system has not been immune to such advancements, and like many other sectors, has diversified into an incredibly complex and large-scale industry. While 40% of all school leavers now pursue undergraduate degrees, this was not always the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/4-essential-components-of-your-higher-education-marketing-strategy/">4 Essential Components of Your Higher Education Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The modern business landscape is continually evolving, adjusting to the forever changing needs of society. The higher education system has not been immune to such advancements, and like many other sectors, has diversified into an incredibly complex and large-scale industry.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2016/jun/24/has-university-life-changed-student-experience-past-present-parents-vox-pops">40% of all school leavers</a> now pursue undergraduate degrees, this was not always the case. In fact, during the early 1960s, a mere 4% of high school graduates enrolled in university. Such transformation is reflective of the ever-changing attitudes, expectations and aspirations of this demographic. However, it’s important to remember that these individuals aren’t the only people you’re trying to reach, with around <a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-09-08/more-mature-age-students-enrolling-at-university/10199562">40% of students</a> at university being over 25 years old.</p>
<p>In an increasingly competitive market, discovering new, exciting ways to strategically target members of your target audience is crucial. Effective <a href="/education-marketing/">education marketing</a> can help you do just that, assisting your university or college in leaving a lasting, positive impact.</p>
<h2>1. Build a Brilliant, Practical Website</h2>
<p>University websites are notoriously confusing, which is often a result of the <a href="https://www.pacific54.com/blog/10-must-haves-higher-education-marketing-strategy/">substantial amount of information</a> that needs to be made available to audiences. With an array of courses and units available, enrolment options, resources and the like, it’s no surprise that so many higher education providers struggle to create a website that’s both aesthetic and functional.</p>
<p>Building a visually appealing website that clearly reflects your establishment’s brand is, of course, crucial. However, it’s important to ensure that in doing this, you don’t compromise on the overall usability of your digital domains.</p>
<p>If potential or existing students are met with a website that is difficult to navigate, doesn’t have a responsive design, or takes an extended period of time to load, it’s likely that they’ll become overwhelmed and frustrated. If they’re yet to enrol at your university, a negative experience on your website might even deter them from submitting their application. Thus, ensuring your establishment’s digital domains make an impact and effectively encompasses your branding, all the while remaining practical, is essential.</p>
<h2>2. Leverage Social Media</h2>
<p><a href="https://sea.mashable.com/tech/3110/snaps-plan-to-fight-facebook-is-bold">90% of people</a> aged between 13 and 24 years old use Snapchat, and a large portion of your target audience make up the tail end of this age bracket. In fact, in Australia, there are approximately <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-typical-university-student-is-no-longer-18-middle-class-and-on-campus-we-need-to-change-thinking-on-drop-outs-73509">670,000 university students</a> between the ages of 18 and 22.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://grattan.edu.au/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/907-Mapping-Australian-higher-education-2018.pdf"><em>41 per cent of Australian 19-year-olds</em></a><em> are enrolled in higher education institutions.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>So, what does this mean for your establishment?</p>
<p>By leveraging social media platforms, such as Snapchat, your university can reach a diverse range of individuals in a personal, thoughtful way. Advertising can be seamlessly integrated into a user’s usual online activity, so you can directly target members of your audience without being overly disruptive and sparking annoyance.</p>
<p>In addition to this, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">social media marketing</a> gives you the means to form personal connections with students or those considering their enrolment options. You can interact with individuals, address any queries they raise, share updates and, in the process of doing this, build your brand personality and a positive reputation.</p>
<p>To achieve the best results, your establishment needs to ensure that all of your <a href="/education-marketing/">education marketing</a> messages are perceived as authentic and transparent. By sharing purposeful, relevant content, you can create an online student hub that’s both informative and engaging.</p>
<h2>3. Share Testimonials<strong> </strong></h2>
<p>There are numerous doubts that potential students are likely juggling when weighing up their university options</p>
<p>Which establishment will do the best job of setting them up for a prosperous future? Is the course they’re interested in going to lead them towards their desired career path? What other opportunities, such as career guidance or extra-curricular activities, do you offer? By sharing real-life encounters that existing students and graduates have had at your university, you can help individuals overcome their doubts, all the while building a greater level of trust and authenticity.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Statistics have confirmed that customer testimonials are the most effective form of content, coming in at an </em><a href="https://www.spectoos.com/5-incredible-facts-customer-testimonials/"><em>89% effectiveness rating</em></a><em>.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Testimonials can be shared on your establishment’s website and social media, as well as being incorporated in your advertising efforts. They’re a genuine source of social proof and might just provide prospects with the assurance they need to take the next step towards becoming a student at your university.</p>
<h2>4. Create Personalised Experiences</h2>
<p>Personalisation is becoming an increasingly important component of marketing in the education sector, with individuals often being far more receptive when they’re exposed to highly relevant, targeted messages.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/blog/email-marketing/2019/07/15-email-personalization-stats-might-surprise-you/"><em>74% of marketers</em></a><em> say targeted personalisation increases customer engagement.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>With personalised content, you can cater to each unique group of individuals that will likely be interested in your establishment. This gives you the opportunity to facilitate meaningful, memorable interactions between potential students and your university.</p>
<p>Whether you’re incorporating personalised videos, emails, communication or the like, it’s definitely worth exploring the benefits this incredibly powerful marketing tool could generate for your establishment.</p>
<h2>Get Expert Guidance &amp; Advice Today</h2>
<p>The Lead Agency specialises in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> for establishments operating in the education sector. If you’re interested in boosting your audience’s engagement, <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">building a strong brand</a>, attracting more individuals to your university and retaining existing students, get in touch with one of our experienced <a href="/education-marketing/">education marketing consultants</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/4-essential-components-of-your-higher-education-marketing-strategy/">4 Essential Components of Your Higher Education Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Actionable Tips to Boost Your Higher Education Marketing</title>
		<link>/5-actionable-tips-to-boost-your-higher-education-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 01:28:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Universities and other higher education providers are continuously looking for new ways to attract students. Students are a great target audience in terms of ROI as they are looking to make a significant investment in their education. In order to successfully attract them to your higher education facility over your competitors, a comprehensive education marketing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-actionable-tips-to-boost-your-higher-education-marketing/">5 Actionable Tips to Boost Your Higher Education Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Universities and other higher education providers are continuously looking for new ways to attract students. Students are a great target audience in terms of ROI as they are looking to make a significant investment in their education. In order to successfully attract them to your higher education facility over your competitors, a comprehensive <a href="/education-marketing/">education marketing</a> strategy is necessary.</p>
<p>In most cases, students will be fresh from school or in the 18-25 age bracket, which means they are digital natives who have grown up with exposure to a number of digital channels and ad formats. Targeting such a digital-savvy audience involves an innovative approach to marketing that adopts current trends and follows them as they evolve.</p>
<p>The following are some of the most effective ways to market your higher education facility.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<h4><strong>Go Mobile</strong></h4>
</li>
</ol>
<p><u>Smartphone addiction</u> is real, and it is everywhere around us. The <a href="https://techjury.net/stats-about/mobile-marketing/">average consumer spends more than 5 hours a day on their smartphone</a>, and this amount increases for younger audiences. There is now <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/241462/global-mobile-phone-website-traffic-share/">more Internet traffic coming from smartphones than from any other device</a>. This means that any digital assets your higher education institution has and any campaigns that it runs should be optimised for mobile.</p>
<p>The higher education market typically targets high school and university transfer students, so your campaign should be created around where they are spending their time on mobile. For example, social media is likely to be an important channel for this demographic. It’s also important to ensure your website is mobile-friendly so that if the audience does click on an ad on their mobile, they are taken to a page designed for mobile user experience.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<h4><strong>Focus on SEO</strong></h4>
</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://b2bdigitalmarketers.com/blog/b2b-seo-statistics/">On average 68.3% of all traffic comes from search engines</a>. When it comes to large purchases, like education, <a href="http://blog.breezyhillmarketing.com/10-helpful-seo-stats-for-2017-planning">81% of people will perform some type of online research before making a purchase</a>. It’s important to be there when the prospect starts looking around for higher education options. The best way to do this is with an SEO strategy. SEO is the process of optimising your education website so that it ranks on search engine results pages. It involves using certain keywords and phrases on the website that students will use while they are searching for higher education.</p>
<p>Remember when optimising your website that while your higher education institution may have a unique name, students who are first researching where to study won’t be searching based on the name. They will be typing in the subjects that they want to specialise in and the courses that they are interested in. You should try to optimise your website accordingly. For example, target terms like ‘Bachelor of Business’ and even longer tail keyword terms that stem from this such as ‘Bachelor of Business in Melbourne,’ rather than simply using the name of your institution.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>
<h4><strong>Offer 360° Online Tours<br />
</strong></h4>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Not many universities have fully committed to this strategy as of yet, so those that are fast-moving may gain a competitive edge. For many students, it can be difficult to take time out of their work or current studies to travel to a potential higher education provider, particularly if it is far from their home. By creating a 360° online tour, you can give them a feel for what the campus is like, without them having to travel to it. This saves the student a lot of time and effort while still giving them the opportunity to look around and keep your establishment on their list as one of their options. It is expected that more universities and colleges will start to adopt this tactic to attract more potential students. Some may even use this kind of technology to map out their entire campus.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7534" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Use-Video-Ads.png" alt="" width="850" height="288" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Use-Video-Ads.png 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Use-Video-Ads-450x152.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Use-Video-Ads-768x260.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>
<h4><strong>U</strong><strong>se Video Ads </strong></h4>
</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://blog.bufferapp.com/social-media-video-marketing-statistics">More than 500 million hours of videos</a><a href="https://blog.bufferapp.com/social-media-video-marketing-statistics"><strong> </strong></a>are watched on YouTube each day, with the millennial age group watching the most online videos. As people lead busier lives than ever before, they are spending less time reading content and more time watching videos.</p>
<p>Universities and other higher education facilities are starting to take note of this and are beginning to use video to get their message to their audience. Short video ads give prospective students a quick snapshot of the university without having to sort through loads of information online. After seeing an engaging and convincing video ad, they are more likely to look deeper into your content to find out more about your facility when they have more time to do so.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<h4><strong>Promote Online Learning</strong></h4>
</li>
</ol>
<p>As students’ lives fill up with part-time jobs and other commitments that make it infeasible for them to get to campus, they are using online classes to facilitate their education. As such, more universities and other higher education providers are creating online learning courses. These online courses can be part of a higher education facility’s value proposition to help them attract new students.</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/education-marketing/">education marketing</a> for your facility, get in touch with the team at The Lead Agency today. We’ve worked with a number of higher education institutions and can apply our knowledge of the industry to attract students to your university or college.</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B Digital Marketing</a>, get in contact with the expert <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> at the Lead Agency today!</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget to check out the other industries that we operate in; <a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-actionable-tips-to-boost-your-higher-education-marketing/">5 Actionable Tips to Boost Your Higher Education Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want to Market to The Education Sector? Here’s How.</title>
		<link>/want-to-market-to-the-education-sector-heres-how/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 05:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“Young people are now paying more than double the cost for higher education than the generation before – and much more than the free education obtained by their parents’ generation” The past five years have seen a notable shift in the education industry, with establishments expected to adjust operations accordingly to meet demand-driven funding models. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/want-to-market-to-the-education-sector-heres-how/">Want to Market to The Education Sector? Here’s How.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>“Young people are now paying </em><a href="https://mumbrella.com.au/your-future-starts-meh-education-marketing-is-failing-to-keep-up-with-the-times-511735"><strong><em>more than double</em></strong></a><em> the cost for higher education than the generation before – and much more than the free education obtained by their parents’ generation”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>The past five years have seen a notable shift in the education industry, with establishments expected to adjust operations accordingly to meet demand-driven funding models. Whether providing higher education, coaching, or upper education it is now crucial that organisations maximise their marketing efforts to build a strong favourable reputation.</p>
<p>In today’s highly competitive market, attracting students to your institution is particularly reliant on whether your offering will outweigh the overbearing pressures involved in enrolment. Your marketing efforts need to reassure students and, in some instances, parents that as an education provider you will provide access to exemplary knowledge and training that will set them or their child up for a prosperous future.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Challenges of Education Marketing</strong></h2>
<p>Financial pressures are becoming a growing concern for many individuals, especially when considering pursuing a higher education. With the looming threat of <a href="https://mumbrella.com.au/your-future-starts-meh-education-marketing-is-failing-to-keep-up-with-the-times-511735">student debt</a> and fear that years of study will lead nowhere, it’s essential that you’re able to effectively and clearly communicate the value of your offering.</p>
<p>These concerns need to be offset by the perspective benefits, convincing potential students not only of the importance of gaining higher education, but that your institution would be the perfect fit for them. This is also crucial in overcoming the decreasing belief in the importance of attending university. With an abundance of alternative options readily available, what will make your proposition stand out?</p>
<p>When marketing for the education sector, it’s essential that your efforts establish your establishments’ reputation as a credible, authentic and reliable provider. In many cases, it also needs to be taken into consideration that your marketing will need to convince both parents and potential students that you’re the education provider for them or their child.</p>
<p>Typically, a large proportion of the education sector’s target market are members of a digitally orientated demographic. Therefore, it is fundamental that your business develops a strong digital marketing strategy. As frequent users of electronic devices, your organisation now has more opportunities than ever before to reach your target market in a direct and meaningful way.</p>
<p><em>What are you currently doing to make the most of this?</em></p>
<p>Essentially, it all comes down to showing individuals that the education you’re providing will help them achieve their dreams.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Update Your Website</strong></h2>
<p>A comprehensive website is vital in establishing a strong marketing strategy. Why? It’s essentially the hub of your business.</p>
<p>If individuals want to find out more about what you’ve got to offer, it’s highly likely that they’ll seek out your website online. Because of this it is, of course, essential that when operating in the education sector you build a practical online domain that is aligned with and accurately reflects your organisations’ image.</p>
<p>Your establishment could develop an impressive promotional campaign but if parents or students are led to a site they cannot make sense of, this simply adds an unnecessary hurdle in their consumer journey. Content that is confusing, difficult to navigate and misleading could all too quickly contribute to guardians or potential students being deterred from following through with submitting applications to your institution.</p>
<p>It’s also paramount to ensure that your website is easily accessible, maximising your online visibility through the effective integration of Search Engine Optimisation techniques into your marketing strategy. Creating relevant, frequently updated content is a great starting point and, in staying up-to-date with the intricacies, our expert team at the Lead Agency can assist your business in implementing tactics to boost your visibility.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Leverage User Generated Content</strong></h2>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://www.tintup.com/blog/10-higher-education-marketing-trends-2018/"><em>70% of people</em></a><em> trust online peer reviews and recommendations more than professional content”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>In the education industry, leveraging user generation content can provide your current or potential students with reassurance that your establishment is authentic and trusted by others.</p>
<p>User generated content acts as a form of social proof, showing your target market first-hand insights into what your institution is really like. If integrated into your marketing strategy effectively, the use of such content can be a great way to build a favourable brand image and boost your overall attractiveness as an education provider.</p>
<p>Interested in incorporating user generated content into your marketing strategy, but not sure where to start?</p>
<p>It could be as simple compiling positive quotes from current or previous students regarding their personal experience at your establishment which can then be shared on your website. It’s all about giving your target market an inside look into your business, and providing them with social proof that you really are as great as you say you are.</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Integrate Augmented Reality </strong></h2>
<p>Experiences are truly valued by consumers. In the education industry augmented reality can assist in creating an interactive, unique and personalised experience for your target market.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Almost </em><a href="https://www.lucidpress.com/blog/higher-education-marketing-crucial-strategies-trends"><em>90% of Snapchat users</em></a><em> say they enjoy GeoFilters”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>With an audience who are generally frequent users of digital platforms and social media, through the use of augmented reality those in the education industry have the opportunity to reach their market directly and in a relevant, exciting way.</p>
<p>In creating an interactive experience, augmented reality can work to boost engagement and establish a sense of community at your establishment. In particular, Snapchat GeoFilters are a cost-effective way of getting your students involved. They encourage individuals to share content related to your establishment and, essentially, generate word-of-mouth.</p>
<p>Although this approach is generally more student focused, it can still assist in creating a great experience that children will then want to share with their guardians. In doing this, reaching each distinct target group in a positive way.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, our experienced team can assist your establishment in <a href="/education-marketing/">marketing to the education sector</a>. To find out more, please do not hesitate to get in contact with us.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/want-to-market-to-the-education-sector-heres-how/">Want to Market to The Education Sector? Here’s How.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
