<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Email Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/b2b-email-marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:08:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Email Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>3 types of B2B email marketing campaigns and when to use them</title>
		<link>/3-types-of-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns-and-when-to-use-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 05:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s a reason why approximately 85% of B2B marketers have integrated email marketing into their campaigns – because it works. In fact, 45% of B2B marketers say email is the most effective digital marketing channel. Email is a practical and feasible option for many B2B businesses looking to reach out to new leads, nurture existing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-types-of-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns-and-when-to-use-them/">3 types of B2B email marketing campaigns and when to use them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s a reason why approximately <a href="mailto:https://backlinko.com/email-marketing-stats">85% of B2B marketers have integrated email marketing into their campaigns</a> – because it works. In fact, <a href="mailto:https://www.superoffice.com/blog/b2b-email-marketing-report/">45% of B2B marketers say email is the most effective digital marketing channel</a>.</p>
<p>Email is a practical and feasible option for many B2B businesses looking to reach out to new leads, <a href="/how-to-nurture-leads-with-b2b-marketing-automation/">nurture existing prospects</a> and drive conversions.</p>
<p>There’s now a myriad of email software available and numerous ways to go about getting your message out to prospects.</p>
<p>So, which option is best? The answer isn’t as simple as you may think. When it comes down to it, the most effective <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> strategy for your business will depend largely on your distinct objectives.</p>
<p>In the following article, we’ll be exploring some of the key types of approaches to B2B email marketing we use here at the Lead Agency, while also running you through when their use will be most effective and impactful.</p>
<h2>Why B2B email marketing?</h2>
<p>There are plenty of reasons B2B email marketing should be on your business’ radar. It can not only help you get a leg up on your competition, but also drive real, measurable returns for your business.</p>
<p>When executed well, <a href="mailto:https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/knowledge-base/how-do-you-calculate-email-marketing-roi/">the return-on-investment from email marketing can be as high as 4400%</a>. This means that, for every dollar spent on email campaigns, companies would be making $44.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="mailto:https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">59% of survey respondents said that marketing emails influence their purchase decisions</a> &#8211; HubSpot</p></blockquote>
<p>But, what is at about email that makes this achievable?</p>
<p>With segmented audiences and value-driven content, companies can directly target individuals with information and resources they will actually be interested in – sent right to their inbox.</p>
<p>B2B emails are also a great way to keep leads in the <a href="mailto:/how-do-b2b-and-b2c-marketing-funnels-differ/">marketing funnel</a> so, when they are eventually ready to purchase a product or service like yours, they know where to go. On average, <a href="mailto:https://blog.hellostepchange.com/blog/the-industry-average-b2b-sales-cycle-length">B2B leads take 84 days to convert</a>, so managing this ongoing relationship and fostering meaningful interactions is crucial.</p>
<h2>Types of B2B email marketing</h2>
<p>If you’re ready to get started with <a href="mailto:/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a>, you first need to determine which option/s are for you. Here are three approaches commonly used by our team and when to use them.</p>
<h3>1. B2B newsletters</h3>
<p>By periodically sending <a href="mailto:/crafting-b2b-newsletters-that-drive-engagement/">B2B newsletters</a> to your contacts, you can highlight certain products or offerings, provide your audience with useful information, share exciting updates and more.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="mailto:https://sleeknote.com/blog/b2b-newsletter-ideas">During 2020, 81% of B2B brands were sending out newsletters</a> &#8211; Sleeknote</p></blockquote>
<p>When done right, there’s no denying that B2B newsletters can be a powerful strategy that drives real results for businesses. But, what does ‘done right’ mean in this case?</p>
<p>Here are some newsletter best practices and tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make sure you’re using a high-quality, up-to-date list;</li>
<li>Get your sending frequency right, which means getting an email out <a href="mailto:https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/knowledge-base/how-often-should-you-send-out-a-newsletter/">at least once a month, but no more than twice a week</a>;</li>
<li>Be direct and to-the-point;</li>
<li>Use subject lines that spark interest but won’t be mistaken for spam;</li>
<li>Focus on educating and informing, not selling;</li>
<li>Target the individual with personal, engaging storytelling;</li>
<li>Direct readers to a helpful and relevant resource of yours, such as a blog or whitepaper;</li>
<li>Monitor the ongoing performance of emails and make any necessary adjustments.</li>
</ul>
<h3>2. B2B marketing automation</h3>
<p><a href="/what-is-email-automation-and-why-should-you-use-it/">B2B marketing automation</a> is typically used to capture and nurture leads. For instance, if a prospect downloads a resource on your website like an eBook or whitepaper, and you get their email in the process, you can continue to reach out to them over time.</p>
<p>These emails are a bit different to newsletters, in that there’s usually an aspect of continuity and flow that needs to come into play. In the case of an eBook download, you could highlight a chapter a week and conclude with an exclusive offer at the end of your automation to encourage conversions. This keeps the content relevant to users, while also ensuring the automation’s messaging is consistent and driven by purpose.</p>
<p>When implementing email automation as a strategy for your business, make sure to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Map and plan your automation, rather than jumping in head first;</li>
<li>Find and get familiar with marketing automation software, such as that provided by Active Campaign;</li>
<li>Deliver content that’s targeted and relevant to your audience;</li>
<li>Understand your audience’s buying cycle and use this information to determine how often to email prospects;</li>
<li>Keep your content direct and to-the-point;</li>
<li>Use lead scoring to measure levels of engagement;</li>
<li>Include a call-to-action.</li>
</ul>
<h3>3. B2B email outreach</h3>
<p>Email outreach is a form of <a href="mailto:/auto-draft-2/">outbound marketing</a>, which is when you directly reach out to new customers to see if they’re interested in your product or service. A really important aspect of this is where you source your sending list from, as you want to make sure it’s up-to-date and that the potential leads you’re contacting are likely to have a real interest in your offering.</p>
<p>While marketing automation emails and newsletters are usually designed in a way that leverages graphics, such as through the use of a header image and brand-specific format, outreach emails are often made to look like they’re coming directly from a member of your company.</p>
<p>The email copy is short and direct, but in a different way to the other email options mentioned. An effective way to approach this is starting out by saying who you are and what you’re selling, why you’re contacting them and then asking to arrange a chat if they’d like more information. Personalisation is also key, and when possible (and the details you have allow for this), it’s a great idea to open the email by saying ‘hi’ to the recipient by name.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in building a strong <a href="mailto:/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> strategy or this article has brought up any questions, get in touch with the Lead Agency. We’re experts in B2B marketing, offering a range of services including <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">lead generation</a>, and <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-types-of-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns-and-when-to-use-them/">3 types of B2B email marketing campaigns and when to use them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Create Impactful B2B Email Marketing Campaigns</title>
		<link>/how-to-create-impactful-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 03:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=45259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When email marketing has the potential to generate an astounding 3,800% return-on-investment, it would be easy to assume that this is a strategy B2B companies prioritise. However, while 45% of B2B marketers say email as the most effective digital marketing channel, 59% of B2B organisations are yet to adopt this tactic. B2B email marketing can [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-create-impactful-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns/">How to Create Impactful B2B Email Marketing Campaigns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When email marketing has the potential to generate an <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">astounding 3,800% return-on-investment</a>, it would be easy to assume that this is a strategy B2B companies prioritise. However, while <a href="https://www.superoffice.com/blog/b2b-email-marketing-report/">45% of B2B marketers</a> say email as the most effective digital marketing channel, 59% of B2B organisations are yet to adopt this tactic.</p>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> can be an incredibly powerful tool for nurturing leads and, if you’re overlooking this strategy, it might be time to consider how it could benefit your business.</p>
<h2>The importance of creating effective B2B email campaigns</h2>
<p>B2B email marketing is far more strategic than simply throwing together an email every so often and sending it out to your contacts. Taking a disjointed approach to B2B email marketing can drastically hinder the effectiveness of your campaigns.</p>
<p>A cohesive and effective approach to <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> combines segmentation, content and design to reach prospects in meaningful, impactful ways. Through this, you can build strong, ongoing relationships with leads, keeping them in the marketing funnel and, ideally, driving conversions over time.</p>
<p>This stage of nurturing leads becomes all the more important in the B2B sphere, where the buyer journey is notoriously long and complex. The purchases of B2B buyers often hold far more weight than those consumers make in their day-to-day life. Their buying decisions can be significant and, if they get it wrong, they could seriously impact their business’ profitability and ongoing success.</p>
<p>With this in mind, B2B email marketing is a great way to stay in touch with your business’ different groups of prospects or customers. By regularly providing leads with value-driven information and updates that are relevant to their interests, needs and preferences, you can convey your expertise and remove an element of uncertainty. Recipients become increasingly familiar with you and your brand and, as they continue to move through the B2B buyer funnel, will likely become far more open to enquiring about or purchasing your product or service.</p>
<h2>How can you build a brilliant B2B email marketing campaign?</h2>
<p>Whether you’re starting fresh or looking to improve your existing B2B email marketing campaigns, there are numerous steps you can take to make a real impact.</p>
<h4>1. Review your email list</h4>
<p>First and foremost, it’s important to make sure your email list data is up-to-date and ‘clean’. If your list is largely comprised of unwanted or invalid contacts, you run the risk of increasing your email bounce rate and decreasing deliverability. This can impact your reputation with Internet service providers (ISPs), which may result in less and less of your emails being received by contacts.</p>
<p><a href="https://verifalia.com/blog/email-list-cleaning-7-reasons-why">Email data degrades at an estimated rate of around 22% per year</a> so, if you’re not keeping your lists updated, you may find yourself paying to send emails to inactive accounts. By reviewing your contacts periodically and removing or updating details, you can avoid unnecessarily incurring these costs.</p>
<h4>2. Segment your audience</h4>
<p>While sending out a generic email to all of your contacts can take less time, this isn’t always the most effective approach to take. With consumers increasingly favouring personalised content in recent years, segmenting your audience can be a great way to deliver more targeted marketing messages that tap into the recipient’s specific interests and preferences.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/guides/personalized-email/">74% of marketers say that targeted personalisation increases customer engagement</a> and, in B2B email marketing; engagement is crucial. It helps you drive more traffic to your website, reaffirm that recipients are interested in the content you’re sharing and maximise your return on investment.</p>
<p>By segmenting audiences and creating personalised experiences, organisations can <a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/guides/personalized-email/">increase their sales by 20%</a>, which generally makes this investment well worth their time.</p>
<h4>3. Send value-driven content</h4>
<p>If you’re purely sending emails to stay in touch with leads, rather than focusing on providing them with purposeful and value-driven information, this will likely hinder the overall effectiveness of your campaigns.</p>
<p>Sending <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> campaigns to contacts doesn’t necessarily mean they’ll open or engage with them and, if your content consistently disappoints, recipients may disengage or unsubscribe from your emails altogether.</p>
<p>When crafting your B2B emails, while it’s important to include a call to action, avoid treating the content as another opportunity to push for sales. Rather, <a href="https://www.b2bmarketing.net/en-gb/resources/blog/how-add-value-your-email-marketing-campaigns">you want to add immediate, real points of value and connect with your reader</a>, providing them with helpful resources, information, relevant updates, special offers or the like. In doing this, you can create impactful, effective email campaigns, boost engagement and foster meaningful relationships with more contacts (driving conversions).</p>
<p>For more information or to get started on your B2B business’ next email marketing campaign, please don’t hesitate to <a href="/contact-us/">contact our team</a>.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency also offers a range of other services, including <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B lead generation</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">B2B social media marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B search engine optimisation</a>. <a href="/contact-us/">Get in touch with our team</a> to find out more about what we can do for your B2B business.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-create-impactful-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns/">How to Create Impactful B2B Email Marketing Campaigns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crafting B2B Newsletters that Drive Engagement</title>
		<link>/crafting-b2b-newsletters-that-drive-engagement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 07:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>59% of B2B marketers believe email is their most effective channel for generating revenue, so it comes as no surprise that many are now making regular newsletters a priority. We’re living in increasingly digitalised times and, if you’re yet to create a B2B newsletter of your own, this is a marketing tactic worth looking into. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crafting-b2b-newsletters-that-drive-engagement/">Crafting B2B Newsletters that Drive Engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2017/06/29/email-marketing-statistics">59% of B2B marketers</a> believe <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">email</a> is their most effective channel for generating revenue, so it comes as no surprise that many are now making regular newsletters a priority.</p>
<p>We’re living in increasingly digitalised times and, if you’re yet to create a B2B newsletter of your own, this is a marketing tactic worth looking into.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“83 per cent of B2B companies use e-newsletters as part of their content marketing program.” &#8211; </em><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats"><em>HubSpot</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>Not only is it a great way to stay in touch with those who’ve previously shown interest in your brand, but it’s also a brilliant avenue for your B2B company to further demonstrate your expertise. This can, in turn, help you build ongoing, meaningful relationships with customers, which is vital in what’s undeniably an incredibly competitive market.</p>
<p>Beyond this, you can, of course, share valuable information and relevant updates with existing and/or potential customers. This can come in various forms, for instance, your newsletter may be used to highlight certain blog posts, share helpful resources, make announcements, promote events or discounts and the like.</p>
<h2>The Importance of Building Brilliant B2B Newsletters</h2>
<p>If you’re interested in creating a newsletter or improving the effectiveness of your existing approach, you’ve likely recognised the plethora of benefits this marketing tactic has to offer.</p>
<p>However, e-newsletters aren’t guaranteed to perform exceptionally. In other words, sending out a newsletter to your subscribers doesn’t mean that they’ll open or interact with it, let alone convert into a <a href="/lead-generation/">new lead</a>.</p>
<p>Not to mention, when it comes to <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a>, <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/email-marketing-stats">40% of all B2B marketers</a> say that e-newsletters are <em>most</em> critical to their success. What does this mean for your B2B business? You’re competing for the attention of recipients, who are likely receiving an array of e-newsletters from numerous other companies, all of which are looking to achieve success in this pursuit.</p>
<p>Thus, if you’ve invested in a digital newsletter, there’s no point hastily throwing one together and hoping for the best. Instead, to get the most out of your e-newsletter, you want to make sure that it’s both optimised and impactful, offering real value to users and helping your B2B business stand out from your competitors.</p>
<p>There are numerous steps you can take to do just that, which, when implemented accordingly, can assist you in maximising engagement and driving excellent results.</p>
<h4>1. Get Your Frequency Right</h4>
<p>It can be difficult to pinpoint the frequency at which you should be sending newsletters to your list, but defining a timeframe that works for your B2B company is crucial.</p>
<p>When subscribers receive an influx of e-newsletters from your business, they may become overwhelmed and, consequently, you risk users disengaging and losing interest in your content.</p>
<p>Alternatively, if you’re only reaching out every few months, maybe even once or twice a year, you’ll have jeopardised your relationship with subscribers. In some cases, they may have already chosen a competitor’s product or service over your own and, because of this, feel as though your newsletter isn’t relevant to them anymore. It’s also possible that, after a prolonged period of time without contact from your B2B business, they’ve forgotten subscribing in the first place, which again challenges relevance.</p>
<p><em>So, how often should you be sending e-newsletters to your subscribers?</em><em> </em></p>
<p>Unfortunately, this isn’t always a straightforward answer. For many, the exact timeframe that’s followed will be determined by their organisational goals, context and the like. Because of this, you may benefit from trialling different frequencies and comparing their effectiveness, such as once a month versus once every two weeks.</p>
<h4>2. Segment Your Audiences</h4>
<p>If you’re offering various services and/or products, it’s likely that your subscribers could be classified into categories depending on their specific needs.</p>
<p>While sending out a general e-newsletter may be the preferred approach when you’re starting out, once your list of subscribers begins to grow, this may no longer be a feasible option. This is because, in many instances, information that’s incredibly relevant to one customer group may be completely redundant when shared with another.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Marketers have noted a 760% increase in revenue from segmented campaigns. – </em><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/guides/email-marketing-new-rules/"><em>Campaign Monitor</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>With segmented e-newsletters, your B2B business has the opportunity to create and share highly targeted content that different recipients will resonate with. If users are receiving content they’re actually interested in; they’re far more likely to not only stay subscribed but also engage with your newsletters.</p>
<p>However, with this in mind, don’t fall into the trap of overcomplicating things. If you end up going overboard, regular content may not be maintainable and, beyond this, it could make your newsletters unnecessarily confusing to manage. So, before jumping in headfirst and creating twenty segments, start off with a smaller number, such as three, and see how you go.</p>
<h4>3. Keep it Short &amp; Sweet</h4>
<p>The average person has an <a href="https://www.cision.com/us/2018/01/declining-attention-killing-content-marketing-strategy/">attention span of just eight seconds</a> – so, if you’re not making a fast impact, you’ll likely lose your chance to make an impact at all.</p>
<p><em>What does this mean for your B2B business’ e-newsletter?</em></p>
<p>For starters, you’ll need to include a title that not only encompasses what the email is about but also sparks interest in what’s to come.</p>
<p>In the body text that follows, avoid rambling or going into too much detail and, instead, get straight to the point. Keeping your content relatively short and, of course, only sharing what’s relevant, can assist you in getting your message across clearly and concisely, which often helps to boost engagement.</p>
<p>With this in mind, you can always offer the option for users to ‘find out more’ if that’s something that they’re interested in. For instance, you may provide them with the link to a more detailed resource, such as a blog post, or even your contact details if they’d like to discuss the topic further with a member of your team.</p>
<h2>Ready to Boost Your Newsletter’s Engagement?</h2>
<p>If you’re interested in improving the effectiveness of your existing e-newsletter or looking to start an entirely new one, our team can help. With extensive experience in crafting and managing client newsletters, we can assist you in creating value-driven content, nurturing your network and driving engagement.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve worked on numerous B2B digital marketing campaigns for companies operating across a diverse range of industries. This includes <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">B2B social media marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/marketing-automation/">B2B marketing automation</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B search engine optimisation</a> and more.</p>
<p>For more information, please don’t hesitate to get in touch with us.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/crafting-b2b-newsletters-that-drive-engagement/">Crafting B2B Newsletters that Drive Engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Improve the Deliverability of Your B2B Email Marketing Campaigns</title>
		<link>/how-to-improve-the-deliverability-of-your-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You’ve invested time, money and resources into developing an incredible B2B email marketing campaign. With this in mind, you want to get the most out of your efforts. However, when 20% of all commercial emails end up in the spam folder, it can be incredibly difficult to do so. In addition to this, the click-through-rate [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-improve-the-deliverability-of-your-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns/">How to Improve the Deliverability of Your B2B Email Marketing Campaigns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’ve invested time, money and resources into developing an incredible <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> campaign.</p>
<p>With this in mind, you want to get the most out of your efforts. However, when <a href="https://sleeknote.com/blog/why-emails-go-to-spam">20% of all commercial emails</a> end up in the spam folder, it can be incredibly difficult to do so.</p>
<p>In addition to this, the click-through-rate for emails is only 32% on average and, in certain industries; this figure can drop even lower. This is concerning as even if your emails <em>are</em> received by subscribers, this doesn’t guarantee that they’ll be seen by the majority of people. By keeping your emails out of spam folders, you can reach more subscribers and, ultimately, give more individuals the opportunity to engage with your content.</p>
<p>When was the last time you checked your spam folder?</p>
<p>If you’ve panned through your spam folder recently, you’re likely in the minority. As it stands, the average office worker receives <a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/blog/email-marketing/2019/05/shocking-truth-about-how-many-emails-sent/">121 emails each day</a>. Individuals are already drowning in content and, for many; spending additional time sifting through their spam emails simply isn’t a priority.</p>
<p>This means that even if you’re creating brilliant, value-driven emails, if they aren’t landing in recipient’s inboxes, it’s highly unlikely that you’ll get the results you’re after.</p>
<p>Thus, when developing your mailing list and prior to sending any <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> campaigns out, it’s important to take reasonable precautions. By doing this, you can reduce the likelihood of your emails being marked as spam and, consequently, make sure they reach subscribers (at the very least).</p>
<h2><strong>How Do Emails End up in a Spam Folder?</strong></h2>
<p>Generally speaking, your emails will be classified as spam for one of two reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>They were flagged by a spam filter</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Email providers use spam filters, which are designed to identify any emails that appear particularly ‘spammy’ and remove them from the recipient’s inbox. This is an automated response to help subscribers steer clear of harmful spam emails.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The recipient marked them as spam</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>If subscribers decide they no longer want to receive your emails, they may decide to mark them as spam. Typically, this only happens if individuals are particularly fed up with the content you’re sharing (or how frequently you’re sharing it).</p>
<p>If a large number of recipients do this, email providers will likely mark some or all of the emails sent from your address as spam.</p>
<h2><strong>Keeping Your Emails out of Spam Folders</strong></h2>
<h4>Build Your Email List From Scratch</h4>
<p>While it may be tempting to take shortcuts, if you’re looking for long-term results, building your email list organically is crucial.</p>
<p>There are, of course, easier and faster options out there, but it’s unlikely that they’ll deliver sustainable outcomes. Beyond this, if your list is built from the ground up, the quality and relevance of recipients will likely be far better than if you cut corners. This translates into greater engagement and, ultimately, more successful <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> campaigns.</p>
<p>So, what should you stay away from?</p>
<ul>
<li>Renting or purchasing subscribers from a third party;</li>
<li>Creating shared lists with partners;</li>
<li>Using automated technology to collect email addresses online (this is also known as ‘scraping’ or ‘email harvesting’.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important that, even after adding subscribers, you continue to manage the quality of your list accordingly. Certain recipients may lose interest over time and, consequently, become inactive subscribers. This isn’t uncommon; in fact, it’s estimated that <a href="https://fulcrumtech.net/resources/7-tips-keep-your-email-campaigns-out-of-spam-folder/">25% of subscribers become inactive each year</a>. If your list is predominately made up of inactive, disengaged subscribers, this may negatively impact the deliverability of your emails.</p>
<h4>Get Your Image to Text Ratio Right</h4>
<p>When images are used excessively in B2B email campaigns, this is usually seen as a dead giveaway that the content is spammy.</p>
<p>This is because spam emails are notoriously image-heavy. Thus, if you don’t include enough text, you’ll likely get the attention of spam filters.</p>
<p>So, what’s the best way to overcome this?</p>
<p>When it comes to email best practices, it’s generally accepted that <a href="https://www.emailonacid.com/blog/article/email-marketing/should-i-be-concerned-with-text-and-image-ratio-in-email/">content should be at least 60% text and, at the very most, 40% images</a>.</p>
<p>Striking a balance between images and text is relatively straightforward, but by taking the time to do so; you can drastically improve your campaign’s reach and effectiveness. It all comes back to the concept that, if your emails aren’t reaching subscribers, they’re not even going to have the chance to engage with them.</p>
<h2>Interested in Launching a B2B Emailing Marketing Campaign?</h2>
<p>For more information or if you have any questions, get in touch with our team of experienced B2B marketing consultants at <a href="/">the Lead Agency</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-improve-the-deliverability-of-your-b2b-email-marketing-campaigns/">How to Improve the Deliverability of Your B2B Email Marketing Campaigns</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What To Do When Your B2B Email Marketing Campaign Isn’t Working</title>
		<link>/what-to-do-when-your-b2b-email-marketing-campaign-isnt-working/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 06:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are your B2B email marketing campaigns converting? If not, you’re likely wasting time and resources on an approach that isn’t actually delivering real value to your business. That being said, email marketing has the potential to be an incredibly powerful tool. Luckily for you, there are various practical, actionable tactics that can be integrated into [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-to-do-when-your-b2b-email-marketing-campaign-isnt-working/">What To Do When Your B2B Email Marketing Campaign Isn’t Working</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are your B2B email marketing campaigns converting? If not, you’re likely wasting time and resources on an approach that isn’t actually delivering real value to your business.</p>
<p>That being said, email marketing has the potential to be an incredibly powerful tool. Luckily for you, there are various practical, actionable tactics that can be integrated into your current strategy to get the results you’re after.</p>
<p>If you want to engage recipients and generate valuable outcomes, you’ll need to assess your current email marketing campaigns and identify where exactly they’re going wrong. Asking the following questions is a great starting point and will help you eliminate some of the common mistakes businesses make. Address such downfalls, and you’ll be well on the way to achieving email marketing success.</p>
<h2>Do You Understand Your Target Audience?</h2>
<p>Taking the time to establish a comprehensive understanding of your target audience is a crucial stage in any <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> campaign. If you don’t know the interests and expectations of the individuals you’re reaching out to, how are you going to know the types of content that will be relevant to them? To get real results, you need to deliver emails that comprise high-quality, targeted content and offer recipients unique value. Merely hoping that prospects enjoy what you’re sending them is not enough.</p>
<p>You may also benefit from segmenting your target audience into core consumer groups, sending each group different emails specific to their interests. This will, in turn, help you further personalise the content you’re sharing so that it is incredibly relevant to recipients.</p>
<p>For instance, if you sell plants, you could divide your prospects into segments based on how they use your products. Your customer groups could include those who use your plants in their home garden, construction companies who require large orders for various projects and the like. With distinct customer personas to target, you can ensure that recipients relate to the content and imagery used in your emails. This shows prospects that you recognise their unique needs and will, consequently, boost engagement.</p>
<h2>How Often Are You Sending Emails?</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7578" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/mobile-email.jpg" alt="mobile email" width="850" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/mobile-email.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/mobile-email-450x159.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/mobile-email-768x271.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p><strong> </strong>Who enjoys being constantly bombarded with emails? It comes as no surprise that, if you smother people with emails, they’ll often be inclined to unsubscribe from your list. Scaring off prospects by flooding their inbox isn’t ideal, but neither is only making an appearance every few weeks or months. Leave recipients hanging for too long, and you’ll lose relevance. By the time you finally reach out to them, they may no longer be interested in your brand or even remember who you are.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>45.8% of subscribers flag emails as spam because the sender emailed them too often – </em><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/blog/email-marketing/2019/02/the-surprising-data-about-how-often-to-send-promotional-emails/"><em>Campaign Monitor</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>So, how many emails should you be sending prospects? Determining just how frequently to send emails doesn’t have to be difficult. In fact, Campaign Monitor has done the hard work for you. Based on their collated data, they suggest sending one email to your subscriber list every two weeks. It is, however, important to note that this “sweet spot” may vary across sectors and you’ll still likely benefit from conducting your own tests.</p>
<p>Another great way to get your email frequency right is to let potential customers choose how often they would like to receive updates from your brand. By adding the option to either subscribe to your weekly or monthly newsletter (or both), prospects can have a say in what they want to receive.</p>
<h2>Do Your Emails Have Design Errors?</h2>
<p>The design of your email needs to be a key consideration because if your emails don’t display well, you will lower the overall functionality of them and recipients will be less inclined to continue reading. It is crucial that your email design is compatible with mobile devices; otherwise, you will lose the attention of a large portion of subscribers.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“90% of all emails are read on mobile devices” &#8211; <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/why-your-email-marketing-doesnt-work-and-how-to-fix_b_596d2bb7e4b05561da5a59de">HuffPost</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>If your emails still aren’t mobile-friendly, updating their design should be a priority. You will also need to ensure that the ratio of image to text in your emails is appropriate. In fact, if you include too many images in your emails they might be marked as spam. As a general rule, your emails should be roughly 80% text, with the remaining 20% being dedicated to images.</p>
<p>Want to find out more? Get in touch with our expert team of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> specialists today and find out how to take your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> campaigns to new heights.</p>
<p>Alternatively, find out more about what it takes to build an integrated, relevant strategy by checking out our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/what-to-do-when-your-b2b-email-marketing-campaign-isnt-working/">What To Do When Your B2B Email Marketing Campaign Isn’t Working</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>B2B Email Marketing Best Practices for 2019</title>
		<link>/b2b-email-marketing-best-practices-for-2019/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“For every $1 spent, $44.25 is the average return on email marketing investment.” &#8211;  Experian Over 87% of B2B marketers are using email. Why? Because it works. A 2018 Content Marketing Institute survey revealed that 79% of B2B marketers credited email as the most effective distribution channel for their demand generation efforts. For B2B companies, it is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-email-marketing-best-practices-for-2019/">B2B Email Marketing Best Practices for 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“For every $1 spent, $44.25 is the average return on email marketing investment.” &#8211;  <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/67734-three-key-charts-from-our-2016-email-marketing-census/">Experian</a></p>
<p>Over 87% of B2B marketers are using email. Why? Because it works. A 2018 Content Marketing Institute survey revealed that 79% of B2B marketers credited email as the most effective distribution channel for their demand generation efforts.</p>
<p>For B2B companies, it is extremely important to communicate regularly with current and prospective clients. <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> is a great way of doing this by sharing valuable content with your audience. No other communications channel speaks directly between a brand and a consumer like email does, so with the right B2B email marketing strategy in place, you can increase engagement, leads, conversions, and ultimately profit.</p>
<p>However, with so many B2B companies now embarking on an email marketing strategy, it’s more important than ever to stand out amongst all the other emails that are flooding into the inboxes of your prospects and clients. One of the best ways to do this is to ensure your business is adapting with your client’s changing expectations as a result of innovations in technology. Email marketing has gotten more sophisticated over the past few decades, and your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">email marketing strategy</a> should follow suit.</p>
<p>The following are some of the key things that you can do with your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> strategy to ensure your campaign succeeds in engaging your audience and moving them through the stages of the buying funnel to sale.</p>
<h2><strong>Define Appropriate Goals and Objectives</strong></h2>
<p>Before you start your B2B email marketing campaign it is important to define measurable goals and objectives, which should align with your overall company objectives. Ensure that these objectives are specific and measurable. For example, don&#8217;t define your email marketing goal as ‘generating sales’. This is too broad and will be difficult to analyse how successful the campaign has been for your company. Instead, set a goal like ‘generate 20% more leads and 30% more phone contacts within six weeks’. As this is more specific, it is more measurable and easier to compare your performance with your expected results.</p>
<p>In order to ensure that your email campaign is meeting the set goals and objectives, it is vital that you have processes in place to be able to measure them. As well as being able to monitor open rate, click through rate and unsubscribes from your email provider, it is extremely useful to ensure Google Analytics is set up with conversion goals so that you can track how your email recipients interact with your site after they’ve clicked your email. This will give your business valuable insight into whether or not your email campaign is useful for generating leads, conversions and ROI – and how it compares to other digital channels.</p>
<h2><strong>Use Email to Move Prospects Through the Funnel</strong></h2>
<p>Your B2B email marketing strategy should be considered in the same way as your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content marketing</a> strategy. When you are creating your campaigns, it’s important to remember that not everyone who subscribes to your email list is at the bottom of the sales funnel and ready to buy.</p>
<p>It’s important to create email content that speaks to the subscribers in the middle or even towards the top of the funnel with valuable information that addresses their motivations and overcomes their objections to move them through to sale. This can be done by demonstrating <a href="https://marketinginsidergroup.com/content-marketing/what-is-thought-leadership-and-when-you-should-use-it/">thought leadership</a>. By using your emails and the content within them to convince people that you’re an expert in your niche, they’re more likely to choose your business’ products or services when they decide to act.</p>
<p>Another way to build customer trust in your brand and as such, move them through the buying funnel, is to include an endorsement in your email. This is particularly useful if the endorsement is from someone who is recognised by your audience.</p>
<h2><strong>Use Email to Cross-Sell Services</strong></h2>
<p>Email marketing is a powerful tool for cross-selling your services. Online retail giant <a href="http://rejoiner.com/resources/amazon-recommendations-secret-selling-online/">Amazon uses email marketing to achieve up-selling and cross-selling conversions of more than 60%</a>. While Amazon may not be a B2B company, the stats speak for themselves and cross-selling through email is just as effective for B2B companies. The best way to start cross-selling to your lists is to segment your users into groups of people who currently use only one of your products or services. You can then create a series of emails promoting your other services that they are not using, but that compliment the ones that they are.</p>
<h2><strong>Segment Your List Based on User Engagement </strong></h2>
<p>Personalised emails deliver 6X higher transaction rates, yet 70% of brands fail to use them. Personalisation is the key to effectively segmenting your B2B email marketing campaign. If you’re not segmenting your list, you’re missing opportunities for leads and conversions.</p>
<p>An effective way to start with segmenting your list is based on how interested people are in your brand. Your lists could range from prospects, to warm leads, customers and loyal customers. The content in your email would then be targeted to each segment. For example, you could showcase your business and how it can add value to non-customers who have subscribed to your email list to lead them further down the sales funnel. Your best customers, on the other hand, could receive an email campaign running a promotion that offers them a loyalty discount or other incentive for referrals in order to turn them into brand advocates.</p>
<h2><strong>Choose the Right Time to Send</strong></h2>
<p>Without proper timing, your email campaign may miss out on valuable opportunities, and its messages will resonate less with recipients. That’s why it’s vital to find the right time to send out your email communications to your audience.</p>
<p>There’s no set rule as to what to the perfect time to send your campaign will be, as this will depend on the characteristics and behaviours of your target market. According to <a href="https://coschedule.com/blog/best-time-to-send-email/">a number of email studies</a>, open rates and click through rates are highest on a Tuesday and the best time to send emails is around 10 am or 11 am. While this is very useful information, it’s important to do your own research as your business may not fit into that pattern. <a href="https://ignitevisibility.com/sp_faq/what-is-split-testing/"> Split testing</a> can help you determine the most effective day of the week and hour of the day for your campaigns.</p>
<p>Another consideration that will affect the best time for your business to <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/email-marketing/email-communications-strategy/timing-matter-email-marketing/">send emails is the frequency in which you send them</a>. If you send a lot of emails, you’re likely to see a lower click through rate across the campaign, regardless of the time and day you send them.</p>
<h2><strong>Keep Your Content Concise</strong></h2>
<p>If you’re seeing high open rates but low click through rates in your email, it’s likely because there is too much information in them. People get hundreds of emails a day and often read them on the go. As such, it’s important to ensure your message is short and to the point.</p>
<p>In order to ensure your email is concise, ask yourself what action you want the reader to take and ensure you only include information in the email that encourages the reader to take that action.</p>
<p>Once you’ve identified exactly what you want to say, ensure your email is presented in a way that is easy for the reader to consume. If they glance at the email and see a lot of text, they are likely to delete before they even read it. As such, email content should be concise, with the most important information at the top. Text should be scannable and written in short sentences and paragraphs, making use of bullet-pointed lists where appropriate.</p>
<p>The following are the three components every email should have:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Image: </strong>Choose an image that is related to the topic of your email</li>
<li><strong>Headline: </strong>Make sure your headline grabs the reader’s attention</li>
<li><strong>CTA: </strong>Make sure your call to action is clear and stands out</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Use Your Name in the Email </strong></h2>
<p>B2B purchases are often based on the relationship that one company has with another. With any email campaign, it’s important to ensure it is personal. An email should never be sent from a generic email address like noreply@B2Bbusiness.com.au.</p>
<p>These emails are not only more likely to end up in the recipient’s spam folder but even if they make it into the inbox, they probably won’t get a high open rate. This is because the “from” address is one of the first things that someone sees when they look at their inbox so it’s important that they see a real person’s name. Even if you are in a big company, this can add a human face to the business.</p>
<h2><strong>Ensure Your Email Design is Mobile Responsive</strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.emailmonday.com/mobile-email-usage-statistics/">Emails are now opened more on mobile than desktop</a>, and if your email doesn&#8217;t display correctly on a mobile device, it <a href="https://www.adestra.com/resources/2016-consumer-adoption-usage-study/">may be deleted within three seconds</a>. This means that ensuring your newsletter displays well on mobile devices is just as important, if not more important, as ensuring it can be read in traditional email providers like Outlook and Gmail. If your email does not display well on mobile, you risk alienating the majority of your audience and as such, can expect significantly lower click through rates.</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a>, get in touch with our <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/">Melbourne Marketing Consultants</a> today. Our specialists have significant experience in running a full range of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> campaigns.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-email-marketing-best-practices-for-2019/">B2B Email Marketing Best Practices for 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 B2B Email Marketing Strategies to Boost Engagement</title>
		<link>/6-b2b-email-marketing-strategies-to-boost-engagement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 06:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4965</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Email marketing remains one of the most effective B2B marketing methods. According to WordStream, email is the ‘third most influential source of information for B2B audiences, behind only colleague recommendations and industry-specific thought leaders.’ However, there are many strategies that are often overlooked; strategies that could help to optimise your open and click-through rates. Whether [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/6-b2b-email-marketing-strategies-to-boost-engagement/">6 B2B Email Marketing Strategies to Boost Engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">Email marketing</a> remains one of the most effective B2B marketing methods. According to</span><a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2017/06/29/email-marketing-statistics"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">WordStream</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, email is the ‘third most influential source of information for B2B audiences, behind only colleague recommendations and industry-specific thought leaders.’</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, there are many strategies that are often overlooked; strategies that could help to optimise your open and click-through rates. Whether it is segmenting your audience or using A/B testing for keyword research, you will find strategies in this article to help boost engagement with your audience.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><b>Why Email Marketing?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to business, email is overwhelmingly the platform of choice. According to research at</span><a href="https://www.hubspot.com/marketing-statistics"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">HubSpot</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, ‘86% of business professionals prefer to use email when communicating for business purposes.’</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing is also one of the most cost-effective and efficient ways to deliver campaign messaging. It is estimated by</span><a href="https://vtldesign.com/digital-marketing/email-marketing/b2b-email-marketing-guide/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Experian</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that ‘for every $1 spent, $44.25 is the average return on email marketing investment.’</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><b>Which strategies can I employ to improve the quality of my email marketing?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Below we have highlighted six strategies we employ at The Lead Agency to make sure we get the most out of our email marketing campaigns. Each of these strategies can be employed as often as you need, and translate to most campaigns.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>1. Personalise your email marketing in a meaningful way.</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personalisation has a demonstrable benefit to email marketing. According to market intelligence company </span><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/blog/email-marketing/2017/08/15-email-personalization-stats-might-surprise-you/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aberdeen</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, ‘Personalized email messages improve click-through rates by an average of 14% and conversions by 10%.’</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, there is a big difference between simply slipping in a ‘Hi [INSERT NAME HERE]’ and genuine personalisation. According to a study conducted by the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Temple </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">University</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Fox School of Business</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, poor personalisation can have a detrimental effect on audience engagement. The results of the study, which drew from over 10 million marketing emails sent out to over 600,000 subscribers, showed that, ‘Customers who were unfamiliar with the firm were very likely to click off or unsubscribe from emails with personalised greetings.’</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The team discovered the four key strategies for improving email marketing effectiveness through personalisation were:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though customers agree to terms and conditions, it is better to ask them directly if you plan to use their personal information for marketing purposes;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid using personalised greetings with new customers. If greeting past purchasers, however, personalisation can be very effective;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Send frequent emails to established customers to nurture them into purchasing. However, limit emails to newer customers;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Send new customers ads for products they are predicted to like; likewise, expose existing customers to products they’ve never bought before.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In summary, when personalising, don’t pretend to be too friendly with new customers. Set up measuring tools to find out more about your customers and offer them genuine personalisation once you’ve built up a relationship with them.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>2. Segment your audiences.</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Segmentation of your audience allows you to better target your customers and provide more personalised and relevant messaging for your campaign. According to email marketing specialists </span><a href="https://www.emailmonday.com/smart-email-marketing-segmentation-the-art-of/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email Monday</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, ‘marketers have found a 760% increase in email revenue from segmented campaigns.’</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4958 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/understanding-the-power-of-segmentation-for-marketing-campaigns-2-1-1.jpg" alt="Audience Segment" width="750" height="446" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/understanding-the-power-of-segmentation-for-marketing-campaigns-2-1-1.jpg 750w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/08/understanding-the-power-of-segmentation-for-marketing-campaigns-2-1-1-450x268.jpg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The above image is a visual representation of research conducted by </span><a href="https://www.optimove.com/blog/rewire-your-email-marketing-in-8-steps"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Optimove.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> They found that by being specific and segmenting their customers, they were able to get an average return of $42, up from $28.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When beginning your campaign, consider how you can better segment your audience. The more you segment, the more relevant your messaging can be. However, avoid segmenting too much or it can make the campaign unnecessarily complex and difficult to manage. Somewhere between 6-8 segments is ideal depending on the size of your target audience and the type of campaign you are working on.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>3. Resend emails to subscribers who didn’t open their first email.</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This strategy is one of the simplest on this list, but often marketers forget to revisit their email campaigns. Although </span><a href="https://sendgrid.com/blog/resending-email-good-idea-terrible-idea/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">open rates drop by 44% and click through rates by 46%</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, resending emails to subscribers that didn’t open their first email still gets results.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is some controversy over the practice, as some marketers are worried about spamming their audience. According to an article by </span><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/nealtaparia/2014/09/04/a-simple-way-to-increase-your-email-reach-by-54-7-today/#3441e26e5759"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forbes</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> contributed by Neal Taparia, resending emails can boost email receivership by 54.7%. However, in the same article, Neal warned that drops in open rates and click rates can have long-term negative effects on deliverability; this is because ISPs punish users who continually send emails to unengaged users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In summary, the benefits do outweigh the risks when it comes to resending emails. If you are a B2B business trying to optimise your email marketing campaign, we recommend this strategy, as it is easy to employ and has a dramatic impact on engagement.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>4. A/B test your email marketing campaigns to improve them.</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketers always try to improve their campaigns over time.  To do this requires experimentation. In the world of email marketing, there is no easier way to improve your campaign results than A/B testing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A/B testing simply means sending out two similar campaigns with one key difference and measuring which campaign outperforms the other. This can be as simple as testing the subject line, or you could try sending out two completely different email templates &#8211; the choice is yours. The more you test your campaign material, the more effective your email marketing campaigns get.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The two most commonly used email marketing platforms, </span><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/blog/new-features/2009/06/ab-testing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campaign Monitor</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://mailchimp.com/features/ab-testing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MailChimp</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, both offer A/B testing tools.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>5. Use email as a tool for keyword research.</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the previous strategy suggestion we talked about A/B testing for optimising your campaigns, however, email marketing campaigns are also great opportunities for conducting keyword research on your target market.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using the same principles of A/B testing, you can test out certain keywords to see what statistically has greater impact. The results of this research can then be used to help optimise your content marketing, SEO and paid advertising.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">B2B marketers should always be using the results of campaigns to inform their upcoming strategies, A/B testing keywords is only one way of doing this. In the same way email marketing campaigns can inform your other marketing activities, you should be using the results of your other campaigns to improve your email marketing. An example of this might be using keywords that have performed well on AdWords, or choosing landing page layouts that have good click through rates for your email templates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to experimentation within B2B marketing, the opportunities are endless.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><b>6. Automate your email marketing campaigns.</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketing automation has become synonymous with email marketing, with many email marketing platforms offering automation as part of their services. According to </span><a href="https://myemma.com/email-marketing-automation/21-stats"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Epsilon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, automated emails get 119% higher click rates than broadcast emails.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketing automation is successful as it allows you to target the right people, at the right time, with the right message &#8211; it can also save you a lot of time. The process works by setting up content that is triggered when certain actions are made by users.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A simple example of this might be a welcome message whenever a new subscriber joins your mailing list. Just to demonstrate how popular automation has become, in 2008 40% of businesses sent automated welcome messages, that number doubled to 80% in 2013 according to research conducted by </span><a href="https://returnpath.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/The_Email_Subscriber_Experience_2008-2013_6.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Return Path</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Needless to say, in 2018 marketing automation has become nearly universal. Mapping out a marketing automation strategy is not too difficult, especially with the tools provided by Martech companies like </span><a href="https://au.marketo.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketo </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="https://www.hubspot.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HubSpot</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. However, most email marketing platforms, such as </span><a href="https://mailchimp.com/features/marketing-automation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MailChimp</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/features/marketing-automation/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campaign Monitor</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> both offer automation tools as well.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><b>Summary</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing remains one of the most important channels for nurturing and generating B2B leads. By employing some of these strategies in your next campaign, you can significantly optimise your <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/expertise/">B2B Digital Marketing</a> email campaign.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are looking for advice on your </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">B2B email marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> campaign, then contact the <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">Marketing Consultant</a> experts at the Lead Agency where we can help you generate more leads and better quality leads. </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Click here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to find out more about our email marketing services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you enjoyed this article, why not read our article on </span><a href="/optimising-your-b2b-email-marketing-click-through-and-open-rates/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Optimising Your B2B Email Marketing Click Through And Open Rates</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/6-b2b-email-marketing-strategies-to-boost-engagement/">6 B2B Email Marketing Strategies to Boost Engagement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</title>
		<link>/six-steps-account-based-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Services Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So, you’ve heard of Account Based Marketing and want to know what all the fuss is about? Well, you’ve come to right place. In this article, we’re going to outline what Account Based Marketing is and how you can use it in your business. Account Based Marketing was initially developed to solve the B2B problem [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/six-steps-account-based-marketing/">The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, you’ve heard of Account Based Marketing and want to know what all the fuss is about? Well, you’ve come to right place. In this article, we’re going to outline what Account Based Marketing is and how you can use it in your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing was initially developed to solve the B2B problem of multiple decision makers being involved in a purchase. Rarely is there ever just one sole decision maker in a business deciding what product to buy &#8211; there can be anywhere up to a dozen decision makers in any one account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing can offer a lot to B2B enterprises looking to improve their ROI. According to research from the</span><a href="https://au.marketo.com/account-based-marketing/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Altera Group</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, “97% [of B2B businesses] had a somewhat higher or much higher ROI than other marketing initiatives.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whereas traditional lead generation is akin to fishing with a net, ABM is the equivalent of fishing with a spear. Rather than general broadcasts, you are focused on winning over key accounts. Adjusting to the demands can be difficult at first, but ABM tends to have better results, especially for B2B marketers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, how do you know who to contact? How do you personalise interactions with each decision maker? Read on for a step-by-step method to unlocking complex B2B accounts!</span></p>
<h2><b>How Does Account Based Marketing Differ From The Traditional Sales Pipeline Approach?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing may seem a little alien to those used to employing a sales pipeline. Metrics such as the number of qualified leads, prospects and other such demarcations don’t easily fit the Account-Based Marketing model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the biggest differences is that Account Based Marketing is about creating quality relationships with a few key influencers and decision makers, as opposed to playing a numbers game hoping to attract significant numbers of qualified leads. You will also find that, given the low volume of accounts, you will not be able to use traditional funnel metrics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The longer sales cycles will impact what types of metrics you should focus on. Given your objective is to build stronger relationships over time, engagement becomes an increasingly important metric to use.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing means that sales and marketing have to work closely together to generate real results. Demonstrating value then becomes increasingly important.</span></p>
<h2><b>What Are The Benefits of Account Based Marketing?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account-Based Marketing doesn’t mean you have to start from scratch with your existing marketing. So long as your have your executive on board, have a good team of people and  are able to align your sales and marketing, you will find that this type of marketing will slot in nicely with your existing marketing strategies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Big businesses are run by individuals, if you can harness the power of scaled personalisation, you will find that you will be able to develop one-to-one communication quite easily.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the benefits of employing Account Based Marketing is a higher Return On Investment (ROI), better relationships with existing clients, and better alignment between your sales and marketing departments.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4618 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/findingyouraccount.jpg" alt="Find Your Account" width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h2><b>Step 1. Find Your Account</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Create a list of target accounts and then organise them according to a tiered structure. Once you have your list, you want establish how much of a percentage of your time you wish to dedicate to each tier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You may wish to have three tiers set up:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first tier contains those accounts that you believe are worth investing more time in researching, developing personalised touchpoint and investing in long-term. Tactics may include heavy targeting by sales and significant support. (20-50)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second tier might be accounts you see merit in, but are not willing to spend a significant amount time in pursuing. You may choose to use tactics that are less time intensive, such as direct mail and phone calls. (200-500)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The third tier will be accounts that are in your general periphery but not your focus. General marketing automation and limited personalisation would apply to this group. (2000-5000)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Establishing your list of accounts is a fine balance between art and science. Use any data you have access to to establish the viability of prospects and whom you should priortise.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 2. Map Out Who The Decision Makers Are</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you have your list of accounts it’s time to get started building some generalised personas to represent different members of the teams. Yet again, prioritise these accounts according to key stakeholders, and lower influence team members.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now comes the nitty-gritty of researching each target account and mapping out their staff individually. Attach your persona profiles to each contact and start building a comprehensive database. Tools for developing this could be LinkedIn, or even going through a data vendor.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 3. Research The Account</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now comes the time to get research done on the accounts as whole. You will need to find out the following:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who their target market is?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their mission, vision and values?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their culture and agenda?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The work dynamic within the organisation?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are there any existing connections to the account?</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This research can come from conversations, surveys, stalking their website and social media or even just general market data.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4618 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/createcontent.jpg" alt="Relevant Content " width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h2><b>Step 4. Create Relevant Content</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Creating content that is going to resonate with your different accounts is the next step. We don’t suggest you create specific content for each account but have a wide range of content that varies in its level of personalisation depending on the importance of the account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the higher end of this spectrum is content specifically for one account, at the lower end is generic broad content and in between might be content targeted towards certain industries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Changing the title, feature picture and headline may be all that is needed to personalise content. If you have the time and see value in a particular prospect, you may wish to spend time labouring over some more specific content.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 5. Decide On Your Tactics For Interaction</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where all your hard work and research can finally be put to use. Now you have your accounts, and you know who you are targeting within each account, you can begin to reach out to your prospects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing interactions are unique in that you are applying inbound two-way communication and sharing of relevant content to an outbound marketing strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some tactics you may wish to employ may include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Hosting Events </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Create, or simply host, business networking events. These events allow your sales team to get direct access to those accounts they are targeting.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Direct Mail </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; In a digital world, physical mail is more likely to cut through the clutter. Creating personalised direct mail campaigns to target priority accounts is a great way to open doors.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><b>Email Marketing </b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; You may have general eNewsletters accounts can subscribe to, however, if you want to build two-way communication, consider avoiding smart looking templates and using more text-based personal emails.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Digital Advertising </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Use retargeting, personalised search and social media paid advertising to get to your audience. LinkedIn, for example, allows you to target your posts exclusively to certain demographics.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Free Webinars </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Host relevant and interesting webinars to get the attention of account-holders. By creating personalised invitations to events you are also able to make a good impression.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Step 6. Progress Your Strategy</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now the campaign is up and running, consider what your game plan is going to be. Rather than traditional tactics of broadcasting to a wide net and hoping some stick, you need to be very specific in your planning. Have a marketing flow chart prepared with the list of the different channels and tactics you plan to employ for each account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are two things you need to consider when building your strategy. The first is how long you plan to run your campaign for and how often you plan to post. The second is creating a strategy employing a diverse range of integrated channels.</span></p>
<h2><b>Summary</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are interested in ABM marketing and looking for assistance employing it for your B2B business, please contact <a href="/">The Lead Agency</a>. Our expert <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> are generating leads and prospects for your business and building strong, resilient ties with them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more information about the impact Account Based Marketing is having on <a href="/">B2B marketing</a>, try reading this article on</span><a href="/account-based-marketing-revolutionising-b2b/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">How Account Based Marketing Is Revolutionising B2B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<noscript class="ninja-forms-noscript-message">
    Notice: JavaScript is required for this content.</noscript><style>

        /* PLUGIN WIDE STYLES */
    
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container.textarea-container .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    height:100px!important;
                    }
    </style><style>

        /* FORM STYLES */
    
        #nf-form-2_1-cont {
                                    background-color:#e74c3c;
                                            padding:10px;
                                                    box-shadow: -webkit-box-shadow: 4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);
-moz-box-shadow:    4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);
box-shadow:         4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);                    }
        #nf-form-2_1-cont .nf-form-title h3 {
                                    color:#f8c9c3;
                                            font-size:30px;
                                            margin:10px 0px;
                                                    text-align: center                    }
    </style><style>

        /* FIELDS STYLES */
    
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap {
                                    color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-10_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-10_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-6_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap {
                                    width:100%;
                                            display:block;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    width:100%;
                                            display:block;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    background-color:#31415c;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                                            width:100%;
                                            font-size:18px;
                                            padding:10px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field:hover {
                                    background-color:#162542;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                    }
    </style><div id="nf-form-2_1-cont" class="nf-form-cont" aria-live="polite" aria-labelledby="nf-form-title-2_1" aria-describedby="nf-form-errors-2_1" role="form">

    <div class="nf-loading-spinner"></div>

</div>
        <!-- TODO: Move to Template File. -->
        <script>var formDisplay=1;var nfForms=nfForms||[];var form=[];form.id='2_1';form.settings={"objectType":"Form Setting","editActive":true,"title":"Contact The Lead Agency","key":"","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","default_label_pos":"hidden","conditions":[],"show_title":1,"clear_complete":"1","hide_complete":"1","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","add_submit":"1","logged_in":"","not_logged_in_msg":"","sub_limit_number":"","sub_limit_msg":"","calculations":[],"formContentData":[{"order":1,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["name"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":2,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["contact_number_1491218320211"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":3,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["email"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":4,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["i_need_help_with_1549425070059"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":5,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["recaptcha_1602543056346"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":6,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["hidden_1571292741941"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":7,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["speak_to_a_b2b_expert_1508319997306"],"width":"100"}]}],"container_styles_background-color":"#e74c3c","container_styles_border":"","container_styles_border-style":"","container_styles_border-color":"","container_styles_color":"","container_styles_height":"","container_styles_width":"","container_styles_font-size":"","container_styles_margin":"","container_styles_padding":"10px","container_styles_display":"","container_styles_float":"","container_styles_show_advanced_css":1,"container_styles_advanced":"box-shadow: -webkit-box-shadow: 4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);\n-moz-box-shadow:    4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);\nbox-shadow:         4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);","title_styles_background-color":"","title_styles_border":"","title_styles_border-style":"","title_styles_border-color":"","title_styles_color":"#f8c9c3","title_styles_height":"","title_styles_width":"","title_styles_font-size":"30px","title_styles_margin":"10px 0px","title_styles_padding":"","title_styles_display":"","title_styles_float":"","title_styles_show_advanced_css":1,"title_styles_advanced":"text-align: center","row_styles_background-color":"","row_styles_border":"","row_styles_border-style":"","row_styles_border-color":"","row_styles_color":"","row_styles_height":"","row_styles_width":"","row_styles_font-size":"","row_styles_margin":"","row_styles_padding":"","row_styles_display":"","row_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","row_styles_advanced":"","row-odd_styles_background-color":"","row-odd_styles_border":"","row-odd_styles_border-style":"","row-odd_styles_border-color":"","row-odd_styles_color":"","row-odd_styles_height":"","row-odd_styles_width":"","row-odd_styles_font-size":"","row-odd_styles_margin":"","row-odd_styles_padding":"","row-odd_styles_display":"","row-odd_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","row-odd_styles_advanced":"","success-msg_styles_background-color":"","success-msg_styles_border":"","success-msg_styles_border-style":"","success-msg_styles_border-color":"","success-msg_styles_color":"","success-msg_styles_height":"","success-msg_styles_width":"","success-msg_styles_font-size":"","success-msg_styles_margin":"","success-msg_styles_padding":"","success-msg_styles_display":"","success-msg_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","success-msg_styles_advanced":"","error_msg_styles_background-color":"","error_msg_styles_border":"","error_msg_styles_border-style":"","error_msg_styles_border-color":"","error_msg_styles_color":"","error_msg_styles_height":"","error_msg_styles_width":"","error_msg_styles_font-size":"","error_msg_styles_margin":"","error_msg_styles_padding":"","error_msg_styles_display":"","error_msg_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","error_msg_styles_advanced":"","changeEmailErrorMsg":"Please enter a valid email address!","confirmFieldErrorMsg":"These fields must match!","fieldNumberNumMinError":"Number Min Error","fieldNumberNumMaxError":"Number Max Error","fieldNumberIncrementBy":"Please increment by ","formErrorsCorrectErrors":"Please correct errors before submitting this form.","validateRequiredField":"This is a required field.","honeypotHoneypotError":"Honeypot Error","fieldsMarkedRequired":"Fields marked with an <span class=\"ninja-forms-req-symbol\">*<\/span> are required","currency":"","unique_field_error":"A form with this value has already been submitted.","allow_public_link":0,"embed_form":"","drawerDisabled":false,"ninjaForms":"Ninja Forms","changeDateErrorMsg":"Please enter a valid date!","fieldTextareaRTEInsertLink":"Insert Link","fieldTextareaRTEInsertMedia":"Insert Media","fieldTextareaRTESelectAFile":"Select a file","formHoneypot":"If you are a human seeing this field, please leave it empty.","fileUploadOldCodeFileUploadInProgress":"File Upload in Progress.","fileUploadOldCodeFileUpload":"FILE UPLOAD","currencySymbol":"&#36;","thousands_sep":",","decimal_point":".","siteLocale":"en_AU","dateFormat":"m\/d\/Y","startOfWeek":"1","of":"of","previousMonth":"Previous Month","nextMonth":"Next Month","months":["January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"monthsShort":["Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"weekdays":["Sunday","Monday","Tuesday","Wednesday","Thursday","Friday","Saturday"],"weekdaysShort":["Sun","Mon","Tue","Wed","Thu","Fri","Sat"],"weekdaysMin":["Su","Mo","Tu","We","Th","Fr","Sa"],"currency_symbol":"","beforeForm":"","beforeFields":"","afterFields":"","afterForm":""};form.fields=[{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":1,"label":"Name","key":"name","type":"textbox","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Name","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":"","disable_input":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","disable_browser_autocomplete":"","mask":"","custom_mask":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"#ffffff","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"#ffffff","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"#ffffff","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3466","custom_name_attribute":"","personally_identifiable":"","value":"","id":"5_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["textbox","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":2,"label":"Contact Number","key":"contact_number_1491218320211","type":"textbox","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Contact Number","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":"","disable_input":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","disable_browser_autocomplete":"","mask":"","custom_mask":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"0px","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3470","custom_name_attribute":"","personally_identifiable":"","value":"","id":"10_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["textbox","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":3,"label":"Email","key":"email","type":"email","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Email","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3473","custom_name_attribute":"email","personally_identifiable":1,"value":"","id":"6_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"email","element_templates":["email","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":4,"label":"I need help with...","type":"textarea","key":"i_need_help_with_1549425070059","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"default":"","placeholder":"I need help with...","container_class":"","element_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":false,"admin_label":"","help_text":"","textarea_rte":"","disable_rte_mobile":"","textarea_media":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"cellcid":"c3476","drawerDisabled":false,"value":"","id":"71_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textarea","element_templates":["textarea","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":5,"label":"Recaptcha","type":"recaptcha","container_class":"","element_class":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"size":"visible","key":"recaptcha_1602543056346","cellcid":"c3731","id":"80_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["recaptcha","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap","site_key":"6LdootYZAAAAAEwDzfbB_4BI4UK8B2U9F1bmQcbQ","theme":"dark","lang":"en"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":6,"label":"Hidden","type":"hidden","key":"hidden_1571292741941","default":"{wp:post_title}","admin_label":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_border":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_border":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"cellcid":"c3479","drawerDisabled":false,"id":"72_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"hidden","element_templates":["hidden","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap-no-label"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":7,"label":"SPEAK TO A B2B EXPERT","key":"speak_to_a_b2b_expert_1508319997306","type":"submit","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","processing_label":"Processing","container_class":"","element_class":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"100%","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"block","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"100%","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"block","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"#31415c","element_styles_border":"","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"#ffffff","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"100%","element_styles_font-size":"18px","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"10px","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","submit_element_hover_styles_background-color":"#162542","submit_element_hover_styles_border":"","submit_element_hover_styles_border-style":"","submit_element_hover_styles_border-color":"","submit_element_hover_styles_color":"#ffffff","submit_element_hover_styles_height":"","submit_element_hover_styles_width":"","submit_element_hover_styles_font-size":"","submit_element_hover_styles_margin":"","submit_element_hover_styles_padding":"","submit_element_hover_styles_display":"","submit_element_hover_styles_float":"","submit_element_hover_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"submit_element_hover_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3482","drawerDisabled":false,"id":"8_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["submit","button","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap-no-label"}];nfForms.push(form);</script>
                <script id="nf-tmpl-cell" type="text/template">
            <nf-fields></nf-fields>
        </script>

        <script id="nf-tmpl-row" type="text/template">
            <nf-cells></nf-cells>
        </script>

        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/six-steps-account-based-marketing/">The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimising Your B2B Email Marketing Click Through And Open Rates</title>
		<link>/optimising-your-b2b-email-marketing-click-through-and-open-rates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you looking for ways to increase your click through and open rates for your next B2B email marketing campaign? Find out the secret to optimising your campaigns today. Email marketing may be one of the most economic and effective ways to nurture and mobilise existing leads and customers. According to Campaign Monitor’s annual report [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimising-your-b2b-email-marketing-click-through-and-open-rates/">Optimising Your B2B Email Marketing Click Through And Open Rates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are you looking for ways to increase your click through and open rates for your next </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">B2B email marketing campaign</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? Find out the secret to optimising your campaigns today.</span></p>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> may be one of the most economic and effective ways to nurture and mobilise existing leads and customers. According to </span><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/company/annual-report/2016/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Campaign Monitor’s annual report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from 2016, the average Return On Investment (ROI) for every dollar spent on email marketing is $44. That kind of return eclipses almost all other forms of marketing, including mobile marketing, social media, display advertising and search engine marketing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the context of <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B marketing</a>, email plays a central role in generating and nurturing leads. Compared to other marketing tools email marketing has a wide reach and can help you isolate and nurture leads if you do it right. </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> tends to be the B2B marketing tool of choice for three reasons: measurability, affordability and personalisation.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Below we will identify what makes a good email marketing campaign, how you can improve the click through rates (CTR) and optimise open rates for your brand using a variety of tactics ranging from segmentation to utilising calls-to-action more effectively.</span></p>
<h2><b>Overview of B2B Email Marketing</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The world of social media marketing may attract many with it’s glamour; however, according to global management consultant </span><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/about-us/overview"><span style="font-weight: 400;">McKinsey &amp; Company</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, email marketing is 40 times more likely to lead to acquisition than Facebook and Twitter combined.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we all know, the world of business revolves around email. Over </span><a href="http://sourcedigit.com/4233-much-email-use-daily-182-9-billion-emails-sentreceived-per-day-worldwide/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">190 billion emails</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are sent every day. The hard part for marketers is cutting through the clutter.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Principles of Good B2B Email Marketing</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The principles of good </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">B2B email marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have been around for a long time; long before the internet even. </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is essentially direct mail marketing gone digital. There are plenty of lessons to be learned from the past. Direct marketing is an art-form that has been around since the 19th century when mail-order catalogues were first distributed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there is anything to learn from a century of direct marketing, it is that results require patience &#8211; especially for B2B. After all, the term “impulse buy” is not one you hear often in the world of B2B marketing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">B2B purchasing decisions are made over a long period of time. That is to say, the foundation of B2B marketing is in building relationships gradually. Doing this requires more than just a hard sell, it requires being genuinely useful to your leads. If you are useful, when it comes to buy, they will come to you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike their B2C counterparts, B2B marketers have found that the majority of their success comes from inbound </span><a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-content-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">content marketing solutions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead of hard selling, informative and relevant emails allow businesses to build a rapport with their leads.  Sharing informative articles and resources with clients will help them along their buyer journey and expose your brand to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To quote the Roman poet, Publilius Syrus, “Take an interest in others and they will take an interest in you!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After you have built this rapport, finding the right moment to strike is important. Much like a good joke, the most important element of lead generation is… timing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best email marketing campaigns are event-driven. Good marketers will learn as much as possible and find opportunities to engage with their leads at exactly the right times. Whether that be the expiration of a contract, changes in the life-cycle of the business or even the impact of a natural disaster. Find ways to bring your product or solution forward when your prospects need them the most.</span></p>
<h2><b>Optimising Open Rates</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An email marketing campaign is only effective if the recipient actually opens the email in the first place. This is the first step in enticing them, if they don’t open it then all the content is wasted as they won’t see it anyway.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Open rates are a percentage based on how many of recipients actually opened your email. This number can differ drastically depending on the type campaign you are running and type of subscribers on your list.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The open rate is a good indication of how many prospects are genuinely engaged in the content that you are sending them. Below are five of our top tactics for optimising open rates.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4671 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DELIVERY-TIMES.jpg" alt="Open Rates" width="800" height="380" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DELIVERY-TIMES.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DELIVERY-TIMES-300x143.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/05/DELIVERY-TIMES-768x365.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Experiment with Delivery Times</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As we’ve already mentioned earlier in the article, timing is everything in marketing! When it comes to sending out emails, you want to get in front of your audience when they are in front of their screens.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t rely on generalised infographics to find out what those times are. Just because HubSpot says that 12 noon on a Wednesday is the best time to send out a campaign doesn’t mean that it will work for your business. Every campaign is different. Try experimenting with different delivery times and look for patterns.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Segment Your Prospects</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Break up your subscriber lists into more detailed segments. The more you can personalise each email sent out, the more likely you are going to get the response you want. There are several ways to do this.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You may want to divide your prospects by behaviour, demographics, the dates they signed up or even the type of devices they use to open their emails. According to </span><a href="https://mailchimp.com/resources/research/effects-of-list-segmentation-on-email-marketing-stats/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">MailChimp</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, segmented campaigns are 13.07% more likely to be opened than general campaigns.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Don’t Use Spam Words</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spam filters are getting tougher and tougher on bulk emails every day. Check your emails to make sure you aren’t setting off any red flags with your content. Terms like “earn now”, “winning” or “free when you buy”, may be interpreted by Google or Outlook as spam. Be careful not to trigger those spam filters!</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Resend Emails That Have Been Left Unopened</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Entrepreneur Neil Taparia discovered that he was able to improve the reach of his email marketing by 54.7% by resending emails that were left unopened. Email marketer Noah Kagan replicated Taperia’s results with a 30% increase in his open rates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It may be that your email was lost in the clutter, not necessarily ignored. Give your prospects the benefit of the doubt and try changing the subject line and sending out those emails again a few days later.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Simple and Urgent Subject Lines</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Long subject lines will discourage viewers. Get to the point with your subject lines, or at least create some intrigue. Use scarcity tactics or humor to get their attention. If you can’t attract attention immediately you are not likely to see results. Don’t try to be too obscure either; just be up front. To quote the advertising legend David Ogilvy, “What you say in advertising is more important that how you say it!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One tactic you may wish to employ may be subject line testing. This involves experimenting with different subject lines to see what gets the best result. As a rule of thumb, headings with numbers are effective at engaging prospects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Emojis don’t tend to have a place in B2B communication, however this is a bit of a contentious issue. Read this article to find out more about the </span><a href="/the-rise-of-emojis-in-email-marketing-can-b2b-marketers-benefit/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rise Of The Emoji</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2><b>Improving Your Click-Through Rates</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So you have gotten as far as getting your prospects to open the email, but do you know how to get them from their inbox to your website?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Click-Through Rates (CTR) can be measured by the number of prospects who clicked a link over the number of recipients who opened the email or by the number of recipients total. Measuring your CTR against the number of opened emails is more accurate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In our experience, there are a number of things that you can do to improve your CTR.  Below are some of those tactics.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Make Your Message Clear</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every email has a purpose. This purpose is expressed through a call-to-action (CTA) which is designed to motivate the client into doing some sort of action. An example of a Call to Action may be, “call now to receive 10% off” or “don’t miss out, find out more today.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t convolute your email marketing with too many ambiguous CTAs or irrelevant copy. Have one purpose and one purpose only and design your copy so that it guides the prospect towards it. For that matter, don’t write an essay, keep it concise and to the point, and remember pictures are always preferable to words.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4671 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/socials.jpg" alt="Social Sharing Buttons" width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Add Social Sharing Buttons</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the </span><a href="https://www.socialfresh.com/how-to-use-social-sharing-buttons-to-increase-email-marketing-results/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Social Times</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, adding social sharing buttons to your email campaigns can increase the CTR by up to 150%. You may ask, ‘why put social sharing buttons in your emails?’, but the more pertinent question is, ‘why not?’. They take little space, improve CTR and are nice way to make your email less text-heavy. Social sharing buttons are a great way spread information further and reach a wider audience.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Mobile Responsive Emails</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did you know that</span><a href="https://lonelybrand.com/blog/mobile-email-statistics/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 65% of all emails are first opened on a mobile phone</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? However, if your email templates aren’t mobile optimised they may end up being difficult to navigate and take a while to load. Optimising your emails to make them more mobile-friendly is one of the best things you can do to ensure a higher CTR.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Video Email Marketing</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to email marketing company </span><a href="https://www.zettasphere.com/why-adding-video-to-your-emails-isnt-working/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mailigen</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, embedding a video inside your email will increase your CTR by 280%. Mailigen aren’t the only ones to notice these kind of miraculous results, the town of Enfield, CT found they experienced a 28% increase in their CTR by adding a video. If you are struggling with your CTRs, experimenting with videos may be a great avenue to explore.</span></p>
<h2><b>Summary</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Email marketing can be one of the most effective marketing tools available for B2B marketers. However, to get the most out of your email marketing requires regular optimisation and experimentation. Using industry benchmarks may be a great way to measure how you are tracking at first, however the ultimate goal of any email marketing campaign is to learn how to outperform your own results. Hopefully these tips will empower you to do just that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are looking for advice on your </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">B2B email marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> campaign, The Lead Agency, are experts with experience in developing email campaigns that generate more leads and better quality leads. </span><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Click here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to find out more about our email marketing services.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you would like to learn more about optimising your email marketing campaigns, read this article about </span><a href="/the-3-most-important-benefits-of-email-marketing/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Three Most Important Benefits Of Email Marketing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p>And don’t forget to check out our other service industries which include the following; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/optimising-your-b2b-email-marketing-click-through-and-open-rates/">Optimising Your B2B Email Marketing Click Through And Open Rates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Warm Up a Cold Email List</title>
		<link>/warm-cold-email-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 05:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Any relationship is difficult to maintain without regular communication over time, and this is no different when it comes to your email subscribers or customers. If you don’t communicate with them, they’re likely to give you the cold shoulder. What is a Cold Email List? A cold email list is often the result of purchasing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/warm-cold-email-list/">How to Warm Up a Cold Email List</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Any relationship is difficult to maintain without regular communication over time, and this is no different when it comes to your email subscribers or customers. If you don’t communicate with them, they’re likely to give you the cold shoulder.</p>
<h3><strong>What is a Cold Email List?</strong></h3>
<p>A cold email list is often the result of purchasing email addressed or using a list that is out of date. Email contacts move companies and change email addresses often and the longer your list sits there, the more email addresses that you have will bounce.</p>
<p>A cold email list tends to have higher bounce rates and spam reporting. There are many risks when sending emails to cold or unengaged lists, which will negatively impact your ability to communicate with your subscribers. For example, you may:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hurt your sender reputation</li>
<li>Associate your brand/business with bad email etiquette</li>
<li>Taint your relationship with your Email Service Provider</li>
<li>Generate spam complaints</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>What is a Hot Email List?</strong></h3>
<p>With a hot email list, the recipients were put there purposefully for example by signing up to a network or downloading a piece of content. The recipients on a hot email list know who your brand is and are therefore more likely to open your email and respond accordingly.</p>
<p>Contact is maintained with the recipients on a hot email list by sending them regular content and company updates so that the brand name has stayed familiar in their minds. Furthermore, a hot email list is most often segmented so that you can send personalized messaging to each segment.</p>
<h3>How to Warm Up a Cold Email List</h3>
<h4><strong>Say Goodbye</strong></h4>
<p>The first step to warming up your cold list is to remove any purchased names and out of date contacts.   Get rid of any contacts that aren’t interested in you, your products or services. 20,000 contact aren’t always better than 2,000 contacts who read every email.</p>
<h4><strong>Re-Engage Your Contacts</strong></h4>
<p>Then you need to decide on a strategic plan as to how you are going to re-engage these people and give them the opportunity to decide if they want to continue to hear from your brand or not.</p>
<p>Your re-engagement email should be personal, and remind the recipient of why they opted in and why they should continue to receive your communications. In order to do this, the email should offer value to the customer, whether that be through knowledge or information, a product or service offer such as a discount or other special offer, or anything else that is valuable to your customer.</p>
<h4>Make a Good Second Impression</h4>
<p>A strong second impression is vital in warming up your email list. The re-engagement shouldn’t be a regular newsletter, or a fun brand update. Those will come later. Instead, you should address the fact that you haven’t been in touch for a while with a ‘we miss you’ email, a touching base email, or a survey asking for input on the types of communications they’d like to receive.</p>
<p>By doing this, you will quickly heat up your email list.</p>
<h4><strong>Be Prepared</strong></h4>
<p>Don’t just plan you’re re-engagement email, send it, and then decide what comes next. In order to heat up your email marketing list, it’s vital to have your entire email campaign planned out before you send a single email.</p>
<p>Consider the objectives of your email campaign and how you’re going to use the channel to improve your wider marketing efforts. Write out a schedule and the next few weeks or months of emails so that you can keep the conversation going.</p>
<h3><strong>Warming Up an Email List: Lead Agency Case Study</strong></h3>
<p>At <a href="/contact-us/">The Lead Agency</a>, we specialise in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">email marketing</a> and have warmed up email lists for several clients that we have worked with. A particular campaign that we were involved a Recruitment client aiming to re-engage with a cold email list of over 18,000 subscribers.</p>
<p>We cleaned up and segmented the database, so that we could send a reengagement email to specific sectors. As a result, we received extremely high open rates up to 43.56% and click through rates up to 26.21% with over 2,500 recipients visiting the website. We have continued to send emails to this database, and almost 12 months on from this campaign, still see much success.</p>
<p>This case study demonstrates that a cold email list isn’t necessarily dead, and with the right strategy, can be used to create a successful campaign.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">Digital Marketing</a> and in particular <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B Email Marketing</a> read our article on <a href="/5-email-marketing-tips-to-increase-your-open-rate/">5 Email Marketing Tips To Increase Your Open Rate</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/warm-cold-email-list/">How to Warm Up a Cold Email List</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
