<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Marketing Strategy Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/marketing-strategy-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:02:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Marketing Strategy Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>3 Reasons Why Your B2B Leads Aren’t Converting</title>
		<link>/3-reasons-why-your-b2b-leads-arent-converting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 01:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=42597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>You’re attracting an influx of leads, but still struggling to drive conversions and reach your B2B business’ objectives – what’s going wrong? It’s not uncommon for B2B organisations to encounter issues when working towards converting leads, and if you look at the statistics, they paint a pretty good picture of why this is the case. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-reasons-why-your-b2b-leads-arent-converting/">3 Reasons Why Your B2B Leads Aren’t Converting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’re attracting an influx of leads, but still struggling to drive conversions and reach your B2B business’ objectives – what’s going wrong?</p>
<p>It’s not uncommon for B2B organisations to encounter issues when working towards converting leads, and if you look at the statistics, they paint a pretty good picture of why this is the case.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://sherpablog.marketingsherpa.com/email-marketing/b2b-lead-nurturing-importance/"><em>73% of all B2B leads</em></a><em> are not sales-ready.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>More often than not, a new lead isn’t actually ready to convert. The B2B purchasing process is far from linear and, rather, is becoming increasingly long and complex. Now, <a href="https://www.bluecorona.com/blog/b2b-marketing-statistics/">90% of B2B buyers</a> loop back and repeat at least one step or task in the sales funnel, so a prospect’s initial interest in your product or service by no means guarantees that they’ll convert anytime time soon – or at all.</p>
<h2>Getting to the Crux of the Problem</h2>
<p>First and foremost, it’s important to recognise that, unfortunately, there isn’t a ‘cookie-cutter’ approach for converting leads. What works for one company won’t necessarily work for another, so finding a suitable solution isn’t always going to be straightforward.</p>
<p>When it comes to determining what needs to change, pinpointing where exactly your leads are disengaging is a great place to start. This will give you the means to target specific downfalls, tackling them head-on, rather than making changes that <em>might </em>help and hoping for the best.</p>
<p>While their circumstances aren’t identical, many B2B companies do experience similar issues that negatively impact their conversions. In this article, we’ll be looking into 3 common reasons why your leads might not be converting.</p>
<h2>1. Your Leads Aren’t Qualified</h2>
<p>First of all, you need to consider whether or not the leads you’re generating are actually qualified. In essence, this means knowing who your B2B business’ ideal audience and clients are and, respectively, making sure they’re the leads you’re attracting.</p>
<p>While it might be easy to generate an abundance of leads, if you’re not getting the <em>right</em> leads, your efforts will be both unproductive and ineffective.</p>
<p>To drive conversions, there needs to be a strong alignment between your marketing, audience and product or service. If your marketing efforts aren’t targeted and; thus, aren’t reaching your ideal audience members in impactful ways that will resonate with them, this lack of direction will be reflected in the number of these leads that convert.</p>
<p>If you’re struggling to generate qualified leads, you want to ensure your marketing efforts are targeted, which means focusing on the right keywords, marketing channels, audiences and the like. This all stems from conducting thorough market research and continuing to monitor and refine your campaigns even after they’re up and running, so that the strategic decisions you’re making are informed and supported by relevant facts and evidence.</p>
<h2>2. Your B2B Marketing &amp; Sales Teams Aren’t Aligned</h2>
<p>If your marketing and sales teams aren’t working together cooperatively, this will likely result in bumps along your prospect’s buyer journey.</p>
<p>For instance, from your marketing efforts, a potential buyer may have a certain understanding of your B2B business’ offering. However, if they then speak with sales and, in doing this, are met with a message that doesn’t quite line up, this can result in confusion, frustration and disengagement.</p>
<p>In avoiding this, there needs to be strong two-way communication between your sales and marketing teams, helping employees ensure that messages remain consistent, so they can be reinforced at each point of contact.</p>
<p>In addition, by establishing clear pathways for different segments of your ideal audience to follow in the buyer journey, your B2B business can effectively categorise prospects, delivering personalised communications and making their overall experience harmonious and well thought out.</p>
<p>For example, a prospect might display a specific interest in a particular product or service you offer. With this in mind, you can then tailor your sales team’s efforts accordingly, such as by getting the customer in contact with an employee who is experienced or specialised in their area of interest.</p>
<h2>3. Your Leads are Slipping Through the Cracks</h2>
<p>Even if you’re generating a large number of leads, if you don’t have the team members available to follow your B2B business’ processes for managing them, you’re likely letting potential customers slip away.</p>
<p>This may be the case if the responsibility for managing prospects sits with a few select individuals. In such instances, there’s the potential for valuable leads to essentially get ‘stuck’ in the buyer funnel, especially during peak times when key team members may be preoccupied with other tasks.</p>
<p>While it’s easy to get comfortable and content with your B2B business’ existing processes, your team only have so much time in a day. Insufficient systems and procedures will hinder their ability to <a href="/how-to-nurture-leads-with-b2b-marketing-automation/">nurture leads</a> and, ultimately, to capture and leverage their initial interest and drive conversions. Thus, with this in mind, you may need to consider outsourcing, delegating or automating certain processes, so you can maximise outcomes and convert more leads.</p>
<p>If you’re interested in driving conversions and building strong client relationships, <a href="/contact-us/">get in touch</a> with our team at the Lead Agency today.</p>
<p>We specialise in a range of <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/">B2B marketing services</a>, including <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">B2B social media marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B search engine optimisation</a>, <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-reasons-why-your-b2b-leads-arent-converting/">3 Reasons Why Your B2B Leads Aren’t Converting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Your B2B Business Can Use Data More Effectively</title>
		<link>/how-your-b2b-business-can-use-data-more-effectively/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>B2B marketers unanimously agree that quality data empowers them to deliver the right message to customers at just the right time – Dun &#38; Bradstreet The value of applying marketing data to B2B campaigns is undeniable. Businesses that adopt a data-driven approach to marketing have an advantage over the competition, and are more likely to [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-your-b2b-business-can-use-data-more-effectively/">How Your B2B Business Can Use Data More Effectively</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>B2B marketers unanimously agree that quality data empowers them to deliver the right message to customers at just the right time – <a href="https://www.dnb.com/perspectives/marketing-sales/5-shocking-stats-about-b2b-marketing-data.html">Dun &amp; Bradstreet</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The value of applying marketing data to B2B campaigns is undeniable. Businesses that adopt a data-driven approach to marketing have an advantage over the competition, and are more likely to increase profitability. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescommunicationscouncil/2018/03/05/the-rise-of-the-data-driven-marketer-why-its-beneficial-and-how-to-hire-one/#43ccee9a490d">In fact, they are six times more likely to be profitable year-over-year</a>.</p>
<p>The case for using marketing data has never been stronger, and B2B companies that can master best practices for collecting, analysing, and reporting on data are most likely to thrive now and into the future.</p>
<p>In order to become data-focused with their marketing campaigns, B2B marketers must first understand which metrics are most important to them. Gone are the days when ‘total website traffic’ was a sufficient metric to analyse the success of a campaign. Now, marketers can arm themselves with in-depth, insightful data on the specifics of each campaign. This can then be used to inform not only marketing initiatives, but also wider business decisions.</p>
<h2>Which Marketing Metrics Should B2B Companies Measure?</h2>
<p>In order to get the most out of marketing efforts, B2B companies should establish clear business goals based on results-based marketing metrics. Some of the results-based metrics that can inform these decisions are as follows.</p>
<h3> 1. Conversion Rate</h3>
<p>Your <a href="https://www.wordstream.com/conversion-rate">conversion rate is the percentage of website visitors that complete a desired goal</a>. If your site has a high conversion rate, you can assume that your marketing is performing well overall, as people are responding to your campaigns and acting on your message.</p>
<p>A ‘conversion’ can be any action that you want on your website. Typically a conversion should measure a specific, measurable jump in the sales funnel, for example, a sign up to a newsletter, resource download or a request for a demo. Consider which actions are valuable to your business and that indicate interest in your products or services. These can then be set up as conversion actions.</p>
<p>Remember that not all leads will move down the sales funnel to purchase, in fact most of them won’t: <a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2014/03/17/what-is-a-good-conversion-rate">2.35% is the average conversion rate, and anything above 5% is considered a good conversion rate</a>. The best way to increase your conversion rate is to set up conversion tracking to measure the different actions a website visitor takes before making a sale. With this data, you can start to identify where potential customers are dropping off and look at reducing this drop off through your marketing messaging and campaigns.</p>
<h3> 2. Return on Investment (ROI)</h3>
<p>ROI is a calculation that compares the amount of money you spend on a project with the amount of revenue you gain from it. In applying this to your marketing campaigns, you can ensure that the value they are bringing in outweighs the costs incurred. This is one of the <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/34054/the-6-marketing-metrics-your-ceo-actually-cares-about-cheat-sheet.aspx">best metrics to use to show other c-level executives that they should be investing more in marketing</a> – and exactly which campaigns they should be investing in.</p>
<p>If you compare ROI data between campaigns, you will be able to see which are the most effective in generating revenue, and as such, where marketing budget should be assigned. Simply put, measuring your ROI is one of the easiest ways to understand what actually works (and what does not) with your campaigns.</p>
<h3> 3. Marketing-Qualified Leads (MQL)</h3>
<p><a href="https://searchcustomerexperience.techtarget.com/definition/marketing-qualified-lead-MQL">Marketing Qualified Leads</a> are leads that are generated through marketing campaigns, such as Google Ads, SEO and Social Media. These leads have found your website, and have shown some interest in your business but they are not yet ready to buy, and so, have not converted. While they may not be ready to purchase yet, these leads should not be discounted. They are still valuable to your company as they are interested in your business’ products or services, and they meet early-stage criteria of a potential customer.</p>
<p>The definition of a Marketing Qualified Lead is up to the business to decide. Relevant information, such as company size, industry and annual revenue, are all considerations that may identify a Marketing Qualified Lead. If your business has a lot of Marketing Qualified Leads, this is an indication that your marketing campaigns are effective in attracting potential customers to your site and sparking interest in your company’s products or services.</p>
<h3> 4. Sales-Qualified Leads (SQL)</h3>
<p>A Sales Qualified Lead differs from a Marketing Qualified Lead in that it has been nurtured along the sales funnel and is more ready to purchase. At this point, the lead will most likely be passed on to the sales team, who will be responsible for closing the sale. Like Marketing Qualified Leads, Sales Qualified Leads should be identified by the business on the basis of their own sales funnel. For example, a Sales Qualified Lead may have they requested a demo, clicked an important link in an email, or submitted an enquiry on your website.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.marketingprofs.com/">Aligning sales and marketing leads to 38% higher sales win rates</a>. Marketing Qualified Leads and Sales Qualified Leads are both essential element of the sales funnel. Both should be taken into consideration when evaluating the success of a marketing campaign. If you have a lot of Marketing Qualified Leads but not many Sales Qualified Leads, you may need to do more work in nurturing leads through the sales funnel. This can be done by altering the messaging and content for these contacts.</p>
<p>The most important thing to takeaway from this article is to remember that marketing metrics are vital in informing the success of any campaign. Ensure you are not wasting your marketing budget on things that don’t work by measuring key conversion-focused metrics that are important for your business.</p>
<p>For more information on this article, or for wider <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">b2b digital marketing</a> advice, get in touch with the Lead Agency. We’re <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B marketing specialists</a> with wide-reaching experience in a number of on and offline channels.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-your-b2b-business-can-use-data-more-effectively/">How Your B2B Business Can Use Data More Effectively</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Shift to Digital: Enhancing the Online Customer Experience</title>
		<link>/the-shift-to-digital-enhancing-the-online-customer-experience/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 02:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In recent times, life as we know it has changed dramatically and, to the disdain of many Australians, COVID-19 restrictions may not be eased for more than six months. As the environment within which we live and work evolves and adapts, your B2B marketing strategy needs to develop as well. These are incredibly volatile times [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-shift-to-digital-enhancing-the-online-customer-experience/">The Shift to Digital: Enhancing the Online Customer Experience</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In recent times, life as we know it has changed dramatically and, to the disdain of many Australians, COVID-19 restrictions may not be eased for <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/11/the-covid-19-exit-strategy-when-will-australia-know-the-coronavirus-battle-is-over">more than six months</a>.</p>
<p>As the environment within which we live and work evolves and adapts, your B2B marketing strategy needs to develop as well. These are incredibly volatile times and, unsurprisingly, an outdated approach to B2B marketing isn’t going to help you achieve your organisation’s goals.</p>
<p>If you’re yet to establish your business’ presence online, the events unfolding across the world at the moment should be as good of a reason as any to take the plunge. With physical interactions being considerably limited, people are turning to digital, for both their personal and professional needs.</p>
<p>Given the current business climate, a strong B2B digital marketing strategy has arguably become <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2020/03/20/why-companies-turn-to-digital-marketing-to-survive-covid-19/#10e877812425">more important than ever before</a>. In the weeks and months to come, if you fail to embrace digital, you’ll likely miss out on business opportunities that are all the more valuable in these trying times.</p>
<p>Digital capabilities have transformed the way we conduct business and, in many ways, have given B2B organisations the means to streamline and enhance the customer experience. By building a strong B2B digital strategy, your business can create an exceptional online experience for users and, consequently, attract, engage and retain more quality leads well into the future.</p>
<p><em>So, how can you B2B business enhance your customer’s online experience and start reaping the benefits?</em></p>
<h3>Get Active on Social Media</h3>
<p>If your B2B company relies heavily on customer interaction that, in the past, would’ve been done face-to-face, this obviously isn’t going to be particularly practical in the existing business environment.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to maintain relevance and functionality in the current market, opening new online channels, for instance, on social media, can be an effective way to do just that. Platforms, such as Facebook or LinkedIn, give your B2B company the means to communicate with and, respectively, connect with, your audience.</p>
<p>In a time when it’s easy to feel disconnected and when even a simple handshake has become a thing of the past, creating personal, meaningful customer experiences is all the more important.</p>
<p>Whether you’re regularly posting relevant content and updates, running social media campaigns, using these channels to directly reach your target audience, or a mixture of the three, social media can be a brilliant way to foster and nurture customer relationships.</p>
<h3>Optimise Your Website</h3>
<p>With many individuals now working online, it’s a great time to build an informative, easy-to-navigate and fully functional B2B website or, alternatively, update your existing one.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“B2B vendor websites are the storefront for the organisation in today’s digital age. According to Demand Gen Report’s annual B2B Buyers </em><a href="https://www.demandgenreport.com/resources/research/the-2019-b2b-buyers-survey-report"><em>Survey</em></a><em>, 97% of senior-level B2B executives say it’s important for vendor websites to have easily-accessible content that speaks directly to their company.” – </em><a href="https://komarketing.com/blog/b2b-marketing-guide-to-success-in-the-digital-era/"><em>Ryan Young</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>Ensuring that your B2B website’s content is of high quality and; thus, that it offers notable value to users, is crucial. The content you’re putting out is a direct reflection on your brand and, beyond this, it gives your B2B business the opportunity to demonstrate your expertise in your field.</p>
<p>Typically, customers will spend <a href="https://www.crazyegg.com/blog/why-users-leave-a-website/">less than 15 seconds</a> on a website before deciding whether to look elsewhere. What does this mean for your B2B business? If you don’t effectively capture the attention of prospects in just a fraction of time, you’ll likely struggle to drive leads from your website.</p>
<p>Thus, even if you’ve got brilliant content, it’s just as important to create an impactful, memorable and aesthetically pleasing digital domain that supports and reinforces your B2B business’ branding. This will not only help spark initial interest from potential clients but also keep them engaged, all the while creating an enjoyable, value-driven customer experience online.</p>
<h3>Leverage Data to Create Targeted Customer Experiences</h3>
<p>By collecting, analysing and applying insights from data relating to your ideal consumer, your B2B business can create highly targeted online marketing efforts. This can, of course, then translate into more personalised customer experiences, all of which are tailored to the unique needs, priorities and preferences of your audience.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Only 15% of B2B companies feel they have a complete view of their customers” – </em><a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/how-b2b-digital-leaders-drive-five-times-more-revenue-growth-than-their-peers"><em>McKinsey &amp; Company</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>Beyond this, advanced analytics can guide and support continual improvement, assisting your B2B organisation in identifying and resolving any existing downfalls. In an ever-changing market, this is of particular importance. To achieve exceptional outcomes well into the future, your B2B business needs to be proactively and consistently implementing data-driven solutions that meet and, ideally, exceed your audience’s expectations.</p>
<p>Your B2B business’ goals and where exactly you’ve built, or intend to build, a presence online will impact the types of analytical software that are of value to you. If you’re interested in seeing <em>how </em>people are navigating your website, you may benefit from using Mouseflow. For more, in-depth insights for optimising your website, it could also be worth looking into SEMrush.</p>
<p>By strategically constructing B2B online experiences that are backed by reliable data, your organisation can boost customer satisfaction and facilitate positive interactions with your brand.</p>
<h3>Enhance Your Customer’s Online Experience Today</h3>
<p>For more information about the topics discussed in this article, please don’t hesitate to get in touch with our team of B2B marketing consultants. With extensive experience in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">B2B social media marketing</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">lead generation</a> and more, we’re experts in creating valuable online customer experiences that drive brilliant results.</p>
<p>Ready to prepare your B2B business for future success? <a href="/contact-us/">Contact us</a> today.</p>
<p><em>From all of the team at the Lead Agency, we hope you stay safe and healthy during these uncertain times.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-shift-to-digital-enhancing-the-online-customer-experience/">The Shift to Digital: Enhancing the Online Customer Experience</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>B2B Marketing Collateral Ideas to Keep You Busy</title>
		<link>/b2b-marketing-collateral-ideas-to-keep-you-busy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Australian economy has taken a monumental blow in recent weeks, with the fallout from the ongoing coronavirus pandemic placing immense financial strain on companies across the country. Due to the existing business climate and, more specifically, its incredibly volatile state, many organisations are looking to cut costs. This is, for many, being done in [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-marketing-collateral-ideas-to-keep-you-busy/">B2B Marketing Collateral Ideas to Keep You Busy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian economy has taken a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2020/mar/21/coronavirus-has-delivered-a-hammer-blow-to-australias-economy-what-happens-next">monumental blow in recent weeks</a>, with the fallout from the ongoing coronavirus pandemic placing immense financial strain on companies across the country.</p>
<p>Due to the existing business climate and, more specifically, its incredibly volatile state, many organisations are looking to cut costs. This is, for many, being done in a bid to preserve the long-term viability of their company.</p>
<p>Demand for products and services has plummeted across sectors, with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2020/apr/07/coronavirus-crisis-has-had-staggering-impact-on-australian-businesses-data-reveals">two-thirds of Australian companies</a> experiencing devastating losses in revenue. These financial shortcomings have, of course, been reflected in the way organisations are managing their funds.</p>
<p>Many businesses are now taking a step back from non-essential costs and, instead, prioritising those that have been deemed absolutely vital to their day-to-day operations.</p>
<p>For a large number of B2B companies, this has translated into fewer leads and, in some cases, existing clients either cutting back on or completely discontinuing their work with your business.</p>
<p>With this in mind, if you have a bit more extra time on your hands than usual at the moment, figuring out how exactly to spend it might be difficult. There are, however, numerous ways you can keep yourself (and your employees) busy if work is slow, helping you get ahead for when business takes off again.</p>
<p>Creating an exceptional collection of <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">B2B marketing collateral</a> is just one way you can use this time to prepare your business for success.</p>
<h3><strong>The Value of Brilliant B2B Marketing Collateral</strong></h3>
<p>If you’re questioning whether it’s really worth investing your time in <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">B2B marketing collateral</a>, it’s definitely worth considering the value such material can offer your business.</p>
<p>For starters, B2B marketing collateral can assist you in building up a diverse range of new value-driven resources and the like, which can be shared with your existing and future clients. This can be an incredibly effective way to keep customers engaged, providing them with access to a broad range of relevant information, all of which is presented in different, interesting ways.</p>
<p>In addition to this, it’s a great tactic for <a href="https://blog.demandmetric.com/2012/10/31/importance-of-marketing-collateral-material">establishing your business’ credibility</a> in your sector. The creation of various types of B2B marketing collateral gives your company the opportunity to effectively demonstrate your team’s expertise and depth of industry-specific knowledge. This can, of course, help you attract and retain more customers who appreciate the unmatched value that comes with an expert understanding of your field.</p>
<p>In some cases, your B2B business’ offering may be particularly complex. Because of this, the average person may struggle to comprehend various technicalities at the core of your product or service. However, marketing collateral gives you the means to explain different elements of your offering in simple terms. While this, again, conveys your expertise, it also helps to educate consumers. This, in turn, can help you differentiate your product or service from that of your competitors, all the while helping individuals understand why exactly your offering is the ideal solution for them.</p>
<h3>Types of Marketing Collateral to Try</h3>
<p>Your B2B company’s unique business context, priorities, preferences and goals will likely dictate the types of marketing collateral you decide to produce.</p>
<p>By building a deep understanding of your desired audience, you can ensure that the content you’re putting out is highly targeted, applying a distinct tone and covering carefully selected topics that will be of interest to your market. Of course, it’s a good idea to establish what types of information will be best suited to reaching your target audience in meaningful, memorable and valuable ways <em>before </em>investing in marketing collateral.</p>
<p>There’s a wide variety of printed and digital <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">B2B marketing collateral</a> that you may decide to give a try, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Corporate Brochures</li>
<li>Case Studies</li>
<li>Clients Testimonials</li>
<li>Websites</li>
<li>Regular Blogs</li>
<li>Email Newsletters</li>
<li>eBooks and Downloadable Guides</li>
<li>Infographics</li>
<li>Product Catalogues</li>
<li>Audio-Visual Content</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s also worth keeping in mind that, when you’re creating B2B marketing collateral, consistent branding across all of the material is crucial. This will assist you in reinforcing your brand messaging, while also helping you present aesthetically pleasing content that’s enjoyable for users to consume.</p>
<h3>Get Started on Your B2B Marketing Collateral</h3>
<p>Interested in creating brilliant marketing collateral for your B2B business? Our team can help. With extensive experience in B2B marketing, we have the expert skills and knowledge to help you build a collection of engaging, value-driven B2B marketing collateral. For more information, <a href="/contact-us/">get in touch with us</a> today.</p>
<p><em>From all of the team at the Lead Agency, we hope you stay safe and healthy during these uncertain times.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-marketing-collateral-ideas-to-keep-you-busy/">B2B Marketing Collateral Ideas to Keep You Busy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Practical Ways to Build an Exceptional Inbound Marketing Strategy</title>
		<link>/3-practical-ways-to-build-an-exceptional-inbound-marketing-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When people think of marketing, outbound tactics are often the first to come to mind. Strategies of this nature are disruptive, as the consumer isn’t actively searching for the product or service being advertised to them. Businesses employing this tactic seek out potential customers and target them through relatively traditional marketing approaches. Television, print or [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-practical-ways-to-build-an-exceptional-inbound-marketing-strategy/">3 Practical Ways to Build an Exceptional Inbound Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When people think of marketing, outbound tactics are often the first to come to mind. Strategies of this nature are disruptive, as the consumer isn’t actively searching for the product or service being advertised to them. Businesses employing this tactic seek out potential customers and target them through relatively traditional marketing approaches.</p>
<p>Television, print or radio ads, telemarketing calls, paid email lists, video ads and the like are all considered outbound forms of advertising. Such methods are interruptive and, if you don’t pay much attention to them, you aren’t alone.</p>
<p>It’s becoming increasingly easy for consumers to avoid advertisements, which makes generating valuable outcomes from outbound marketing all the more challenging. Viewers are recording television shows so they can skip over the ads at a later time and streaming services, such as Netflix, that have no ads are continuing to grow in popularity. In fact, it’s estimated that <a href="https://www.statista.com/topics/842/netflix/">37% of Internet users</a> worldwide are now using Netflix – and it’s only one of the many streaming platforms available to customers.</p>
<p>Email is another common outbound marketing technique but, similarly to ads, this tactic has its downfalls. If the recipients on your email lists aren’t interested in your content, then they can unsubscribe in just a few seconds. Alternatively, they may simply ignore your emails when scanning through their inbox. The average worker has <a href="https://www.theladders.com/career-advice/average-inbox-199-unread-emails">199 unread emails</a>, so if your message doesn’t grab their attention or appear important, you’ll likely end up being number 200.</p>
<p>So, when consumers are constantly looking for new ways to avoid your advertisements, how are you meant to reach them in meaningful ways that drive conversions? By drawing those who are genuinely interested in, and actively looking for your product or service to your business.</p>
<p>This is a <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">marketing strategy</a> known as <em>inbound marketing.</em></p>
<h2>What is Inbound Marketing?</h2>
<p>When organisations implement inbound marketing strategies, they focus on creating valuable, relevant, high-quality content that attracts their target audience to their brand. Through inbound marketing, businesses can essentially ‘pull’ prospects that are interested in the type of offering they provide towards their company.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Inbound marketing is responsible for </em><a href="https://www.wordstream.com/blog/ws/2015/08/25/inbound-marketing-strategy"><em>90%+ of clicks online</em></a><em>.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>By implementing a comprehensive inbound marketing strategy, brands can attract potential consumers to their business naturally. When customers search for certain content, discover your brand and deem what you’re offering as valuable to them, they’re displaying a clear interest in what you have to offer. This is why, often, inbound marketing proves to be far more effective than telling prospects that they <em>should </em>like your offering by using in-your-face tactics.</p>
<h2>Actionable Inbound Marketing Strategies</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7532" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Actionable-Inbound-Marketing-Strategies.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Actionable-Inbound-Marketing-Strategies.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Actionable-Inbound-Marketing-Strategies-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Actionable-Inbound-Marketing-Strategies-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>Inbound marketing tactics can be incredibly effective when implemented correctly. If you’re interested in integrating inbound marketing into your current strategy but aren’t sure where to begin, why not give one of the following a try?</p>
<h4>1. Focus on Search Engine Optimisation</h4>
<p>For any inbound marketing strategy to reach its full potential, prospects need to be able to find your brand’s content online. There are over <a href="https://www.internetlivestats.com/total-number-of-websites/">1.7 billion websites</a>, and if potential customers can’t find your online domains, they’ll simply look to satisfy their needs elsewhere.</p>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">Search Engine Optimisation</a> helps to boost your ranking in Google’s search results, which, in turn improves your accessibility online. It’s an approach that focuses on growing your visibility to drive more relevant, organic traffic to your website.</p>
<p>A strong <a href="/why-internal-linking-is-a-vital-part-of-any-seo-strategy/">SEO strategy</a> incorporates high-quality content, internal and external links site-wide and a functional website structure. The inclusion of keywords is also another crucial component of this tactic and it’s important that, when choosing terms to include, you select those that have both high search volume and user intent. This ensures that your online domains are appearing in relevant contexts and, thus, that you’re attracting prospects who are actually interested in your content.</p>
<h4>2. Launch a Pay-Per-Click Advertising Campaign<strong> </strong></h4>
<p><a href="/steps-to-success-with-your-b2b-paid-search-campaigns/">Paid search advertising</a> may seem out of place in an article about inbound marketing, but it can actually be a great technique to use when employing a strategy of this nature.</p>
<p>Your PPC ads will be shown in contexts where potential customers have actively sought out a topic or offering relevant to your brand. This means that rather than being disruptive, like what we see with outbound tactics, you’re essentially paying to boost your search ranking and improve your visibility. By doing this, organisations can compete for the top positions in the search results and, thus, attract a greater volume of highly relevant leads.</p>
<p>Similarly to SEO, Pay-Per-Click advertising campaigns focus on keywords that are highly relevant to your brand. However, organisations will often find that PPC delivers quicker results that SEO, which is generally more of a gradual process.</p>
<h4>3. Refresh &amp; Revolutionise Your Content Marketing</h4>
<p>Content is a crucial component of your inbound marketing strategy. If you aren’t regularly creating fresh content that delivers unique value to consumers, they’ll likely lose interest in your brand.</p>
<p>By building an effective <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content strategy</a> into your inbound marketing approach, you’ll be able to further differentiate your brand from competitors while also giving prospects a reason to stick around. This, in turn, can help you foster ongoing, meaningful relationships with leads that achieve mutually beneficial outcomes.</p>
<p>So, what types of content could your B2B business consider creating?</p>
<ul>
<li>A frequently updated blog that covers topics directly related to your offering;</li>
<li>Downloadable resources such as guides or eBooks;</li>
<li>Case studies based on customer testimonials;</li>
<li>Infographics;</li>
<li>Videos.<strong style="color: #555555; font-size: 14.4px;"> </strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Want to start enjoying the benefits that come with an effective, comprehensive B2B inbound marketing strategy? For more information, or to find about the <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends your business should be paying attention to, speak with a <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> specialist today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-practical-ways-to-build-an-exceptional-inbound-marketing-strategy/">3 Practical Ways to Build an Exceptional Inbound Marketing Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Overlooking Technical Elements in Your SEO Strategy?</title>
		<link>/are-you-overlooking-technical-elements-in-your-seo-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 06:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>61% of marketers say improving SEO and growing their organic presence is their top inbound marketing priority. What these marketers need to remember is that technical SEO is one of the most important elements of any B2B SEO strategy. Technical SEO is not as time-consuming as other SEO tactics like content, link building, and on-page [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-overlooking-technical-elements-in-your-seo-strategy/">Are You Overlooking Technical Elements in Your SEO Strategy?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.impactbnd.com/blog/seo-statistics">61% of marketers say improving SEO and growing their organic presence is their top inbound marketing priority</a>.</p></blockquote>
<p>What these marketers need to remember is that technical SEO is one of the most important elements of any <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a> strategy. Technical SEO is not as time-consuming as other SEO tactics like content, link building, and on-page optimisation, however, it is just as, if not more, important.</p>
<p>If your technical SEO is not on-point, you run the risk of completely ruining the search performance of your site.</p>
<h2>Why is Technical SEO So Important?</h2>
<p>Technical Search Engine Optimisation (technical SEO) is the process of ensuring a website technically adheres to search engine guidelines. This is vital for any SEO strategy, as these technical elements ensure that a website can be properly indexed and ranked by search engines so that it appears on the Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs). Search engines will <a href="https://ignitevisibility.com/technical-seo/">rank websites higher in search results if their technical set up is good</a>.</p>
<p>The best time to set up your technical SEO is during the construction of the website. It involves optimising both the website and its server to help search engine spiders crawl and index the site, so it is a fundamental step in the setup of any site. It is also much easier to implement technical SEO from the start than it is to identify and fix any issues when the site is running. However, while you may set up technical SEO when you are setting up your website, it’s important to check back on it regularly. The technical elements you have in place may need to be updated as <a href="https://moz.com/google-algorithm-change">search engines update their algorithms</a>, your business changes, or consumer behaviour shifts.</p>
<h2>What are the Key Elements of Technical SEO?</h2>
<p>When search engines crawl a site, they are looking for a number of indications that the technical set up is good. Some of the most important things that you can do to set up your technical SEO properly are as follows.</p>
<h3>Set Up a Mobile-Friendly Site</h3>
<p><a href="https://searchengineland.com/report-nearly-60-percent-searches-now-mobile-devices-255025">Nearly 60% of searches today occur from mobile devices</a>. This shows that your users are mobile. If they come to your site from their mobile device and it doesn’t load properly, they’re likely to leave and find an alternative. Google has been aware of this for some time and has implemented a <a href="https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2018/03/rolling-out-mobile-first-indexing.html">‘mobile-first’ approach to indexing content</a>. This means that it’s not only important for the user experience that your site is mobile-friendly, it’s also essential for rankings.</p>
<p>In order to ensure your website is mobile-friendly, you can implement a <a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/01/guidelines-for-responsive-web-design/">‘responsive’ web design</a>. This is a type of web design that ensures the site adjusts itself automatically depending on the device that it is being viewed on so that it displays well and can be easily navigated.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7550" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site.jpg" alt="" width="815" height="376" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site.jpg 815w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site-450x208.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site-768x354.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 815px) 100vw, 815px" /></p>
<h3>Speed Up Your Site</h3>
<p>In an increasingly digital world, consumers want answers, and they want them fast. Search engines know this and have responded. Now, <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/page-speed">page speed is an important ranking signal for search engines</a>. There are a number of things that you can do to ensure your site is loading quickly, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use fast hosting and a quick DNS provider</li>
<li>Minimise the use of scripts and plugins on your site as much as possible</li>
<li>Try to use one CSS stylesheet rather than using multiple CSS stylesheets or inline CSS</li>
<li>Without compromising on quality, make image files on your site as small as possible</li>
<li>Compress your web pages</li>
<li>Minify the code on your site by removing any unnecessary spaces, line breaks or indentation in your HTML, CSS and Javascript</li>
</ul>
<h3>Check for Duplicate Content</h3>
<p>Search engines do not like duplicate content as it can be confusing for both users and search engine algorithms. In addition, duplicate content has previously been used as a ‘black hat’ SEO technique by marketers who are trying to manipulate search engine rankings.</p>
<p>What does this mean for your website? Any duplicate content issues should be identified and fixed as quickly as possible. There are a number of tools available that can help you to identify duplicate content issues. <a href="http://www.siteliner.com/">Siteliner</a> is one of our favourites. You can also minimise duplicate content issues by preventing your CMS from publishing multiple versions of a page or post and using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canonical_link_element">canonical link element</a> to show search engines where the ‘main’ version of your content sits.</p>
<h3>Create an XML Sitemap</h3>
<p>An XML sitemap is basically a digital roadmap that outlines exactly where each page sits on your site. Creating an XML sitemap is one of the best ways to assist a search engine in understanding your website while it is crawling it. The sitemap contains useful information about the pages on your site, such as when the page was last edited, how important the page is on your site in terms of priority and how often it is updated. Some website hosts will create your XML sitemap automatically. However, if yours doesn&#8217;t, there are a number of <a href="https://code.google.com/archive/p/sitemap-generators/wikis/SitemapGenerators.wiki">sitemap generator</a>s available to help you build one.</p>
<p>Some other important things that you can do to improve the technical SEO on your site are using SSL, enabling AMP, adding structured data mark up to your website, and registering your site with Google Search Console and Bing Webmaster Tools.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a specialist <a href="/">B2B Marketing</a> Agency with significant experience in developing and implementing campaigns across industries. We’ve worked on a number of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a> campaigns. Get in touch with us for more information on how we can help boost your website’s ranking on the SERPs.</p>
<p>Want to proactively plan for future success? Start developing your business&#8217; strategy for next year with our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-overlooking-technical-elements-in-your-seo-strategy/">Are You Overlooking Technical Elements in Your SEO Strategy?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Identify and Remove Bottlenecks in Your Marketing Funnel</title>
		<link>/how-to-identify-and-remove-bottlenecks-in-your-marketing-funnel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to B2B selling, the purchasing process can be both long and complex. Prospects are likely to engage in extensive research, carefully evaluating their options prior to making a buying decision. If your current B2B sales strategy doesn’t take this into account, you may be losing valuable leads that become ‘stuck’ in funnel [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-identify-and-remove-bottlenecks-in-your-marketing-funnel/">How to Identify and Remove Bottlenecks in Your Marketing Funnel</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to B2B selling, the purchasing process can be both long and complex. Prospects are likely to engage in extensive research, carefully evaluating their options prior to making a buying decision. If your current B2B sales strategy doesn’t take this into account, you may be losing valuable leads that become ‘stuck’ in funnel bottlenecks. Luckily, depending on your unique requirements, there are various tactics you can implement to improve sales processes and boost conversions.</p>
<p><a href="https://sherpablog.marketingsherpa.com/b2b-marketing/b2b-marketing-sales-funnel-missing/">68% of organisations</a> are yet to clearly define their sales funnel, missing out on the significant benefits that could otherwise be achieved. By creating a systematic, thoughtful sales funnel that targets bottlenecks you have the opportunity to distinguish your business from competitors and offer real value to potential customers.</p>
<p>Before looking for funnel bottlenecks, it’s important to establish a sound understanding of the different buyer journeys your potential customers are following. By developing a thorough comprehension of your distinct sales funnel, you’ll be well equipped to accurately identify any pain points.</p>
<h2>Understanding Your Sales Funnel</h2>
<p>Your sales funnel represents the unique buying process prospects follow when interacting with your brand. It looks at how exactly a potential customer’s initial interest is transformed into a valuable conversion and meaningful, ongoing relationship.</p>
<p>A typical B2B sales funnel involves <a href="https://medium.com/@B2BSalesPreach/tips-for-optimizing-and-improving-your-b2b-sales-funnel-8583b472ba99">three key stages</a>, which are as follows:</p>
<p><img class="alignright wp-image-7069" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/funnel-450x386.png" alt="" width="320" height="252" /></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Top-Of-Funnel:</strong> lead generation</li>
<li><strong>Middle-Of-Funnel:</strong> lead nurturing</li>
<li><strong>Bottom-Of-Funnel:</strong> customer acquisition and retention</li>
</ol>
<p>By establishing a clear, precise sales funnel you can ensure that the unique needs of your leads are being adequately satisfied at each point of the buyer journey. Without a well-defined purchasing process, you’ll likely experience great difficulty when trying to remove bottlenecks.</p>
<p>Once having determined the core stages of your sales funnel, it is crucial that you work proactively to discover and address any funnel bottlenecks that may disengage prospects.</p>
<h2>Identifying Common Funnel Bottlenecks</h2>
<p>So, where exactly in your sales funnel are potential customers stalling? To effectively pinpoint any bottlenecks, this is what you need to establish.</p>
<p>While there may be certain bottlenecks that are specific to your organisation’s unique context, often, other companies will be experiencing similar issues. Because of this, analysing your competitors could provide some valuable insights into what other businesses in your industry are trying to combat. This is a great starting point, but it’s also essential to delve deeper into your own company processes and identify where consumers are getting stuck.</p>
<p>Here are some common funnel bottlenecks you can look out for as well as practical, actionable tactics you can employ to overcome them.</p>
<h4>1. You’re Attracting Very Few Prospects (TOFU)</h4>
<p>If your business is receiving only a small number of enquiries, or none at all, then it’s likely potential consumers haven’t moved past the top of your sales funnel.</p>
<p>What does this mean for your organisation? You need to build greater interest in your brand and offering, boosting awareness among members of your target audience.</p>
<p>Finding the source of this bottleneck is crucial, you’ll need to ask yourself:</p>
<ul>
<li>Are you targeting the right audience?</li>
<li>Do you have a strong <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/business-value-proposition/">B2B value proposition</a> that differentiates your brand from competitors and is clearly communicated with prospects?</li>
<li>Does the <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content</a> you’re sharing with potential customers offer them real value?</li>
<li>Is your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> consistent and engaging?</li>
<li>Are you reaching your target audience directly and in a relevant, memorable way?</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you’ve determined why prospects aren’t converting into leads, you can start developing a strategy that addresses these funnel bottlenecks. This may involve researching and refining your customer persona, brainstorming innovative ways to further distinguish your brand from competitors, creating new exciting content or, potentially, rebranding.</p>
<h4>2. Your Leads Aren’t Converting (MOFU)</h4>
<p>Do you have a high number of leads, but they aren’t converting into customers? In such cases, it’s important to focus on improving the middle of your funnel through lead nurturing.</p>
<p>At this point of the sales funnel, understanding your target audience and capturing their ongoing interest is crucial. Investing in great content such as case studies, informative videos and blog posts can help your business offer prospects continued value. By creating such resources, you have the opportunity to demonstrate your expertise, build credibility and keep leads engaged. You’re able to maintain relevance, staying in contact with potential customers in a meaningful way.</p>
<p>Lead scoring can also be particularly useful at this stage of the sales funnel. By scoring your leads, you can determine the level of interest different prospects have in your brand and the content you’re sharing. This means that you can identify your most promising leads and target them directly, encouraging them to convert. For instance, after noticing that a prospect is especially engaged, sending them a personal message with an exclusive offer may be all it takes for them to take action.</p>
<h4>3. You’re Experiencing Difficulty Retaining Customers (BOFU)</h4>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7584" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/leads.jpg" alt="lead generation" width="850" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/leads.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/leads-450x159.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/leads-768x271.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>You’re acquiring new customers but, for some reason, they’re not sticking around. If this is the case, consumers are getting stuck at the bottom of your sales funnel.</p>
<p>But what does this actually mean for your business? You’ve likely dedicated time, resources and money into converting prospects so it’s crucial that, once they’ve made their first purchase, you don’t stop offering them value.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/solve-customer-retention-problem/"><em>53% of customers</em></a><em> have switched companies because they felt unappreciated.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Often, it’s cheaper and easier to sell to an existing customer than a new lead. If you want to do this, however, your business needs to give them a reason to stay. Luckily, there are numerous marketing strategies you can apply to overcome bottlenecks at the bottom of your funnel. These include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creating customer loyalty programs that encourage and reward repeat purchase;</li>
<li>Sending a thank you email after a customer makes a purchase;</li>
<li>Giving your customers the opportunity to share any feedback from their buying experience;</li>
<li>Sending customers exclusive offers for special events, such as their birthday;</li>
<li>Providing readily accessible, reliable and proactive customer service;</li>
<li>Acknowledging any issues your consumers encounter and acting promptly to offer them an appropriate solution.</li>
</ul>
<p>By successfully addressing any bottlenecks at the bottom of your sales funnel you can improve the customer experience and boost retention. This can, in turn, help your business upsell, cross-sell and gain a greater number of referrals from satisfied customers.</p>
<p>Want to find out more about removing funnel bottlenecks? Get in touch with our <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> specialists at the Lead Agency today. We can get your business up-to-date on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, so you can proactively plan for future success.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-identify-and-remove-bottlenecks-in-your-marketing-funnel/">How to Identify and Remove Bottlenecks in Your Marketing Funnel</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Comprehensive Guide to B2B Remarketing</title>
		<link>/a-comprehensive-guide-to-b2b-remarketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 03:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Remarketing has been proven to increase conversions, improve brand recall, and reduce lost prospects. If you’re not currently using it as part of your digital marketing strategy, it’s time to start considering it. It takes 6 to 8 touches to generate a viable sales lead Prospects are unlikely to convert the first time that they [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-comprehensive-guide-to-b2b-remarketing/">A Comprehensive Guide to B2B Remarketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Remarketing has been proven to <a href="https://mailchimp.com/features/google-remarketing-ads/">increase conversions</a>, <a href="https://www.ironpaper.com/webintel/articles/benefits-of-remarketing/">improve brand recall</a>, and reduce lost prospects. If you’re not currently using it as part of your digital marketing strategy, it’s time to start considering it.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.salesforce.com/blog/2015/04/takes-6-8-touches-generate-viable-sales-lead-heres-why-gp.html">It takes 6 to 8 touches to generate a viable sales lead</a></p></blockquote>
<p>Prospects are unlikely to convert the first time that they come to your business’ website. Remarketing gives you a second, third, or even fourth chance to make a sale or capture a lead.</p>
<p>The premise behind remarketing is that it targets users who have already interacted with your business online. As such, these prospects are already aware of your company and the products and services that it provides. Bringing them back to your website moves them further through their buyer journey to conversion.</p>
<p><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/remarketing-for-b2b/">Remarketing</a> is particularly effective for B2B businesses due to the longer sales cycle and complex buyer journey.</p>
<h2>What is Remarketing?</h2>
<p>Using technology such as marketing tags and tracking pixels, remarketing delivers highly personalized ads to people who have already been on a website but have not converted.</p>
<p>Remarketing is a great method for building brand recognition, by keeping your business in front of your prospects long after they have left your site. If your creative is compelling enough, your remarketing campaign will also generate clicks back to your site when the customer is further through their buying journey and more likely to convert.</p>
<h2>Why are Remarketing Campaigns Important?</h2>
<p>As digital marketers, we focus a lot of our efforts on generating traffic to our website through a number of different online channels such as Social Media, Search Engine Marketing and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO</a>. However, 96% of the visitors that come to a website are not ready to buy. If you don’t capture their email address or any other piece of contact information, following up with that 96% is almost impossible. That means that you are missing out on opportunities to turn your prospects into leads.</p>
<p>This is where remarketing comes in. Remarketing gives digital marketers the ability to target these visitors with specific ads that convince them to come back to your website and find out more, without them having to part with their contact information.</p>
<p>Remarketing ads are particularly effective because they are targeting people who have <em>already shown an interest</em><em> </em>in your business offering. As such, conversion rates are proven to increase as more online users see remarketing advertising campaigns.<strong> </strong></p>
<h2>Are There Different Types of Remarketing?</h2>
<p>There are a number of different strategies and channels that you can use to implement a remarketing campaign, from search engines to social media and email. The right channel for you will depend on your audience and the specific objectives that you have for your campaign. The following overview may help you work out which could be the most relevant for your business.</p>
<h3>Standard Remarketing<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>This is the most common form of remarketing, where display ads are shown to website visitors as they browse online. Most advertisers use Google Display Network for this type of remarketing. With over <a href="https://school4seo.com/google-display-exam/how-many-websites-are-part-of-the-google-display-network/">2 million sites and reaching over 90% of Internet users</a>, the Google Display Network is an extremely effective way to reach your audience. Ads are displayed on websites in the Google Display Network, acting as a passive reminder of your business while the user browses online.</p>
<p>Another option for this type of remarketing is to use a Social Media platform like Facebook. Facebook remarketing gives advertisers the opportunity to reconnect with website visitors when they are using Facebook. This is done by installing a pixel on the website that sends information back to Facebook. As long as the user is signed in to their Facebook account while they are browsing online, the pixel will be able to track them.</p>
<h3>Dynamic Remarketing<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/3124536?hl=en-AU">Dynamic remarketing</a> is a hyper-targeted version of remarketing, where previous website visitors are shown ads related to the specific page that they viewed on a website. This type of remarketing includes personalised messaging and images for the visitor, which increases the ad’s relevancy and, as such the chances of the visitor returning to the website to find out more.</p>
<p>This type of remarketing is most often used by e-commerce websites, where they generate ads that include the exact product that a visitor put in their online shopping cart but did not buy. When the visitor sees the ad again, they remember their intentions to buy and are more likely to click through and purchase. This method can also be used in B2B, for someone who has read a particular blog or visited a certain section on your site. Remarketing ads for this audience can link to other informational materials on the same topic, or to a landing page with a downloadable resource or sign up form for an informational webinar.</p>
<h3>Remarketing Lists for Search Ads</h3>
<p>Also abbreviated to RLSAs, remarketing lists for search ads is a feature offered by Google Ads that allows advertisers to customise search advertising campaigns for visitors who have previously visited their website. With this feature, you can adjust bids, ad copy and ad extensions so that you can specifically target previous visitors. Your ads will then show to visitors after they leave your site if they search again on Google for keywords and phrases that you specify.</p>
<p>To get the most out of this feature, consider increasing bids for existing keywords for the visitors on the remarketing lists. If they are searching again for your products or services, they are more likely to be closer to purchase and as such, may be worth a higher bid. Alternatively, you can add more keywords for visitors who have been on the website, or have previously purchased something. Going a bit broader on keywords for this audience can also be an effective strategy in re-engaging them as they are already aware of your brand and as such, are more likely to come back with their new search queries.</p>
<h3>Video Remarketing</h3>
<p>As its name suggests, video remarketing involves using video ads to remarket to people who have previously been on your website. You can also set up video remarketing for people who have watched a video on your YouTube channel. These ads can be shown at the beginning or in-between the videos that your audience are looking at on YouTube. Alternatively, you can show your remarketing ad on the YouTube homepage where users see video suggestions.</p>
<h3>Email Remarketing<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>There are two different techniques for email remarketing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Showing display remarketing ads on different websites to users who have opened an email from you. In order to do this, you can use a retargeting agency called <a href="https://app.adroll.com/">AdRoll</a>. AdRoll gives digital advertisers the ability to reach out to users who opened an email from their business and clicked on a link but didn’t complete the purchase.</li>
<li>Following up on visitors who have left your website without purchasing with targeted emails that aim to convince them to come back to your site. This is most effective if you show the user the exact product that they were looking at in the email that you send.</li>
</ol>
<p>Whichever type of email remarketing you choose to run, make sure you segment the audience properly so that you can send extremely targeted, relevant ads. The more personalised an ad, the more likely it is to convince a visitor to come back to your website and buy.<strong> </strong></p>
<h2>Remarketing Best Practices</h2>
<p>In order to get the best performance out of your remarketing campaign, the following best practices can help.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reduce List Membership Duration: </strong>The default list membership on Google Ads is 540 days. Google offers this option to advertisers so that they can have flexibility in the ways to use their lists in future. But, the reality is that it probably won’t be beneficial for your business to send communications to users 540 days after they have been on your site. Choose a more relevant time frame depending on your business sales cycles and the services you offer.</li>
<li><strong>Implement a Frequency Cap: </strong>This is an extremely important thing to do with any remarketing (or display) campaign. You don’t want to show your audience your ads so much that they get annoyed. Set a limit that will serve as a reminder for the audience, without being in their face too much.</li>
<li><strong>Only Remarket to “Quality” Visitors: </strong>With a bit of technical know-how, you can narrow down your remarketing lists so that they only target users who have had a quality interaction with your site. In order to refine your list to quality visitors, exclude people who have bounced and people who have spent less than twenty seconds on your site. This can be done in Google Analytics.</li>
<li><strong>Don’t Show your Ads on Low-Quality Content:</strong> There are some content types that you may not want to show your image ads on. These can be excluded by specifically naming the sites that you don’t want your ads to appear on or by listing the site categories to avoid. It is also advisable to exclude error pages, parked domains and forums as placements, as they typically contain low quality content that you don’t want to associate with your brand.</li>
<li><strong>Ad Creative:</strong> Your image ads should look similar to your website design and always include your logo so that the user can see that they are from a website that they have already interacted with.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/remarketing-for-b2b/">B2B remarketing</a> get in touch with the <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing specialists</a> at The Lead Agency.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/a-comprehensive-guide-to-b2b-remarketing/">A Comprehensive Guide to B2B Remarketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Optimise Your B2B Local SEO Strategy</title>
		<link>/how-to-optimise-your-b2b-local-seo-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 23:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Local Search Engine Optimisation, or local SEO, is a type of SEO that focuses on optimising a website so that it is found in local search results. As 46% of all searches on Google are seeking local information, local search is a vital component of any comprehensive Search Engine Optimisation campaign. The premise behind is the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-b2b-local-seo-strategy/">How to Optimise Your B2B Local SEO Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Local Search Engine Optimisation, or <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/local-seo/">local SEO</a>, is a type of SEO that focuses on optimising a website so that it is found in local search results. As <a href="https://seoexpertbrad.com/local-seo-stats/">46% of all searches </a>on Google are seeking local information, local search is a vital component of any comprehensive Search Engine Optimisation campaign.</p>
<p>The premise behind is the same as regular SEO. As such, optimising a page for local SEO involves the same elements as a regular SEO campaign; content, on-page optimisation, and link building, but with a focus on localised intent.</p>
<p>The big search engines, Google and Bing are continuously working to update their algorithms to ensure they are delivering the most relevant results to match the user’s search intent. In many cases, the most relevant results are local. In fact, a recent Hubspot study found that <u>46% of all Google searches are local</u>, which indicates that almost half of the time, users are looking for a local solution. As such, it’s becoming more important to optimise your website for local search.</p>
<p>Many B2B companies are put off by the term ‘local SEO’ as they often operate across the country or have branches in multiple cities. However, local SEO can optimise all the locations that your business has to attract leads and customers in that location.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://seoexpertbrad.com/local-seo-stats/">92% of searchers</a> will pick businesses on the first page of local search results</p></blockquote>
<p>Ensuring your strategy is right, or at least better than your competitors’ strategy, is essential to your success on the SERPs.</p>
<p>The first step to a winning <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/local-seo/">B2B local SEO</a> campaign is simple, and costs nothing: set up a Google My Business Account.</p>
<h2>Google My Business for Local SEO<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>Despite the <a href="https://www.chatmeter.com/blog/growth-of-near-me-searches-shows-importance-of-local-seo/">massive increase in local search</a>, particularly on Google, 56% of local retailers haven’t yet claimed their Google My Business listing.</p>
<p>Claiming and optimising your Google My Business listing is the foundation of local SEO. If you are one of the 56% of businesses that haven’t claimed their listing, you’re missing out on valuable opportunities for generating leads.</p>
<h3>What is Google My Business?</h3>
<p>Google My Business is an online directory listing that connects your business directly with customers across Google, whether they’re looking for you on Search, Maps or Google+. The below screenshot shows an example of how your business may appear on the search results page with a Google My Business listing.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM.png" alt="" width="1914" height="1126" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM.png 1914w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM-450x265.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM-768x452.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM-1024x602.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1914px) 100vw, 1914px" /></p>
<h3>Why Use Google My Business?</h3>
<p>With a Google My Business account, your customers can find your company immediately, anywhere, on any device, and it doesn’t cost you a cent.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Be Found On Google:</strong> With such a prominent position in the search results, your business can’t afford not to set up Google My Business. If your business has multiple stores or locations, you can make use of the ‘Multiple Service Areas’ functionality, which means upon searching, your customer can find your closest location to them. This is particularly effective for mobile searchers.</li>
<li><strong>Showcase Your Business:</strong> Google My Business offers a fantastic opportunity for showcasing your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">brand personality and values</a>. Customise your profile with a value proposition, photos, virtual tours, videos and other media to create a real point of difference from your competitors.</li>
<li><strong>Make the Most of Social Proof:</strong> Customers can review your products or services on Google My Business by giving a star rating scale and leaving a comment. Positive reviews can help your business build trust and credibility in your brand.</li>
</ul>
<p>Don’t miss out on this free marketing opportunity, claim your <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en_au/business/">Google My Business</a> listing today – and stay ahead of the 44% of your peers who still don’t have one.</p>
<h2>Other Vital Elements of Local SEO</h2>
<p>While creating a Google My Business account is an excellent starting point for a local SEO strategy, there are many more things that you can do to ensure your website is fully optimised for local search.</p>
<p>As mentioned above, local SEO isn’t hugely different from organic SEO, it still centres around keywords, content, links, on-page SEO and reviews. However, when you are optimising for local search, these strategies should have more of a local focus to ensure your business is found when people are performing these searches in the area surrounding your business. It is vital to get these elements right in order to outrank your local competitors in the SERPs.</p>
<h3>Local SEO Keyword Research<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Keyword research for local SEO is not much different from traditional <a href="https://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo/keyword-research">keyword research</a>. However, <a href="https://searchengineland.com/local-search-mobile-268208">local searches are most often performed on a mobile device</a>, such as a smartphone, Amazon Echo, or Google Home, which have voice search capabilities. <a href="/is-your-seo-strategy-ready-for-voice-search/">Voice search is shaping SEO</a> going forward and it has been predicted that by 2020 <a href="https://www.campaignlive.co.uk/article/just-say-it-future-search-voice-personal-digital-assistants/1392459">50% of all searches will be voice searches</a>. Ensuring your website is optimised for voice search is one of the ways to boost your local SEO.</p>
<p>This means, trying to optimise for conversational voice search terms like “find a financial advisor near me”. Most voice searches will be more question-focused, so when you are conducting keyword research, try to look for these terms. In addition to the Google Keyword Planner, SEMrush’s topic research tool, Keyword.io, and AnswerThePublic are great for identifying the questions people are searching for, and their search volume. Given the increase in this type of search, you should be able to find some questions that are relevant to your business, with a reasonably high search volume.</p>
<h3>Content for Local SEO <strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Locally focused content is extremely important for a local SEO strategy. As with any content that you publish, showing a depth of knowledge on the topics that you cover is essential. However, while traditional SEO best practice is to <a href="https://www.sweor.com/seocontentlength">write long-form content</a>, this won’t necessarily get results for local SEO. Local SEO is more about matching your content to the user intent behind the query, rather than getting a high word count for the query. This means applying the keyword research that you have done to find out exactly what your local customers are searching for, and then writing content around these terms that addresses and answers their queries effectively.</p>
<p>Another tip for optimising your content for local is to ensure your headlines and metadata focus on local keywords and phrases. The snippet of your web page that Google shows in the search results should let Google, and the searcher, recognise your business as a local provider.</p>
<h3>Links for Local SEO<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Firstly, it’s important to follow <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35769?hl=en">Google’s Webmaster Guidelines</a> when considering any linking strategy, as you don’t want your link acquisition efforts to result in a penalty from Google. Any links that violate Google’s guidelines will be detected eventually, which will significantly affect your search rankings.</p>
<p>Once you know what Google likes and doesn’t like in terms of linking, you can start to define your local linking strategy. For local SEO, linking is slightly different than for organic SEO. There are various link categories that make up a quality local SEO strategy, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Citation / NAP Sites:</strong> NAP stands for Name, Address and Phone number. These details are critical for businesses that want to rank in local search results, as search engines like Google take this data into account when determining which companies to show for geo-targeted searches. There are certain citation sites where you can submit your URL and NAP details to in order to increase local search presence.</li>
<li><strong>Local Directory Websites:</strong> Focus on adding your business to local directory sites to increase relevant links to your page and give your business more chance of appearing on local search results.</li>
<li><strong>Industry-Related Local Sites:</strong> Consider other local sites that might have link opportunities, such as newspapers, schools, universities and government associations. These sites can help significantly increase the value of your local link profile.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Content for Local SEO</h3>
<p>For local SEO, it’s best practice to create a webpage for each relevant town, county, or region. By focusing a page specifically on each area that you serve, you can really boost your local search optimisation. Ensure each page speaks to the unique characteristics of the location while keeping it relevant to your business. It can also be useful to add case studies of businesses that you’ve worked within the local area to add credibility and demonstrate how your business has contributed to the community.</p>
<h3>Reviews for Local SEO</h3>
<p><a href="https://moz.com/blog/2018-local-search-ranking-factors-survey">The 2018 Local Search Ranking Factors report by Moz</a> identified online reviews as one of the top 3 most important ranking factors in local search. In fact, having review stars in Google’s search engine results pages <a href="http://localclienttakeover.com/review-stars-serps/">can improve your click-through rate by up to 35%</a>. Customers trust and value online reviews, and treat them as they would a word of mouth recommendation from a friend or family member. They want to see recent reviews of your business that are long enough to provide specific details about the products or services that they received. As such, businesses should try to encourage their satisfied customers to leave detailed reviews on platforms that are relevant to them.</p>
<p>Google is the most important source of reviews for local SEO, which can be set up through Google My Business. In addition, depending on the industry you operate in, you may also want to consider generating reviews on Citysearch, Tripadvisor, Foursquare, Facebook, Yahoo Local or Yelp.</p>
<p>The <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">marketing consultants</a> at the Lead Agency have considerable experience in developing <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/local-seo/">Local SEO campaigns</a> that generate more leads and better quality leads for our clients. Get in touch with us to find out how we can help your business today.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget to check out the other industries that we operate in; <a href="/education-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<div class="blog-share text-center"></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-b2b-local-seo-strategy/">How to Optimise Your B2B Local SEO Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>B2B Email Marketing Best Practices for 2019</title>
		<link>/b2b-email-marketing-best-practices-for-2019/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“For every $1 spent, $44.25 is the average return on email marketing investment.” &#8211;  Experian Over 87% of B2B marketers are using email. Why? Because it works. A 2018 Content Marketing Institute survey revealed that 79% of B2B marketers credited email as the most effective distribution channel for their demand generation efforts. For B2B companies, it is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-email-marketing-best-practices-for-2019/">B2B Email Marketing Best Practices for 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“For every $1 spent, $44.25 is the average return on email marketing investment.” &#8211;  <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/67734-three-key-charts-from-our-2016-email-marketing-census/">Experian</a></p>
<p>Over 87% of B2B marketers are using email. Why? Because it works. A 2018 Content Marketing Institute survey revealed that 79% of B2B marketers credited email as the most effective distribution channel for their demand generation efforts.</p>
<p>For B2B companies, it is extremely important to communicate regularly with current and prospective clients. <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> is a great way of doing this by sharing valuable content with your audience. No other communications channel speaks directly between a brand and a consumer like email does, so with the right B2B email marketing strategy in place, you can increase engagement, leads, conversions, and ultimately profit.</p>
<p>However, with so many B2B companies now embarking on an email marketing strategy, it’s more important than ever to stand out amongst all the other emails that are flooding into the inboxes of your prospects and clients. One of the best ways to do this is to ensure your business is adapting with your client’s changing expectations as a result of innovations in technology. Email marketing has gotten more sophisticated over the past few decades, and your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">email marketing strategy</a> should follow suit.</p>
<p>The following are some of the key things that you can do with your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> strategy to ensure your campaign succeeds in engaging your audience and moving them through the stages of the buying funnel to sale.</p>
<h2><strong>Define Appropriate Goals and Objectives</strong></h2>
<p>Before you start your B2B email marketing campaign it is important to define measurable goals and objectives, which should align with your overall company objectives. Ensure that these objectives are specific and measurable. For example, don&#8217;t define your email marketing goal as ‘generating sales’. This is too broad and will be difficult to analyse how successful the campaign has been for your company. Instead, set a goal like ‘generate 20% more leads and 30% more phone contacts within six weeks’. As this is more specific, it is more measurable and easier to compare your performance with your expected results.</p>
<p>In order to ensure that your email campaign is meeting the set goals and objectives, it is vital that you have processes in place to be able to measure them. As well as being able to monitor open rate, click through rate and unsubscribes from your email provider, it is extremely useful to ensure Google Analytics is set up with conversion goals so that you can track how your email recipients interact with your site after they’ve clicked your email. This will give your business valuable insight into whether or not your email campaign is useful for generating leads, conversions and ROI – and how it compares to other digital channels.</p>
<h2><strong>Use Email to Move Prospects Through the Funnel</strong></h2>
<p>Your B2B email marketing strategy should be considered in the same way as your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content marketing</a> strategy. When you are creating your campaigns, it’s important to remember that not everyone who subscribes to your email list is at the bottom of the sales funnel and ready to buy.</p>
<p>It’s important to create email content that speaks to the subscribers in the middle or even towards the top of the funnel with valuable information that addresses their motivations and overcomes their objections to move them through to sale. This can be done by demonstrating <a href="https://marketinginsidergroup.com/content-marketing/what-is-thought-leadership-and-when-you-should-use-it/">thought leadership</a>. By using your emails and the content within them to convince people that you’re an expert in your niche, they’re more likely to choose your business’ products or services when they decide to act.</p>
<p>Another way to build customer trust in your brand and as such, move them through the buying funnel, is to include an endorsement in your email. This is particularly useful if the endorsement is from someone who is recognised by your audience.</p>
<h2><strong>Use Email to Cross-Sell Services</strong></h2>
<p>Email marketing is a powerful tool for cross-selling your services. Online retail giant <a href="http://rejoiner.com/resources/amazon-recommendations-secret-selling-online/">Amazon uses email marketing to achieve up-selling and cross-selling conversions of more than 60%</a>. While Amazon may not be a B2B company, the stats speak for themselves and cross-selling through email is just as effective for B2B companies. The best way to start cross-selling to your lists is to segment your users into groups of people who currently use only one of your products or services. You can then create a series of emails promoting your other services that they are not using, but that compliment the ones that they are.</p>
<h2><strong>Segment Your List Based on User Engagement </strong></h2>
<p>Personalised emails deliver 6X higher transaction rates, yet 70% of brands fail to use them. Personalisation is the key to effectively segmenting your B2B email marketing campaign. If you’re not segmenting your list, you’re missing opportunities for leads and conversions.</p>
<p>An effective way to start with segmenting your list is based on how interested people are in your brand. Your lists could range from prospects, to warm leads, customers and loyal customers. The content in your email would then be targeted to each segment. For example, you could showcase your business and how it can add value to non-customers who have subscribed to your email list to lead them further down the sales funnel. Your best customers, on the other hand, could receive an email campaign running a promotion that offers them a loyalty discount or other incentive for referrals in order to turn them into brand advocates.</p>
<h2><strong>Choose the Right Time to Send</strong></h2>
<p>Without proper timing, your email campaign may miss out on valuable opportunities, and its messages will resonate less with recipients. That’s why it’s vital to find the right time to send out your email communications to your audience.</p>
<p>There’s no set rule as to what to the perfect time to send your campaign will be, as this will depend on the characteristics and behaviours of your target market. According to <a href="https://coschedule.com/blog/best-time-to-send-email/">a number of email studies</a>, open rates and click through rates are highest on a Tuesday and the best time to send emails is around 10 am or 11 am. While this is very useful information, it’s important to do your own research as your business may not fit into that pattern. <a href="https://ignitevisibility.com/sp_faq/what-is-split-testing/"> Split testing</a> can help you determine the most effective day of the week and hour of the day for your campaigns.</p>
<p>Another consideration that will affect the best time for your business to <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/email-marketing/email-communications-strategy/timing-matter-email-marketing/">send emails is the frequency in which you send them</a>. If you send a lot of emails, you’re likely to see a lower click through rate across the campaign, regardless of the time and day you send them.</p>
<h2><strong>Keep Your Content Concise</strong></h2>
<p>If you’re seeing high open rates but low click through rates in your email, it’s likely because there is too much information in them. People get hundreds of emails a day and often read them on the go. As such, it’s important to ensure your message is short and to the point.</p>
<p>In order to ensure your email is concise, ask yourself what action you want the reader to take and ensure you only include information in the email that encourages the reader to take that action.</p>
<p>Once you’ve identified exactly what you want to say, ensure your email is presented in a way that is easy for the reader to consume. If they glance at the email and see a lot of text, they are likely to delete before they even read it. As such, email content should be concise, with the most important information at the top. Text should be scannable and written in short sentences and paragraphs, making use of bullet-pointed lists where appropriate.</p>
<p>The following are the three components every email should have:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Image: </strong>Choose an image that is related to the topic of your email</li>
<li><strong>Headline: </strong>Make sure your headline grabs the reader’s attention</li>
<li><strong>CTA: </strong>Make sure your call to action is clear and stands out</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Use Your Name in the Email </strong></h2>
<p>B2B purchases are often based on the relationship that one company has with another. With any email campaign, it’s important to ensure it is personal. An email should never be sent from a generic email address like noreply@B2Bbusiness.com.au.</p>
<p>These emails are not only more likely to end up in the recipient’s spam folder but even if they make it into the inbox, they probably won’t get a high open rate. This is because the “from” address is one of the first things that someone sees when they look at their inbox so it’s important that they see a real person’s name. Even if you are in a big company, this can add a human face to the business.</p>
<h2><strong>Ensure Your Email Design is Mobile Responsive</strong></h2>
<p><a href="https://www.emailmonday.com/mobile-email-usage-statistics/">Emails are now opened more on mobile than desktop</a>, and if your email doesn&#8217;t display correctly on a mobile device, it <a href="https://www.adestra.com/resources/2016-consumer-adoption-usage-study/">may be deleted within three seconds</a>. This means that ensuring your newsletter displays well on mobile devices is just as important, if not more important, as ensuring it can be read in traditional email providers like Outlook and Gmail. If your email does not display well on mobile, you risk alienating the majority of your audience and as such, can expect significantly lower click through rates.</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a>, get in touch with our <a href="/marketing-consultant-melbourne/">Melbourne Marketing Consultants</a> today. Our specialists have significant experience in running a full range of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> campaigns.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/b2b-email-marketing-best-practices-for-2019/">B2B Email Marketing Best Practices for 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
