<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>IT Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/it-marketing-blogs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 07:14:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>IT Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Improve Your IT Marketing Strategy with These 3 Tactics</title>
		<link>/improve-your-it-marketing-strategy-with-these-3-tactics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 23:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2019, the information technology sector is expected to reach $5 trillion globally. As the industry continues its’ rapid expansion, those who fail to adapt accordingly will likely be left behind in the rush. Competition is high, so if you don’t adequately satisfy the needs and preferences of consumers, your company’s ongoing viability may be [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/improve-your-it-marketing-strategy-with-these-3-tactics/">Improve Your IT Marketing Strategy with These 3 Tactics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2019, the information technology sector is expected to reach <a href="https://www.comptia.org/resources/it-industry-trends-analysis">$5 trillion globally</a>. As the industry continues its’ rapid expansion, those who fail to adapt accordingly will likely be left behind in the rush. Competition is high, so if you don’t adequately satisfy the needs and preferences of consumers, your company’s ongoing viability may be threatened.</p>
<p>What makes you different from those with similar offerings? How are you going to make sure consumers are not only aware of who you are, but also maintain an ongoing interest in your business? If you want to reach your organisational goals and lead your company to success, these are just some of the many questions you’ll need to answer.</p>
<h2>The Difficulty With IT Marketing</h2>
<p>A strong, comprehensive <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing strategy</a> can help your business establish clear direction and create highly targeted initiatives.</p>
<p>IT services are typically commodities, so customers often find them <a href="https://www.digitalauthority.me/resources/it-marketing-guide/">difficult to distinguish between</a>. When searching for an IT company online, prospects are bombarded with a vast array of services that they perceive to be relatively similar. Even if there are certain intricacies that set your offering apart of the rest, there’s no guarantee that consumers will understand the technicalities of your service. If prospects can’t comprehend your unique selling points, they’ll likely struggle to differentiate your offering from the next.</p>
<p>This is where effective marketing is vital, playing an integral role in your ability to overcome the distinctive challenges of the IT sector. With marketing, you can strategically position your brand in an ever-competitive business landscape, clearly communicating your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/business-value-proposition/">B2B value proposition</a>.</p>
<p>There are, of course, various marketing tactics that your company can focus on to start building an exceptional strategy. Not sure where to begin? Discover the benefits that come with a systematic, targeted <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing</a> approach by exploring the following.</p>
<h2>1. Conduct Market Research</h2>
<p>Understanding your target audience is crucial as, if you don’t, your marketing efforts may be completely misguided.</p>
<p>Researching and accurately defining buyer personas is a great starting point, helping you determine key groups of consumers who are likely to convert. Trying to reach everyone in the market is almost always going to be counterproductive.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Firms that conduct systematic research on their prospects and clients grow </em><a href="https://hingemarketing.com/blog/story/it-marketing-what-every-technology-services-firm-should-know-for-higher-gro"><em>three to ten times faster</em></a><em> – and are up to two times more profitable.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7522" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Market-Research.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Market-Research.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Market-Research-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Market-Research-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>So, you know who you’re trying to reach, you understand the type of marketing approach your target audience will respond to – what now? While it may be tempting, don’t fall into the trap of simply stopping there. The business landscape you’re operating in is constantly evolving and, thus, market research needs to be a continual process.</p>
<p>An out-dated <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a> is costly and ineffective, so regularly recording and analysing new, valuable insights should be a priority. Market research can aid in the discovery of exciting, innovative business opportunities that will boost performance, while also helping you identify current downfalls that require attention.</p>
<h2>2. Search Engine Optimisation</h2>
<p>Online domains that rank on the first page of Google enjoy <a href="https://www.theleverageway.com/blog/how-far-down-the-search-engine-results-page-will-most-people-go/">almost 95% of website traffic</a>. So, how can your IT company’s website become one of them?</p>
<p>Regardless of how extraordinary your website or offering is, if the right prospects aren’t aware of your brand’s existence, you’ll struggle to get the results you desire. This is where integrating a comprehensive <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">Search Engine Optimisation</a> strategy into your marketing has the potential to deliver tremendous results.</p>
<p>Search Engine Optimisation helps businesses boost their online visibility. There are various, systematic tactics that companies can employ to improve their ranking in Google’s search results, one of which is focusing on certain <a href="/keyword-research-how-to/">high-value keywords</a>. This involves incorporating highly relevant, well-ranking terms in unique, value-driven content, which is then shared on a business’s website.</p>
<p>Another important component of your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO strategy</a> is internal linking, which reinforces the connections between your content. When done right, internal linking provides Google with an enhanced perception of your website’s structure while also boosting your online authority. Main landing pages will typically have more incoming internal links, reflecting their significance on your website and encouraging Google to favour them over content that is deemed less valuable. For more information about internal linking and how it can be integrated into your marketing strategy, <a href="/internal-linking-how-to/">see our in-depth blog</a> on the topic.</p>
<h2>3. Build a Brilliant Website</h2>
<p>Relying on your product or service to sell itself isn’t always going to be enough. Your website is at the centre of your business, so it needs to accurately and clearly reflect your organisation’s image and level of expertise.</p>
<p>For many prospects, your online domains will form their initial impression of who you are and what you’ve got to offer. If potential customers are greeted by a website that’s difficult to navigate, out-dated and confusing they’ll likely look elsewhere.</p>
<p>Creating an impressive online hub that reinforces your credibility and <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branding</a> is crucial, especially when <a href="https://hingemarketing.com/blog/story/it-marketing-what-every-technology-services-firm-should-know-for-higher-gro">80% of buyers</a> turn to your website to find out more about your business.</p>
<p>When designing your organisation’s website, it’s important to take the following into account:</p>
<ul>
<li>Compatibility with mobile devices;</li>
<li>Usability and ease of navigation;</li>
<li>The value and relevance of the information being shared;</li>
<li>Search engine optimisation techniques;</li>
<li>Using an appealing design that enforces your branding;</li>
<li>Minimising the loading time of webpages;</li>
<li>Including calls to action;</li>
<li>Connecting your site with <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">social media</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, or to speak with an <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing</a> professional, get in touch with the Lead Agency today. We can get your IT business up-to-date on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, so you can proactively plan for future success.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/improve-your-it-marketing-strategy-with-these-3-tactics/">Improve Your IT Marketing Strategy with These 3 Tactics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Marketing Strategies to Help Your B2B Technology Business Make a Lasting Impact</title>
		<link>/3-marketing-strategies-to-help-your-b2b-technology-business-make-a-lasting-impact/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 22:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The technology sector is incredibly fast-paced, with new innovations and opportunities surfacing daily. This rapid progression is forecast to continue and, thus, it is vital that you are prepared to evolve as required. It’s no surprise that organisations that accurately define their target audience’s needs and are responsive to the shifting market will most probably [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-marketing-strategies-to-help-your-b2b-technology-business-make-a-lasting-impact/">3 Marketing Strategies to Help Your B2B Technology Business Make a Lasting Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The technology sector is incredibly fast-paced, with new innovations and opportunities surfacing daily. This rapid progression is forecast to continue and, thus, it is vital that you are prepared to evolve as required.</p>
<p>It’s no surprise that organisations that accurately define their target audience’s needs and are responsive to the shifting market will most probably be those who excel.</p>
<p>In a bid to remain relevant in an ever-changing business landscape, you’re likely working diligently to improve and advance your offering. But, while this is undeniably important, it’s also crucial to consider whether you are backing your marketing efforts with the same dedication.</p>
<p>The sales funnel is at the centre of a technology business’s success. If a company is unable to reach promising members of their target audience in meaningful ways, they will experience great difficulty when trying to achieve their organisational goals. <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/279643">More than 50%</a> of B2B technology start-ups experience ongoing difficulty when trying to generate more leads. If you can overcome this challenge, you have the opportunity to outperform competitors and take your business to new heights.</p>
<p>As a technology business, you need to engage your audience in new, exciting ways, differentiating your brand and leaving a memorable impact. A systematic, comprehensive <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a> can help you do just that.</p>
<p>Accomplish your goals, and maybe even surpass them, by giving these exceptional <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a> strategies a try today.</p>
<h2>1. Share Engaging Video Content</h2>
<p>Video <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">content</a> is becoming an increasingly prevalent component of many business marketing strategies &#8211; but why?</p>
<p>While reading an entire document may seem tiresome, often, watching a short video can appear far less daunting. This is because audio visual content requires little effort to view and is generally perceived as captivating or entertaining, which attracts a customer’s attention.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“73% of B2B marketers report positive ROI results from video content.” &#8211; </em><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/video-marketing-statistics"><em>HubSpot</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>Research suggests that <a href="https://synecticsmedia.com/7-powerful-benefits-of-video-content-marketing">74% of the users who watch explainer videos</a> go on to purchase the product they viewed. Thus, content of this form has the potential to generate exceptional results for your business when done right.</p>
<p>When incorporating video content in your marketing strategy, there is an abundance of variations you can decide between. This isn’t a one size fits all approach, so while you can gain inspiration from other companies, it’s crucial that you still convey your business’s <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branding</a> and core message clearly. At the end of the day, it’s all about delivering real value to prospects in an interesting, easily comprehendible way.</p>
<p>Not sure where to begin? Why not give one of the following a try:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing great stories that inspire;</li>
<li>Fun videos that convey your brand’s personality;</li>
<li>Informative, useful content;</li>
<li>Client testimonials;</li>
<li>Animated infographics and explainer videos.</li>
</ul>
<h2>2. Boost Your Credibility With Influencer Marketing</h2>
<p>If you advocate for your brand, assuring prospects you’ve created a phenomenal offering that they’ll love, what’s going to make them believe you?</p>
<p>When companies market a product, it’s highly unlikely they’ll make a point of highlighting its downfalls. Customers get this, so when organisations endorse their own product or service, they’ll often take what’s being said with a grain of salt. This is where influencer marketing comes into the picture.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://business.linkedin.com/content/dam/business/sales-solutions/global/en_US/c/pdfs/n/linkedin-the-new-formula-for-connecting-with-b2b-buyers.pdf"><em>72% of technology buyers</em></a><em> look to industry peers while researching relevant content for B2B purchase decisions.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>By effectively integrating influencer marketing techniques into their strategy, businesses can establish greater credibility, all the while generating more brand awareness. For this approach to reap exceptional results, however, it’s vital that you carefully consider which influencers your business works with.</p>
<p>When determining which influencer is right for your brand, you may benefit from asking yourself the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Is the individual respectable in your area of expertise?</li>
<li>Who makes up the individual’s target audience?</li>
<li>Does the individual have a strong, positive reputation?</li>
<li>Are you happy to be associated with their actions and beliefs?</li>
<li>How much are you willing to spend?</li>
<li>Where is the individual located and how expansive is their reach?</li>
</ul>
<h2>3. Incorporate Interactive Tools and Experiences</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7524" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Interactive-Tools-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" />Interacting with customers is a great way to boost engagement and build connections that are both personal and memorable. This can, in turn, assist your technology business in acquiring high-quality leads that are actually invested in your brand and what you’ve got to offer.</p>
<p>For instance, you may create a quiz on your website where consumers identify their particular needs and priorities. Then, once submitted, participants receive an evaluation of which of your offerings would likely be best suited to their needs. You’re giving prospects an individual experience that’s tailored to them, while also aiding them in the decision-making process.</p>
<p>In many cases, interactive content can be a valuable point of differentiation that encourages potential customers to consider a brand further, or even make a purchase.</p>
<p>Want to find out more about marketing in the technology sector? At the Lead Agency, we can get your business up-to-date on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, so you can proactively plan for future success. Take your <a href="/technology-marketing/">technology marketing</a> strategy to new heights by speaking with one of our <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> experts today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/3-marketing-strategies-to-help-your-b2b-technology-business-make-a-lasting-impact/">3 Marketing Strategies to Help Your B2B Technology Business Make a Lasting Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Stand Out in a Cluttered Market with IT Marketing</title>
		<link>/how-to-stand-out-in-a-cluttered-market-with-it-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 06:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IT Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Technology is continuing to develop, and as it is adopted by the masses, IT services businesses have significant opportunity to expand. In fact, technology companies lead all professional service industries in terms of revenue growth in FY 18-19. However, while this is presenting opportunities for these businesses, it’s also creating increasingly complex challenges for them. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-stand-out-in-a-cluttered-market-with-it-marketing/">How to Stand Out in a Cluttered Market with IT Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Technology is continuing to develop, and as it is adopted by the masses, IT services businesses have significant opportunity to expand. In fact, <a href="https://hingemarketing.com/blog/story/key-findings-from-the-2018-technology-high-growth-study">technology companies lead all professional service industries in terms of revenue growth in FY 18-19</a>.</p>
<p>However, while this is presenting opportunities for these businesses, it’s also creating increasingly complex challenges for them. As the market for IT services is growing, it’s becoming more competitive than ever before. To survive in today’s hyper-competitive market, companies in this sector need a comprehensive and effective <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing</a> strategy.</p>
<h2>The Challenges for IT Businesses</h2>
<p>The first step in creating a solid marketing strategy is to identify the business’ main challenges. The ‘<a href="https://hingemarketing.com/library/article/2018-high-growth-study-technology-services-edition-executive-summary">High Growth Study: Technology Services Addition</a>’ outlined the most common struggles for businesses in the IT sector today. According to surveyed IT services firms, the top five marketplace challenges were are follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>Attracting new business</li>
<li>Finding and retaining good employees</li>
<li>Staying innovative</li>
<li>The overly competitive marketplace</li>
<li>Meeting customer expectations</li>
</ol>
<h3>Increased Competition Impacting IT Service Firms</h3>
<p>The development of technical innovations such as automation and artificial intelligence is impacting technology businesses in two very different ways. On the one hand, these advancements help IT service companies develop new, exciting offerings for the market. However, on the other hand, these new, innovative programs are being developed quicker, better and cheaper than before, which reduces the barriers of entry for newcomers in the market. As such, the marketplace is becoming crowded with both established businesses and newcomers, which is not only increasing competition in the sector but pushing price down and making these services become more commoditised.</p>
<p>As IT service firms are seeing increased competition from both established businesses and newcomers to the market a solid marketing strategy can help your business stand out from all its competitors in the market, and give your customers a reason to choose you one of your competitors.</p>
<h2>Effective IT Marketing Strategies</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7556" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Effective-IT-Marketing-Strategies.png" alt="" width="850" height="260" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Effective-IT-Marketing-Strategies.png 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Effective-IT-Marketing-Strategies-450x138.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Effective-IT-Marketing-Strategies-768x235.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p>The following are some of the steps that your IT service business can take to create competitive advantage in a crowded market.</p>
<h3> 1. Create A Cutting Edge Website</h3>
<p>Despite operating in the technology space, many IT service firms are lagging behind with a website that has a poor user experience. This can be put down to the previous generations of IT service firms growing through business referrals and word of mouth, without the need for much marketing.</p>
<p>In today’s increasingly digital world, businesses can’t survive without a website. This is even more important for IT businesses, whose clients take their website design and experience as a direct indication of credibility. A staggering <strong>88% </strong>of online consumers are less likely to return to a site after a bad experience. This means that having a website is more than just about having a presence online. You also need to pay particular attention to your website design and usability to ensure visitors keep coming back.</p>
<h3> 2. Develop Thought Leadership</h3>
<p>Client education is critically important in the IT services industry, where products and services are complex. Creating a suite of educational content for your audience can help to build the profile of your brand and position it as a thought leader in the sector. By attributing this content to the employee who wrote it, you can also help to create personal brands for the individual experts within your business. Developing these employees and growing their brand can also benefit your business brand. When their reputation is established in the industry, they will likely be offered opportunities to represent your business by speaking at conferences, events or seminars. At these events, the employee has an excellent opportunity to attract both business and talent to your company. These authoritative employees are a particularly powerful asset for your business to have because their good reputation extends to the business as a whole, as well as to the other individuals within the business.</p>
<h3> 3. Create Compelling Content</h3>
<p>As mentioned above, educational content is critical in IT marketing. Your content is the foundation of building your business’ brand. It is also the basis of any campaign that you are running, from your website to email, social media and blog; so getting it right is essential. Your IT marketing content should educate target audiences and address their challenges. It should engage prospects at each stage of the buying funnel, addressing their motivations and objections at each stage to move them through their buyer journey to sale. This means that every piece of content coming from your brand is effectively building your entire company’s credibility and visibility, ultimately leading to new business, ROI and growth.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a specialist <a href="/">B2B marketing agency</a> offering a full-service approach to B2B marketing campaigns across industries. For more information on our <a href="/it-marketing/">IT marketing</a> services, don’t hesitate to get in touch. We can get your IT business up-to-date on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, so you can proactively plan for future success.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-stand-out-in-a-cluttered-market-with-it-marketing/">How to Stand Out in a Cluttered Market with IT Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
