<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Branding Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/b2b-branding-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:14:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Branding Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Keeping the Harmony: The Importance of Consistent B2B Branding</title>
		<link>/keeping-the-harmony-the-importance-of-consistent-b2b-branding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 06:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Your B2B brand is a key component of your business, encompassing and clearly communicating the core aspects that define your organisation’s personality, values and the like. If your B2B business fails to construct a recognisable and memorable brand, you’ll likely struggle to make a strong impact in your industry, making it all the more difficult [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/keeping-the-harmony-the-importance-of-consistent-b2b-branding/">Keeping the Harmony: The Importance of Consistent B2B Branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Your B2B brand is a key component of your business, encompassing and clearly communicating the core aspects that define your organisation’s personality, values and the like.</p>
<p>If your B2B business fails to construct a recognisable and memorable brand, you’ll likely struggle to make a strong impact in your industry, making it all the more difficult to establish your company as a market leader. Branding in of itself can deliver immense value to your organisation, inhibiting a vital role in representing why your offering is superior and; thus, why consumers ought to view it as their preferred choice.</p>
<p>However, when it comes to branding, your B2B organisation needs to be thorough and consistent, as to avoid ‘missing the mark’ altogether and, consequently, deterring buyers from following through. Moreover, if your business lacks effective branding and, as a result of this, has an unfavourable reputation or isn’t well known at all, consumers may not even consider your business as a viable option for them.</p>
<p>But why is this the case and, more importantly, what can your business do to avoid this unwelcome fate? In the following article, we’ll be discussing just that, so you can nail your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> strategy and start enjoying the benefits of consistent and impactful brand messages.</p>
<h2>Making Consistency a Priority</h2>
<p>As a B2B organisation, you’re likely looking to optimise your investment in branding and; thus, get the most out of your efforts, making your mark as a fighting force in your industry. In order to do just that, however, you need to approach branding in a strategic, systematic and harmonious way, as opposed to hastily developing and implementing disjointed efforts.</p>
<p>Your B2B brand can, in many ways, be what distinguishes and differentiates your offering from that of your competitors, especially if the product or service you provide is relatively similar.</p>
<p>However, branding goes beyond positioning your organisation in what is, in many cases, a highly competitive market. With well-thought-out, integrated <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, you can build invaluable trust with your audience and, in doing this, promote brand loyalty and repeat sales.</p>
<p>Moreover, uniform branding gives your B2B business the opportunity to reinforce your key messages, making them far more memorable in the minds of consumers and boosting awareness. With <a href="https://www.protocol80.com/blog/b2b-branding-statistics">84% of B2B marketers</a> citing brand awareness as their top goal, it comes as no surprise that getting your branding ‘right’ is imperative in giving you the opportunity to reach more prospects in effective ways.</p>
<h2>The Consequences of Inconsistent B2B Branding</h2>
<p>All too often B2B businesses underestimate the power of consistent branding and, instead, send an array of confusing and ineffective messages to their audience.</p>
<p>There are various reasons why this may occur, for instance, if internal communications are flawed and, because of this, team members aren’t working collectively and cooperatively towards <em>shared </em>goals. In such cases, during their day-to-day activities, employees wouldn’t all be completing tasks with an agreed understanding of the business’ desired branding in mind. Thus, unsurprisingly, the brand messages being conveyed to consumers across various channels may be conflicting, confusing and, of course, inconsistent.</p>
<p>The B2B customer journey can be relatively complex, with organisations often making large-scale, expensive or arguably risky purchases that will, ultimately, impact their business’ ongoing success. If prospects don’t feel assured and confident in their decision, they’ll likely look to have their needs met elsewhere.</p>
<p>An inconsistent brand can harbour doubt, sending mixed messages that don’t effectively endorse and support your business’ strengths. People want to buy from authentic brands that they connect with – inconsistent branding makes fostering meaningful relationships of this nature all the more difficult.</p>
<p>However, alternatively, a professional, well-executed and unified brand can help reinforce your key selling points, positioning you as a trusted provider and highlighting your business’ core values in impactful ways. Also, as companies with strong branding are often perceived as less risky options, customers are typically willing to <a href="https://www.elevationb2b.com/blog/b2b-marketing-myth-brand-consistency-negligible">pay a higher price</a> for their product or service.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>If their brand is consistently maintained, survey respondents would expect to experience a 33% increase in overall growth, which often translates in higher revenue &#8211; </em><a href="https://www.lucidpress.com/blog/brand-consistency-competitive-advantage"><em>Lucidpress</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>With all of this in mind, it’s apparent that effective and consistent branding is crucial in B2B marketing, alleviating message discrepancies that may leave prospects confused and doubting whether your offering is for them.</p>
<h2>Building a Consistent B2B Brand</h2>
<p>Ready to start constructing your business’ B2B brand in a consistent, impactful and memorable way? Take the first step today by <a href="/contact-us/">getting in touch</a> with our team of B2B marketing experts. At the Lead Agency, we have extensive experience helping B2B business build brilliant branding strategies that drive exceptional results.</p>
<p>In addition to <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, we offer a range of specialised services, including those involving <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-social-media-marketing/">B2B social media marketing</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B lead generation</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B email marketing</a> and more. To find out more, please don’t hesitate to <a href="/contact-us/">contact us</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/keeping-the-harmony-the-importance-of-consistent-b2b-branding/">Keeping the Harmony: The Importance of Consistent B2B Branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Knowing When (and How) to Rebrand Your B2B Business</title>
		<link>/knowing-when-and-how-to-rebrand-your-b2b-business/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 05:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Establishing a strong brand presence in your sector is incredibly important, especially if you want to make a memorable impact. In the business landscape, it’s not often that you see successful B2B organisations flourishing without exceptional branding to back them up &#8211; but why is this the case? Your brand encompasses your company’s identity, acting [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/knowing-when-and-how-to-rebrand-your-b2b-business/">Knowing When (and How) to Rebrand Your B2B Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Establishing a strong brand presence in your sector is incredibly important, especially if you want to make a memorable impact.</p>
<p>In the business landscape, it’s not often that you see successful B2B organisations flourishing without exceptional branding to back them up &#8211; but why is this the case?</p>
<p>Your brand encompasses your company’s identity, acting as a clear, easily recognisable representation of who you are. For those who manage to present their brand in a positive light, this tactic can be a powerful way to build trust, drive conversions and reinforce defining messages.</p>
<p>A collection of your company’s logo, website, colour scheme, images and the like; your brand assists customers in differentiating your offering from that of your competitors. It can help you stand out in a market flooded with products and services, some of which may be relatively similar in nature.</p>
<p>With effective <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> comes strong, positive customer perceptions and interactions, which can be invaluable in the modern marketplace. <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> can strongly influence your customer’s opinions of your company and, as such, will often play an instrumental role in their final purchase decisions.</p>
<p>Building a synergetic, consistent brand image is paramount in B2B marketing, as it’s central in communicating your business’ key attributes and values. At the end of the day, your brand embodies what you stand for, uniting the defining components at the heart of everything you do.</p>
<h2>So, What’s B2B Rebranding?</h2>
<p>The fundamentals of rebranding are essentially in the name itself so, even if you’ve never heard of the term, an educated guess will likely get you pretty close to the mark.</p>
<p>To <em>rebrand</em> is to redefine the attributes of your company, such as your logo, colour scheme and the like. Those who engage in rebranding will often be looking to reinvent their business’ image, for whatever reason they see fit.</p>
<p><strong><em>But why do B2B organisations rebrand?</em></strong><strong> </strong></p>
<p>There are various reasons why a B2B company may decide to take the dive and rebrand their organisation.</p>
<p>For instance, their organisation may have recently undergone a big change, such as a change in ownership. To highlight this, a business may update aspects of their existing brand to better reflect its new, refined values, identity and aesthetics.</p>
<p>In other cases, a business’ branding may have a dated look and feel that they wish to modernise. This often involves updating logos, <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/sales-marketing-collateral/">B2B marketing collateral</a> and websites, making them more in touch with your business’ current desired brand identity.</p>
<p>Beyond this, rebranding gives you the opportunity to try something different and thus, it can be a great way to remain competitive in a volatile business environment. What differentiates your offering from that of your competitors and, more importantly, why is it a superior solution for prospects? Well-thought-out, effective branding is a practical way to reinforce the unmatched value of your product or service.<strong> </strong></p>
<h2>Rebranding Your B2B Business</h2>
<p>The exact process organisations follow when rebranding can differ on a case-to-case basis. Your company’s desired outcomes aren’t going to align with those of every other business in the market, so it’s important to follow a procedure that makes sense for you.</p>
<p>During each stage of the rebranding process, it’s important to ensure your efforts remain consistent and work in harmony with one another, as well as with your pre-existing branding. Often, companies won’t completely revitalise all of their branding, instead, they’ll keep certain aspects consistent for existing customers. In such instances, maintaining synergy across all of your marketing collateral and the like is crucial.</p>
<p>You’ll likely invest money, resources and time into rebranding your business, so following a thorough process that drives long-term, value-driven outcomes is key. This will, ultimately, help you avoid ending up with mismatched brand messages that confuse and hinder customer’s perceptions of your company.</p>
<p>While there isn’t a rigid approach for rebranding your company, the following may act as a guide to give you a general idea of what to expect.</p>
<p>During the <a href="https://spireagency.com/blog/five-things-consider-rebranding-b2b-company">rebranding process</a>, you’ll likely need to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Identify and redefine your B2B business’ unique <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/business-value-proposition/">value proposition</a> or promise;</li>
<li>Assess your organisation’s existing internal values and, where required, make amendments so that they’re more closely aligned with your desired outcomes;</li>
<li>Conduct extensive market research, testing new branding concepts with select customers and listening to their feedback;</li>
<li>Rebranding is more than just updating your company’s logo. Be prepared to revamp your business’ messaging, positioning, websites and the like;</li>
<li>When it comes to rebranding, responsibility doesn’t sit purely with your marketing team. Getting your employees on board with the required changes is crucial, as they’ll play a significant role in representing your company’s branding behind the scenes and on the front line.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Ready to Rebrand Your B2B Business?</h2>
<p>Take the first step in rebranding your B2B organisation by getting in touch with our team of marketing experts. With extensive experience in the B2B business landscape, we know what it takes to effectively rebrand your company in a way that will drive long-term results.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/knowing-when-and-how-to-rebrand-your-b2b-business/">Knowing When (and How) to Rebrand Your B2B Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Getting Your B2B Branding Right Is Essential</title>
		<link>/why-getting-your-b2b-branding-right-is-essential/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 09:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Selling from one business to another is vastly different than selling to end consumers. As B2B marketers, we’ve long discussed the differences between B2B &#38; B2C Marketing. One thing that doesn&#8217;t change, however, is the importance of a strong brand. Many B2B marketers overlook the importance of branding, as they know that their customers make [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-getting-your-b2b-branding-right-is-essential/">Why Getting Your B2B Branding Right Is Essential</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Selling from one business to another is vastly different than selling to end consumers. As B2B marketers, we’ve long discussed the differences between B2B &amp; B2C Marketing. One thing that doesn&#8217;t change, however, <a href="https://www.brandingmag.com/2015/10/14/what-is-branding-and-why-is-it-important-for-your-business/">is the importance of a strong brand</a>.</p>
<p>Many B2B marketers overlook the importance of branding, as they know that their customers make purchase decisions on more functional things such as cost, quality and availability. While this is certainly true, emotions, relationships and, of course, branding also play a significant role in the B2B buying decision.</p>
<p>In fact, according to the <a href="https://hbr.org/2012/05/three-myths-about-customer-eng">Harvard Business Review</a>, 64% of people cite shared values as the main reason they enter into a buy-sell relationship with a brand.  In addition, B2B consumers are <a href="https://www.marketingweek.com/2014/04/02/b2b-branding-where-is-the-love/">more than twice as likely to consider a brand that shows personal value over business value</a> because they perceive little difference in the business value between suppliers.</p>
<p>This all comes down to business branding.</p>
<h2>How B2B Branding is Different from B2C</h2>
<p>B2B markets are very different than B2C ones. The B2B buying cycle is usually longer, the purchasing business’ requirements are more specific, more people are involved in the buying decision, and the final product or service that is chosen will often impact a number of end-users. Put simply, the stakes are higher for B2B buyers.</p>
<p>As such, B2B purchases are typically more heavily considered, with pre-determined functional requirements that have to be met. This means that competitive pricing, on-time delivery and customer support are critically important for B2B businesses to get right. If you are easy to do business with, you make your customer’s job more efficient and reliable. They will then feel confident to do business with you and see your business as a partner who can help them to overcome their problems. How does this relate to your brand? Every interaction that your customer has with your business makes up their holistic picture of your brand.</p>
<p>The most successful B2B companies create a strong brand that incorporates all of these elements so that customers and potential customers have positive associations with the business. If you can create a brand the evokes trust and reliability, you can not only build relationships with existing customers through exceeding their expectations, but you can attract new ones that already have faith in your business.</p>
<h2>What your B2B Brand Incorporates</h2>
<p>When most people think of branding, they think of their colours, logos and design. These are certainly important foundational elements of any branding strategy, however, it’s important to remember that the following elements are also vital for creating your business brand:</p>
<ul>
<li>The website copy and language used</li>
<li>How your business interacts with the target audience, both in a public sphere and privately</li>
<li>Your brand voice that is used across all materials and channels</li>
</ul>
<p>The above elements of your brand should be consistent across all on and offline channels, such as print advertising, social media and your website.</p>
<p>Your brand values will be the basis for the entire culture of your company, so it’s important that this is something that is intentionally considered and developed from the outset. Don’t simply focus on the design elements of your brand, but look deeper into the core of your company. Who are you as a business? What is important to you? Why should customers do business with you?</p>
<h2>How to Create Your B2B Brand</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7581" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/B2B-Branding-2.jpg" alt="B2B Branding" width="850" height="385" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/B2B-Branding-2.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/B2B-Branding-2-450x204.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/B2B-Branding-2-768x348.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<p><a href="http://contentmarketinginstitute.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/2015_B2B_Research.pdf">84% of B2B marketers say that brand awareness is their top goal</a>. This means that the competition to get your audience’s attention is getting fiercer.</p>
<p>In order to cut through the noise and really speak to your audience, you have to develop an effective brand strategy that separates your business from your competitors (who likely have a very similar offering). The following can help you engage with your audience on a deeper level.</p>
<h2>1. Stay Simple</h2>
<p>While the products and services that you’re selling may be complex, your brand shouldn’t be. The most successful B2B businesses keep their brand simple, ensuring their message is easy to understand and remember. Crafting a message that is concise, comprehensible and tells your brand story can be difficult. However, spending a bit of time working on getting it right will pay off in the end.</p>
<h2>2. Be Clear About What You Do</h2>
<p>B2B buyers want to know that your brand can solve their problem. The longer it takes for them to work it out, the more likely you are to lose their attention. When they get to your website or see one of your ads, they should know immediately whether your product or services are relevant to them. This should all be communicated through your brand. For example, do you work with start-ups or bigger companies? Is there a specific industry that you work in? Do you mostly work with people in certain roles? Are you a premium product or low-cost provider?</p>
<h2>3. Differentiate Your Brand</h2>
<p>In the B2B environment, businesses typically face a lot of competition from other companies that offer very similar products and services. Your audience will be researching to find the best solution for their needs. When they perform a Google search, they&#8217;re likely to find all of these other businesses and their similar solutions. How do you make sure that they choose you? Differentiation. Find something that is unique about your business and communicate that to your audience. Give them a reason to choose you over your competitors.</p>
<h2>4. Stand Out</h2>
<p>In the cluttered B2B space, it is vital that your messaging stands out from your competitors. The products you are selling may not be the most exciting, but your tagline has to be. All too often, B2B businesses stick to explaining exactly what their product does, which comes across a little bland and doesn’t stand out.</p>
<p>A consumer’s brain is wandering <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/brain-wise/201301/our-minds-wander-least-30-percent-the-time">30% of the time, on average </a>. You need to grab their attention and tell them exactly how your product or service will benefit them. This can only be done through compelling, strong messaging.</p>
<h2>5. Focus On Customers</h2>
<p>Instead of defining your brand by your services or how long you have been in business, think of how your brand adds value to your customers. Your brand should articulate why a customer should choose to work with you. The best way to identify this is to ask the customer directly. When they respond, listen to their answers carefully and apply them in your brand strategy. This is the foundation of customer-centricity and, according to Delloite, customer-centric brands are 60% more profitable than companies not focused on the customer. Being a customer-centric brand means understanding the customer and ensuring that every aspect of your business is geared towards them. This involves continually learning from your customers and applying what you have learned in every interaction that you have with them.</p>
<h2>6. Be Data-Driven</h2>
<p>Including analytics data is necessary for creating a customer-centric brand. This data can come in many forms. For example, looking at data from search trends and on social platforms can identify audience demographics and interests. You can also look at your website data, such as how far down the page visitors are they scrolling, what they are clicking on, and what content seems to be holding their attention. Out-with your business data, you can look at analyst and market research reports to get well-researched, comprehensive information on your industry and audience.</p>
<p>The key to using data to inform your brand strategy is to test continually. By testing each element of your campaigns, you can work out what resonates with your audience and what is most likely to encourage them to take action. You can then tweak your strategies to ensure they are most effective in engaging your audience.</p>
<h2>6. Evoke Emotion</h2>
<p>Focusing on developing an emotional connection with your prospects and customers is one of the most important things you can do to ensure your brand succeeds. People who are emotionally invested in your business will not only pay more for your products or services but will go out of their way to seek out your business and recommend it to their peers.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/marketing-resources/promotion-emotion-b2b/">B2B buyers are almost 50% more likely to make a purchase and 8X more likely to pay a premium when they are emotionally engaged.</a></p></blockquote>
<p>While B2B decisions may be more rational, the truth is that the purchaser will subconsciously first make an emotional decision and then rationalise it. According to Google, <a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/marketing-resources/promotion-emotion-b2b/">purchase intent dips in the B2B purchase funnel as emotion in messaging decreases</a>. When crafting your emotional messaging, bear in mind that the <a href="https://hbr.org/2018/03/the-b2b-elements-of-value">main driver of B2B purchases is risk reduction</a>.</p>
<p>For more information on <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a> or your wider <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B marketing</a> strategy, get in touch with the specialists at The Lead Agency. We&#8217;ve worked on a number of B2B campaigns across industries and can apply our in-depth experience to benefit your business.</p>
<p>Want to proactively plan for future success? Start developing your business&#8217; strategy for next year with our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/why-getting-your-b2b-branding-right-is-essential/">Why Getting Your B2B Branding Right Is Essential</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Event Marketing Can Help Your B2B Brand</title>
		<link>/event-marketing-for-b2b-brands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 05:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What Is Event Marketing? Event Marketing in business is the act of hosting a gathering that gives your company’s buyers, executives and prospects the opportunity to engage with your brand face-to-face – both in-person (with seminars/workshops etc) and virtually (live streaming of these events). There has been a rise in virtual events in recent years, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/event-marketing-for-b2b-brands/">How Event Marketing Can Help Your B2B Brand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>What Is Event Marketing?</strong></h2>
<p>Event Marketing in business is the act of hosting a gathering that gives your company’s buyers, executives and prospects the opportunity to <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">engage with your brand</a> face-to-face – both in-person (with seminars/workshops etc) and virtually (live streaming of these events). There has been a rise in virtual events in recent years, which is extending the reach for B2B organisations to engage prospects despite their geographical location. Attendees can sign up online and are given login details to join sessions online no matter where they are from.</p>
<p>Events also hold the added appeal of providing the opportunity for your business and your attendees to build their professional networks.</p>
<p>Event Marketing facilitates the promotion of causes that are central to your organisations expertise. Events give organisations the opportunity to demonstrate their authority and skill by sharing insights and information with their audience.</p>
<p>By initiating dialogue between your business and individuals from other businesses you can begin to communicate how your offering could serve to solve your prospects business problems.</p>
<h2><strong>Why Should I Include Event Marketing in My Marketing Mix?</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Event Marketing = Lead Generation!</strong></p>
<p>Research conducted by the International Data Group indicates that executive events are among the highest yielding lead generation strategies. A well-executed marketing event has the ability to advance buyers through multiple stages of the sales funnel, in order to deliver qualified, sales-ready leads.</p>
<p>This is because hosting an event gives your business the potential to position your business with highly relevant people who may otherwise be entirely unaware of who you are and what you do. What’s more is that you have the power of knowing that those who register and attend your event are there because they actually want to learn more about the topic you’ve promised them and that you specialise in.</p>
<p>What’s more, leads generated through Event Marketing present organisations with the opportunity of significant return on investment compared to other generation methods, based on a cost-per-lead basis:</p>
<blockquote><p>Meeting a prospective customer at an exhibition versus in the field saves an organisation $943 on average! [Center for Exhibition Industry Research, 2014]
<p>It takes an average of 4.5 sales calls to close a sale without an exhibition lead, and only 3.5 sales calls to close a sale with a lead from an exhibition. [Center for Exhibition Industry Research, 2014]</blockquote>
<p>Event Marketing is built around the idea of providing a solution for troubled businesses prospects that is based around your product or service offering as a solution. Chances are, many of those who attend will be troubled buyers that are looking for some clarity. If you can provide that clarity for them at your event they are much more likely to explore the solutions you can offer them, given that you’re the one who helped them.</p>
<blockquote><p>99% of exhibitors find unique value delivered by B2B exhibitions which is not provided by other marketing channels. [Center for Exhibition Industry Research, 2014]</blockquote>
<h2><strong>3 Tips For Hosting a Successful Marketing Event:</strong></h2>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px;">1. Tailor your event:</h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">In order to effectively position your organisation to your audience’s industry or business problem ensure your event has a clear theme or focus that draws the specific crowd you will be best suited to service.</p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px;">2. Promotion:</h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">It is important to understand that the vast majority of those you invite will not attend your event, this is particularly true if you are inviting a “cold” list (i.e. those not aware of you already). As such, use of multiple touch points to promote your event is crucial! Experts recommend interacting with your invited audience a minimum of 5 times in the lead up to your event in order to maximise the number of attendees.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">The most used and most effective form of promotion for Event Marketing is email. However, some other great promotion options include your businesses website, physical mail and word-of-mouth.</p>
<h3 style="padding-left: 30px;">3. Have a communication plan:</h3>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Be sure you have a communication plan, post-event, that involves following-up up and keeping in regular contact with attendees, as well as those who were invited but did not register.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Every prospect you invite to your event is entered into your sales funnel for nurturing. By keeping in contact with these leads and prospects after the event you will minimise the chance of them exiting the sales funnel and ensure they understand the problems you can solve for them, keeping you front-of-mind for when they next come across that problem that you have the power to solve.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p>“Events are the original social experience. It&#8217;s the immersive experience centered around a central topic, idea, or belief, shared between the collective audience and presenters, which makes events so central.”-<em>Matt McGowan, Ad Strategy, Google</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Keep in mind that the scale of your B2B event will vary depending on your budget, your available resources and your target market.</p>
<p>Skilled B2B marketers are always looking for new ways to generate leads and <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">build brand awareness</a>. Staging a targeted, <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branded</a> and unique event, seminar or conference presents the opportunity to expand from “business as usual” to offering a point of difference.</p>
<p>For more information on the importance of <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, read our article on <a href="/business-branding-importance/">The Importance of Business Branding</a>.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget to check out the other industries that we operate in; <a href="/education-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Education Marketing</a> |<br />
<a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing </a>| <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/event-marketing-for-b2b-brands/">How Event Marketing Can Help Your B2B Brand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance Of Business Branding</title>
		<link>/business-branding-importance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 06:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is Business Branding? Branding is the marketing practice of defining your business to yourself, your team and all your external audiences. Your brand should embody the core of what your business is and what values it stands for not just it’s “look” or “sound”. Business Branding Done Well:  A trap that many businesses tend [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/business-branding-importance/">The Importance Of Business Branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><strong>What is Business Branding?</strong></h2>
<p><a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">Branding i</a>s the marketing practice of defining your business to yourself, your team and all your external audiences. Your brand should embody the core of what your business is and what values it stands for not just it’s “look” or “sound”.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>Business Branding Done Well: </strong></h2>
<p>A trap that many businesses tend to fall into, when it comes to determining their “brand”, is getting caught up in focusing all of their attention on the product or service and how it leads to customers and revenue. If this sounds like you STOP! This is not the way to go about <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">branding your business</a>. Your brand should communicate the very essence of your company’s identity and values, not merely it’s material offering.</p>
<p>Take, for instance, the idea of marketing soft drinks: There are countless cola options available to the general public, so why is it that Coca-Cola and Pepsi (the indisputable mega-houses of this segment) have such successful and established “brands”?</p>
<p>The answer is that Coca-Cola and Pepsi don’t approach the delivery of their message as a purely product-oriented solution. They market an experience to their audience, which aims to communicate a shared understanding of what their customers want out of their interaction with the brand. Coca-Cola and Pepsi offer more than thirst quenching, they market happiness and joy and an eagerness to take on the world!</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Open-Happiness.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2852 alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Open-Happiness-300x150.jpg" alt="Coca-cola brand open happiness advertisement" width="399" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Open-Happiness-300x150.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Open-Happiness.jpg 709w" sizes="(max-width: 399px) 100vw, 399px" /><img class=" wp-image-2853 alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pepsi-300x240.jpg" alt="Pepsi Brand Advertisement" width="250" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pepsi-300x240.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pepsi.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 250px) 100vw, 250px" /></a></p>
<p>Another common way these brands avoid focusing on the physical product, but instead connect with the consumer on an emotional level, is through celebrity endorsements. This tactic adds further humanisation and aspirational desire to the brand and therefore a greater chance for customers to connect on a personal level.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Taylor-Swift.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2854 alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Taylor-Swift-300x189.jpg" alt="Coca-cola Brand Advocate Taylor Swift" width="317" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Taylor-Swift-300x189.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Coke-Taylor-Swift.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 317px) 100vw, 317px" /><img class=" wp-image-2855 alignnone" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pepsi-Beyonce2-300x174.jpg" alt="Pepsi Brand Advocate Beyonce" width="344" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pepsi-Beyonce2-300x174.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Pepsi-Beyonce2-1024x595.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 344px) 100vw, 344px" /></a></p>
<h2></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>How Can You Define Your Brand Like The Experts?</strong></h2>
<p>Before you can do anything about getting the word out about your fabulous brand you need to understand exactly what you’re trying to communicate. This is likely to be a time-consuming process, but if done right, this will set the tone for all your business efforts (internally and externally) both now and in to the future.</p>
<p>This step should feel like a form of business self-discovery and leave you with a clear brand identity. To start you’ll need to be able to answer the following questions about your business:</p>
<ul>
<li>What is your company’s mission?</li>
<li>What benefits and features do your products or services provide?</li>
<li>How do your customers and prospects currently view your company?</li>
<li>What qualities do you want your customers and prospects to associate with your company?</li>
<li>How does your company differ from competitors?</li>
</ul>
<p>By answering the above you should gain a good idea of what your business’ offering is (both tangible and intangible). Be aware of what space in the market your offering occupies and research the emotive and rational needs and concerns of these customers and prospects.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>Humanising Your Brand:</strong></h2>
<p>Think about what your brand’s character is, what is it promising to deliver? This should promote your business, connect with your customers and differentiate you from the market. Think of your brand as a person. What are its beliefs and values that could connect it with individuals with a shared purpose? By building a living brand you create emotion. <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">Business branding</a> is what can turn a cold-faced, corporate organisation into a warm and welcoming company that users trust and support to build long-term relationships with customers.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>What Now?</strong></h2>
<p>Now you have a clear identity with which to craft your company’s personality and can conduct all of your business. With this tactic you’ll be able to capture your audiences interest and secure them as life-long customers by following these simple steps, which utilise your swish new brand identity:</p>
<ol>
<li>Get a great logo and make it seen! Put it everywhere. Make it unique and memorable.</li>
<li>Determine and write down your brand message and ensure all employees understand and adhere to this message.</li>
<li>Integrate you brand and create a brand “voice”. Your brand message should extend to every aspect of your business; how you answer the phone, how your salespeople present themselves, email signatures and so on. Ensures that communication across the entire company is succinct and consistent in order to create a reliable, trustworthy image. This voice needs to be applied to all verbal, written and visual communication, both online and offline.</li>
<li>Develop a tagline that neatly communicates your brand’s essence in a meaningful and memorable way.</li>
<li>Design templates and determine standards for all marketing materials so that variables like colour scheme, logo placement and overall look are consistent. Keep in mind that this doesn’t need to be overly fancy, but it does need to be universally applied.</li>
<li>Deliver on your brand promise! Most important of all is that you deliver on your brand promise. Customers won’t stay loyal or become brand advocates who rake in referrals if you don’t meet your promises.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">Business Branding</a> can transform a company from an unknown name on the market into a trusted friend for customers, so while it can be a tedious and time-consuming task, it is worthwhile. Give your business a push today and develop a brand identity you can be proud of.</p>
<p>For more information of <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B branding</a>, read this article on <a href="/b2b-marketing-segmentation-will-change-fortune/">B2B Marketing Segmentation</a> to find out how to make your brand relevant to your target audience.</p>
<p>If you have any other questions and queries in regard to <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B Digital Marketing</a>, then get in contact with our expert <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> at the Lead Agency today!</p>
<div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/business-branding-importance/">The Importance Of Business Branding</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
