<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SEO Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/seo-blogs-articles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 08:14:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>SEO Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>7 Ways to Increase Your Organic CTRs</title>
		<link>/7-ways-to-increase-your-organic-ctrs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 03:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=45284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the most effective ways to reduce spend on digital marketing campaigns is to get more quality clicks from the content that is already on the site. This can be done by increasing click-through rates (CTR).   The click-through rate of an organic campaign is the number of clicks you get divided by the number [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-ways-to-increase-your-organic-ctrs/">7 Ways to Increase Your Organic CTRs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most effective ways to reduce spend on digital marketing campaigns is to get more quality clicks from the content that is already on the site. This can be done by increasing click-through rates (CTR). <strong> </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://getstat.com/blog/organic-click-rate-ctr/">The click-through rate of an organic campaign</a> is the number of clicks you get divided by the number of searchers who seen the business listing (impressions). So, if 20 people see your organic search result, and 5 people clicked on it, you’d have a 25% CTR.</p>
<h2>Why CTR is an Important Metric</h2>
<p>CTR is an indirect ranking factor for Google. Simply put, if searchers are clicking on your result more than they are clicking on other results on the SERPs, Google will acknowledge this and push your result higher up the rankings. Having a higher ranking can also improve your CTR because moving up just one spot in the organic search results can increase <a href="https://backlinko.com/google-ctr-stats">click-through rate by 30.8%</a>. This means that increasing organic CTR is highly beneficial for any SEO campaign. It’s also free, as you’re not creating anything new, or paying for ad spots, but rather, making the most of what you already have.</p>
<p>The following are a few simple ways to increase your organic click-through rates.</p>
<h3>1. Use Copy Carefully</h3>
<p>Your copy has a significant impact on your CTR. There are certain ways title tags and meta-descriptions can be written to accomplish this. First, adding a positive emotion leads to an average of <a href="https://backlinko.com/google-ctr-stats"> 7.4% higher CTR</a>. Negative emotion will also generate more clicks than a neutral title. Adding a question to your title is another effective way to increase CTR. Tools like <a href="https://answerthepublic.com/">Answer the Public</a> are ideal for finding popular questions about your subject that may be relevant for your title. But, be careful not to alienate the audience by using ‘power’ words, such as ‘Amazing’ and ‘Ultimate,’ as searchers often perceive these words as clickbait, and as such, do not click-through to the page.</p>
<h3>2. Include Keywords in Your URL &amp; Title Tag</h3>
<p>Including keywords in the URL is another way to increase CTR. <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/7451184?hl=en">Google’s best practice guidelines</a> state that URLs should be descriptive and contain relevant search terms. Keywords should also be included in the title tag, close to the beginning. Digital marketing research tools such as <a href="https://ads.google.com/intl/en_au/home/tools/keyword-planner/">Google Keyword Planner</a>, <a href="https://neilpatel.com/ubersuggest/">Ubersuggest</a> and <a href="https://answerthepublic.com/">AnswerThePublic</a> can help marketers find relevant keywords that contain the specific language used by searchers.</p>
<h3>3. Keep Titles Short</h3>
<p>Despite writing title tags following Google’s best practice, remember that Google can (and often will) update these titles to display on the SERPs. After all the effort that went in to writing your title tags, you want to make sure people see them. The most effective way to ensure they are not changed by Google is to <a href="https://smartsearchmarketing.com/google-title-tag-serp-preview-tool">keep title tags under 600 pixels</a>. With a shorter title, Google is less likely to update it with something that will fit better on its results pages. In addition, shorter title tags are proven to have higher CTRs.</p>
<h3>4. Write Your Own Meta Descriptions</h3>
<p>Just as Google can change a title tag, the search engine will often update the meta-descriptions. This occurs so often, in fact, that SEO experts have long debated whether or not it’s worth writing their own meta-descriptions. Writing a meta-description is still a worthwhile exercise, as pages with meta-descriptions have a higher CTR than those without.</p>
<h3>5. Add the Year to Title Tags</h3>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.clickflow.com/">ClickFlow</a>, adding the current year to the title tag will increase click CTR by 50-150%. Google will also rank this content higher as it appears to be fresher. This is particularly true in fast-paced industries. However, in order to be effective with this tactic, you will not only have to update the title tag but also the content in the article each year in order to reflect up-to-date trends.</p>
<h3>6. Use Insights from Google Ads</h3>
<p>Your organic listings can benefit from learnings taken from Google Ads. If you are running a Google Ads campaign, look at your keywords and their quality score. Ads with a higher quality score typically have the most effective Ad Copy and a higher CTR. This can give invaluable insight into the most effective words and phrases to include in your organic title tags and meta-descriptions.</p>
<h3>7. Optimise Your Featured Snippets Listing</h3>
<p>As a result of Google’s featured snippet results, more than <a href="https://searchengineland.com/now-more-50-of-google-searches-end-without-a-click-to-other-content-study-finds-320574">50% of Google searches now end</a> with no click. This means that even if you have obtained the featured snippet for a certain keyword, you still have work to get searchers to click-through your website. In order to do this, consider adding a few extra points to answer the search query. Google will typically show the first 5-7 points in an answer. If you include 8-9 points, the searcher will have to click-through to see the full results.</p>
<p>Increasing your organic CTR is an underused but effective digital marketing tactic. It doesn’t take much time, and it costs nothing, but it can have a huge impact on your overall campaign.</p>
<p>For more information on this article, or for help with your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO strategy</a>, don&#8217;t hesitate to get in touch with the <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">digital marketing</a> experts at the Lead Agency.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/7-ways-to-increase-your-organic-ctrs/">7 Ways to Increase Your Organic CTRs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Google Ads Can Boost Your SEO Results (Really!)</title>
		<link>/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 03:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google has said over and over again that SEO is not a paid activity. This means that advertising with Google Ads will not have an impact on your organic search rankings. This article does not dispute the above. We definitely believe that using Google Ads alone is not enough for your site to see a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/">How Google Ads Can Boost Your SEO Results (Really!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><u><a href="https://moz.com/blog/how-google-adwords-ppc-affects-organic-results">Google has said over and over again that SEO is not a paid activity</a></u>. This means that advertising with Google Ads will not have an impact on your organic search rankings.</p>
<p>This article does not dispute the above. We definitely believe that using Google Ads alone is not enough for your site to see a boost in its results on the SERPs. However, there are definitely ways that using Google Ads can help improve your SEO strategy. Google Ads and SEO have a similar premise behind them; the benefit of using Google Ads over SEO is that it generates data immediately. Google Ads can provide a wealth of useful audience and keyword-specific data that can be used to inform an SEO campaign before wasting a lot of time and money figuring out what works with slower SEO results.</p>
<p>For example, you may choose keywords for SEO that you think are relevant and spend significant amounts of time and money to rank for them, only to discover months down the line that the traffic those particular keywords brings in does not convert. If you had run a Google Ads campaign previously, you would have already identified that this keyword was not effective.</p>
<p>The following are some of the other ways that you can apply Google Ads to help with your SEO strategy.</p>
<h2> 1. Look at the Search Terms Report</h2>
<p>The Search Terms report from Google Ads provides advertisers with a list of the phrases that people are actually typing into Google before clicking on the ads. It shows the exact phrases that are triggering your ads, which is vital information for your business to know. You can use this report to identify words or phrases that get a lot of impressions and clicks, and most importantly, the ones that lead to conversions. This information can give you a great insight into the keywords that searchers are using to find your business. For SEO, look for the phrases that have intent behind them and the ones that convert to incorporate into your strategy, rather than simply casting a wide net with high-volume keywords.</p>
<h2> 2. Analyse Your Click-Through Rates (CTRs)</h2>
<p>An ad with a high Click Through Rate (CTR) will typically be well written, or contain something compelling that drives a searcher to respond. If you can replicate the formula that gets the best CTR for your ads, you are likely to increase the CTR on your organic results too, which means more traffic for your site without having to increase your position on the SERPs.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>Look at your Google Ads account to see if you can identify anything in your ads that seems to be connecting with the audience and leading to a higher click through rate, such as a specific headline or call to action.</p>
<p>Each part of your ad can corresponds to a different part of your on-page SEO as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Google Ads Headlines = Title Tags</li>
<li>Google Ads Ad Descriptions = Meta Descriptions</li>
<li>Google Ads Display URL = Landing Page URL</li>
</ul>
<p>This knowledge can be used to create SEO meta data that turns searchers into relevant traffic. Just be careful not to optimise Click Through Rate in a way that generates irrelevant traffic, as this will affect bounce rate and dwell time, which may negatively impact your SEO efforts.</p>
<h2> 3. Identify Geographic Locations that Work</h2>
<p>Your Google Ads campaign can provide data on geographic locations that can be useful for creating Local SEO campaigns. Even if your business doesn’t have a physical location to visit, location data from Google Ads can enhance the performance of your campaign in different geographical areas.</p>
<p>In order to use your Google Ads location data, find the areas you are interested in, then, identify which are performing well. For example, look at the ads that have the most conversions, highest sales by revenue, the most clicks or the best Click Through Rates. This information can then be used for location-specific SEO campaigns to improve on-page SEO and refine targeted keywords.</p>
<h2> 4. Compliment SEO With Remarketing</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.dynamicyield.com/glossary/remarketing/">Remarketing (also known as retargeting) is the tactic of serving targeted ads to people who have already visited or taken action on your website</a>. Considering<strong> </strong><u>96-98%</u> of the visitors to your website won’t make a purchase the first time that they are there, this is an incredibly effective way of keeping your brand fresh in their mind and convincing them to come back to your site. When they come back as returning visitors, they are more likely to convert, as they are already aware of your business and its products and services.</p>
<p>Remarketing can help improve your SEO results by giving your business an easy and cost-effective way to get in front of prospects several times, which allows you to get the most value that you can from the visitors that you generate to your site organically.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a specialist <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing agency</a>. Get in touch with us for more information on <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/">Google Ads advertising</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO</a>, or your wider digital marketing strategy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-google-ads-can-boost-your-seo-results-really/">How Google Ads Can Boost Your SEO Results (Really!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Guest Blogging for SEO</title>
		<link>/the-power-of-guest-blogging-for-seo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 05:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>According to marketing guru Neil Patel, guest blogging is the best inbound marketing strategy. Guest blogging benefits both the blog that hosts the content and the person writing the content. The writer gets authority, qualified traffic, links, and leads, while the blog host gets another perspective for the content on their blog. In addition, 62.96% [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-power-of-guest-blogging-for-seo/">The Power of Guest Blogging for SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to marketing guru Neil Patel, <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/why-guest-blogging-is-the-best-inbound-marketing-strategy-a-data-driven-answer/">guest blogging is the best inbound marketing strategy</a>. Guest blogging benefits both the blog that hosts the content and the person writing the content. The writer gets authority, qualified traffic, links, and leads, while the blog host gets another perspective for the content on their blog. In addition, <a href="https://seotribunal.com/blog/blogging-statistics/">62.96% of people perceive blogs that have a number of contributors to be more credible</a>.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re already working to maintain your own business blog, the thought of spending time writing articles for another one can seem overwhelming. However, in today’s digital environment where search engines place more and more emphasis on high quality backlinks, putting time into writing blogs for guest posts may be a more effective strategy for your SEO overall.</p>
<p>The following are some of the reasons that guest posting is such an effective strategy, and one that you should definitely consider including in your digital marketing campaigns.</p>
<h2> 1. Boost Your SEO</h2>
<p>We’ve already mentioned that guest posting is an effective SEO strategy. This is because <a href="https://www.webconfs.com/importance-of-backlinks-article-5.php">Google gives more credit to websites that have a good number of quality backlinks</a>, considering them to be more relevant than sites with fewer or lower quality links.</p>
<p>In order to get these relevant, quality links, you have to find relevant blogs in your niche that will include crawlable links to your blog from the articles that you publish on their site. Most websites that allow guest posts know that the main benefit for the author is a link to their site, and as such, will offer at least one link to the website within the copy and another link in the author bio.</p>
<h2> 2. Build Strong Online Relationships</h2>
<p>Guest posting for other sites will help your business to build digital relationships with relevant blogs. This is particularly important for new businesses or businesses that currently don’t have a significant online presence. When it comes to guest posting, the main thing to remember is that there’s no harm in asking. Some blogs may not be open to receiving guest posts, or may have very strict requirements as to what kind of guest post they will accept, however, others will be happy for the additional content for their site and welcome your posts.</p>
<h2> 3. Establish Authority Online<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>It takes a long time and a lot of effort to build your own business blog. Writing a quality, informative guest post gives you a chance to get yourself and your business in front of a new audience. This helps to build your own reputation, as the readers who enjoy your post are likely to look at your author bio, and even click through to your site to read more of your work. Getting published on a number of sites that have already established an online authority in your niche will help to build your brand and get it out to relevant people in your target audience.</p>
<h2> 4. Shorten the Sales Cycle</h2>
<p>Content marketing isn’t easy. When done wrong, it can quickly drain your marketing budget. However, when it’s done right, content marketing can drive leads and sales for your business. This is because distributing high-quality content across a number of online channels helps build recognition and trust between your business and the target audience. It also helps to boost your brand recognition as the audience starts to see your content more often and recognise you as an expert in the field. This has a significant impact on your <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/296526">sales funnel</a>.</p>
<p>Put simply, the more authority you can build, the more a prospect will trust your brand and be open to your products or services, which effectively shortens the sales cycle. This means that instead of waiting for people to find your business using inbound marketing strategies, or advertising to them more directly with an outbound campaign, guest posting can bridge the gap and drive sales. Having guest posts published on trusted websites gives your brand the opportunity to present its services, messages and value propositions to an interested audience, which can significantly impact their customer journey for the better.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we’re experts in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B Digital Marketing</a>. Contact us for the most up to date <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO strategies</a> to boost your website’s ranking on the SERPs and ensure your business continues to drive traffic that turns into viable leads and sales.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-power-of-guest-blogging-for-seo/">The Power of Guest Blogging for SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does Your Website Need a Blog?</title>
		<link>/does-your-website-need-a-blog/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 06:31:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blogs are becoming an increasingly common component of many B2B content marketing strategies. The business landscape is only continuing to grow in competitiveness and, if organisations fail to evolve, they’ll likely be left behind in the rush. Reaching prospects in new and exciting ways has never been so important, so why are B2B businesses turning [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/does-your-website-need-a-blog/">Does Your Website Need a Blog?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blogs are becoming an increasingly common component of many <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a> strategies. The business landscape is only continuing to grow in competitiveness and, if organisations fail to evolve, they’ll likely be left behind in the rush.</p>
<p>Reaching prospects in new and exciting ways has never been so important, so why are B2B businesses turning to blogs? While in 1999 there were a recorded 23 blogs on the internet, by 2006 this figure had risen to <a href="https://www.webdesignerdepot.com/2011/03/a-brief-history-of-blogging/">50 million</a>. Now, in 2019, there are over <a href="https://hostingtribunal.com/blog/how-many-blogs/">500 million</a> blogs that have been shared online.</p>
<p>So, it’s evident that blogging has grown into an incredibly popular content medium, but it certainly isn’t a new, innovative concept. This, however, doesn’t seem to have significantly impacted the success that individuals can achieve by applying this content marketing tactic.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“Businesses that blog witness their monthly leads rise by 126% more than those who don’t” &#8211; </em><em><a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/5519/Blogging-Businesses-Experience-126-Higher-Lead-Growth-Than-Non-Blogging-Businesses.aspx#sm.000192hi7x101mdhvw2cuusbsvcxt">HubSpot</a></em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you want to achieve exceptional results through blogging, differentiation is key. The internet has been flooded with an abundance of blog content so, if you don’t establish a clear <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/business-value-proposition/">B2B value proposition</a> or point-of-difference, prospects will simply look elsewhere.</p>
<p>Successful B2B content marketing campaigns rely heavily on offering customers real value and, when done right, posting a regular blog can be an effective way to do just that.</p>
<h2>Benefits of Sharing Regular Blogs</h2>
<p>We’ve established that blogs can be an incredibly powerful tool, but the question still remains, does your B2B business need one?</p>
<p>While posting a regular blog isn’t mandatory, it has the potential to benefit your organisation immensely. So, whether or not you <em>need</em> a blog ultimately comes down to whether you’d like to enjoy the benefits this tactic can offer.</p>
<h3>Powerful Component of Your SEO Strategy</h3>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7576" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SEO-Strategy.png" alt="" width="850" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SEO-Strategy.png 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SEO-Strategy-450x159.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SEO-Strategy-768x271.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<h4>Keep Content New and Relevant</h4>
<p>Want to drive more, relevant traffic to your website? <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">Search engine optimisation</a> is essential. Regardless of how great your digital domains are, if your target audience can’t find them, you will likely struggle to generate leads.</p>
<p>While the main landing pages of your website may not be updated often, blogs can be shared regularly to keep your content fresh and current. Google’s algorithm is centred on delivering valuable information to users and blogging is a practical way to do just that.</p>
<h4>Target Long-Tail Keywords</h4>
<p>Blogs are also a great opportunity for businesses to strategically target long-tail keywords, which are short phrases comprising of three to five terms. Such phrases are a fundamental aspect of your SEO strategy, so if you’re yet to use them, the time to start is now.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“Long-tail keywords account for 70% of all web searches” – </em><em><a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/long-tail-keywords-seo/">Neil Patel</a></em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>When incorporated into your blog content, keywords of this nature can help boost your visibility and overall relevance in Google’s search results. This is because they target highly specific searches, so it’s more likely that the users who find your website will actually have a strong interest in what you have to say.</p>
<h4>Increase Number of Internal Links</h4>
<p>Similarly, frequently posting frequent blogs is an effective way for you to include internal links to different pages on your website. Internal linking is a relatively simple approach that, when done right, can increase your <a href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/internal-links-for-seo/">organic traffic by 40%</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>“The number of internal links pointing to a page is a signal to search engines about the relative importance of that page” &#8211; </em><a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/9049606?hl=en&amp;visit_id=637008219833140216-874694717&amp;rd=1"><em>Google</em></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Internal links convey to Google’s algorithm that your pages are useful to readers by building greater credibility, meaning and context. They can, in this way, boost your search engine ranking and significantly improve the performance of your website.</p>
<h3>Transform into Alternative Content</h3>
<p>Blog content can be repurposed to create informative videos, social media posts, email campaigns and the like. By transforming your blogs into different types of content, you can maximise your time by leveraging the work you’ve already done.</p>
<p>It is, however, important that you still continue to create new exciting content and don’t always completely duplicate your phrasing. If the information you’re sharing becomes overused, it will likely lose it’s effectiveness as prospects grow bored of merely being exposed to more of the same.</p>
<h3>Build Trust and Credibility</h3>
<p>By regularly sharing unique, relevant blogs, your B2B business can demonstrate your expertise while also offering prospects ongoing value. Frequent blog posts can, in this way, help you build a mutually beneficial relationship with customers.</p>
<p>Through blogging, you can establish yourself as a thought leader, sharing innovative concepts that accurately display your extensive industry knowledge. This will, in turn, assist your business in fostering a strong reputation as a trusted and informed organisation.</p>
<p>Want to create a blog, but not sure where to begin? Take your <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a> strategy to the next level by getting in touch with a <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a> expert from the Lead Agency today.</p>
<p>We can also help your business get up-to-date on the latest <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, so you can proactively plan for future success.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/does-your-website-need-a-blog/">Does Your Website Need a Blog?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Overlooking Technical Elements in Your SEO Strategy?</title>
		<link>/are-you-overlooking-technical-elements-in-your-seo-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 06:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>61% of marketers say improving SEO and growing their organic presence is their top inbound marketing priority. What these marketers need to remember is that technical SEO is one of the most important elements of any B2B SEO strategy. Technical SEO is not as time-consuming as other SEO tactics like content, link building, and on-page [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-overlooking-technical-elements-in-your-seo-strategy/">Are You Overlooking Technical Elements in Your SEO Strategy?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.impactbnd.com/blog/seo-statistics">61% of marketers say improving SEO and growing their organic presence is their top inbound marketing priority</a>.</p></blockquote>
<p>What these marketers need to remember is that technical SEO is one of the most important elements of any <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a> strategy. Technical SEO is not as time-consuming as other SEO tactics like content, link building, and on-page optimisation, however, it is just as, if not more, important.</p>
<p>If your technical SEO is not on-point, you run the risk of completely ruining the search performance of your site.</p>
<h2>Why is Technical SEO So Important?</h2>
<p>Technical Search Engine Optimisation (technical SEO) is the process of ensuring a website technically adheres to search engine guidelines. This is vital for any SEO strategy, as these technical elements ensure that a website can be properly indexed and ranked by search engines so that it appears on the Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs). Search engines will <a href="https://ignitevisibility.com/technical-seo/">rank websites higher in search results if their technical set up is good</a>.</p>
<p>The best time to set up your technical SEO is during the construction of the website. It involves optimising both the website and its server to help search engine spiders crawl and index the site, so it is a fundamental step in the setup of any site. It is also much easier to implement technical SEO from the start than it is to identify and fix any issues when the site is running. However, while you may set up technical SEO when you are setting up your website, it’s important to check back on it regularly. The technical elements you have in place may need to be updated as <a href="https://moz.com/google-algorithm-change">search engines update their algorithms</a>, your business changes, or consumer behaviour shifts.</p>
<h2>What are the Key Elements of Technical SEO?</h2>
<p>When search engines crawl a site, they are looking for a number of indications that the technical set up is good. Some of the most important things that you can do to set up your technical SEO properly are as follows.</p>
<h3>Set Up a Mobile-Friendly Site</h3>
<p><a href="https://searchengineland.com/report-nearly-60-percent-searches-now-mobile-devices-255025">Nearly 60% of searches today occur from mobile devices</a>. This shows that your users are mobile. If they come to your site from their mobile device and it doesn’t load properly, they’re likely to leave and find an alternative. Google has been aware of this for some time and has implemented a <a href="https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2018/03/rolling-out-mobile-first-indexing.html">‘mobile-first’ approach to indexing content</a>. This means that it’s not only important for the user experience that your site is mobile-friendly, it’s also essential for rankings.</p>
<p>In order to ensure your website is mobile-friendly, you can implement a <a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/01/guidelines-for-responsive-web-design/">‘responsive’ web design</a>. This is a type of web design that ensures the site adjusts itself automatically depending on the device that it is being viewed on so that it displays well and can be easily navigated.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7550" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site.jpg" alt="" width="815" height="376" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site.jpg 815w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site-450x208.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/speed-up-your-site-768x354.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 815px) 100vw, 815px" /></p>
<h3>Speed Up Your Site</h3>
<p>In an increasingly digital world, consumers want answers, and they want them fast. Search engines know this and have responded. Now, <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/page-speed">page speed is an important ranking signal for search engines</a>. There are a number of things that you can do to ensure your site is loading quickly, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use fast hosting and a quick DNS provider</li>
<li>Minimise the use of scripts and plugins on your site as much as possible</li>
<li>Try to use one CSS stylesheet rather than using multiple CSS stylesheets or inline CSS</li>
<li>Without compromising on quality, make image files on your site as small as possible</li>
<li>Compress your web pages</li>
<li>Minify the code on your site by removing any unnecessary spaces, line breaks or indentation in your HTML, CSS and Javascript</li>
</ul>
<h3>Check for Duplicate Content</h3>
<p>Search engines do not like duplicate content as it can be confusing for both users and search engine algorithms. In addition, duplicate content has previously been used as a ‘black hat’ SEO technique by marketers who are trying to manipulate search engine rankings.</p>
<p>What does this mean for your website? Any duplicate content issues should be identified and fixed as quickly as possible. There are a number of tools available that can help you to identify duplicate content issues. <a href="http://www.siteliner.com/">Siteliner</a> is one of our favourites. You can also minimise duplicate content issues by preventing your CMS from publishing multiple versions of a page or post and using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canonical_link_element">canonical link element</a> to show search engines where the ‘main’ version of your content sits.</p>
<h3>Create an XML Sitemap</h3>
<p>An XML sitemap is basically a digital roadmap that outlines exactly where each page sits on your site. Creating an XML sitemap is one of the best ways to assist a search engine in understanding your website while it is crawling it. The sitemap contains useful information about the pages on your site, such as when the page was last edited, how important the page is on your site in terms of priority and how often it is updated. Some website hosts will create your XML sitemap automatically. However, if yours doesn&#8217;t, there are a number of <a href="https://code.google.com/archive/p/sitemap-generators/wikis/SitemapGenerators.wiki">sitemap generator</a>s available to help you build one.</p>
<p>Some other important things that you can do to improve the technical SEO on your site are using SSL, enabling AMP, adding structured data mark up to your website, and registering your site with Google Search Console and Bing Webmaster Tools.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a specialist <a href="/">B2B Marketing</a> Agency with significant experience in developing and implementing campaigns across industries. We’ve worked on a number of <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a> campaigns. Get in touch with us for more information on how we can help boost your website’s ranking on the SERPs.</p>
<p>Want to proactively plan for future success? Start developing your business&#8217; strategy for next year with our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/are-you-overlooking-technical-elements-in-your-seo-strategy/">Are You Overlooking Technical Elements in Your SEO Strategy?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEO Trends to Give Digital Marketers an Edge in 2019</title>
		<link>/seo-trends-to-give-digital-marketers-an-edge-in-2019/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 01:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are over 65,000 searches conducted on Google every second. Considering nearly 80% of users ignore paid ads in search results, ranking in the top positions of the search engine results pages (SERPs) is the ideal way to boost traffic to your B2B site. In order to do this, you need a killer B2B SEO [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/seo-trends-to-give-digital-marketers-an-edge-in-2019/">SEO Trends to Give Digital Marketers an Edge in 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are over <a href="https://www.live-counter.com/google-searches/">65,000 searches conducted on Google every second</a>. Considering nearly <a href="https://seotribunal.com/blog/stats-to-understand-seo/">80% of users ignore paid ads in search results</a>, ranking in the top positions of the search engine results pages (SERPs) is the ideal way to boost traffic to your B2B site. In order to do this, you need a killer <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO strategy</a> in place.</p>
<p>The difficulty with this, however, is that SEO is always changing. Search engines are consistently working to update their algorithms so that they can deliver more accurate results for their users. As these algorithms change, certain SEO approaches become obsolete, while others become more powerful. This means that <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">SEO specialists</a> have to keep on top of these algorithm changes and alter their strategy accordingly to keep seeing results in their rankings.</p>
<p>The following are some of the SEO strategies that are going to shape the latter half of 2019 for both B2B and B2C companies. Master these tactics and your website will dominate the SERPs and generate leads and revenue for your business.</p>
<h2>Optimise for Featured Snippets &amp; Other SERP Features</h2>
<p><a href="https://searchenginewatch.com/2016/04/25/what-are-featured-snippets-and-how-do-i-get-them/">Featured snippets</a> are a type of search result on Google’s SERPs. They provide quick answers to the queries that users are searching for without them having to click through to a website to find the information. Despite the fact that featured snippets don’t require the user to click through, research from HubSpot found that business with featured snippets actually seen a dramatic increase in click-through rate (CTR).</p>
<p>Featured Snippets appear below paid ads but are most often above organic results. This position has come to be known as ‘position zero’ and it’s a good place for businesses to be as they dominate the results page. As such, appearing in featured snippets results can be more effective for driving traffic to a website than reaching position 1 on the SERPs. Going forward into 2019, we’re likely to see more competition for these coveted positions as SEO specialists start to optimise their websites to rank for featured snippets.</p>
<p>In addition to featured snippets, Google is continuously updating its search features and recipes, <a href="https://yoast.com/google-knowledge-graph/">the knowledge graph</a>, carousels, and other features are always being introduced. All of these new features will impact organic traffic for better or worse, so optimising for Google’s additional search features will be more important than ever in 2019.</p>
<h2>Look Beyond Google<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>Search Engine Optimisation is about ensuring your business appears where people are searching, and the way they are doing that is changing. At the moment, Google may be the dominant search engine, <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/search-engine-marketing/search-engine-statistics/">with almost 75% of searchers</a> preferring the search engine to its competitors. However, while optimising for Google will still be a priority in 2019, marketers may have to consider strategies that include other search platforms, such as Amazon and Apple that are starting to cut into Google’s market. As new technologies are starting to be adopted by the masses, it is no longer sufficient to simply optimise your site for Google searches. For example, optimising content for home assistant or audio-only devices (if that’s where your audience is) can be an extremely effective SEO tactic.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/keithlgoode/">According to Keith Goode, a senior SEO Strategist at IBM,</a> this basically comes down to serving the best content on the fastest platforms geared to meet the users wherever they’re coming from. The role of SEO has evolved and in order to succeed, it is necessary to optimise the entire search experience, whether that&#8217;s on web, apps, podcasts, or other technologies and ensure the content that the user find meets their expectation and fulfils their query.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7594" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Voice-Search.jpg" alt="Voice Search" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Voice-Search.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Voice-Search-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Voice-Search-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></p>
<h2>Get Ready for Voice Search</h2>
<p>Gartner has predicted that <a href="https://www.gartner.com/smarterwithgartner/gartner-predicts-a-virtual-world-of-exponential-change/">almost 30% of all web browsing will be voice activated by 2020</a>. ComScore also thinks that voice search is set to increase, expecting <a href="https://www.campaignlive.co.uk/article/just-say-it-future-search-voice-personal-digital-assistants/1392459">50% of all searches</a> to be voice activated by 2020. This will have a huge impact on the way SEO is carried out going forward. As most people do not type the way that they speak, websites that are currently optimised to rank highly on SERPs may not be as easily found by someone conducting a voice search. Another thing to be aware of going forward is that the use of voice can be very different, obviously between countries using different languages, but also the way that people speak (and search) will vary between regions, dialects and social classes.</p>
<h2>Focus on the Audience, Not the Search Engine</h2>
<p>If your website is optimised for the wrong audience it won’t grow your business. As such, the key to crafting a successful SEO strategy is to understand exactly what someone is expecting to find when they search for the keywords or phrases that lead to your site. In in order to keep users engaged on your site, you have to understand the intent behind their search query and deliver the information that they want, in the format that they want. For example, consider if your audience prefers content in the form of text, images, video or audio and ensure your landing page presents the key information in this way.</p>
<p>Considering the user’s intent behind their search query is also important for <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/semantic-search-seo/264037/">semantic search</a>. If you’re not familiar with the term, ‘semantic search’ describe Google’s process of using additional factors, other than keywords, to determine what exactly the searcher is looking for. This includes things like the searcher’s intent, the context of the query and the relationship between the words in the search phrase. Semantic search also allows Google to interpret searcher intent based on a variety of factors including their search history, location, global search history and spelling variations. The easiest way to ensure your website is optimised for semantic search, is to create content for your audience rather than the search engine. Don’t think about matching your content to keyword phrases but rather make sure that your content comprehensively answers the questions your audience is asking when they search, while still being technically optimised for SEO.</p>
<h2>Make Use of Structured Data <strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>Understanding the contextual relationships between topics and behaviour, supported by structured data markup, will be vital for SEO specialists in 2019. Structured data helps Google crawl your site faster and find the information that it is looking for easier. It is the more modern version of information architecture, tags and metadata that gives search engines signals to understand the content structure of a website. By embedding structured data directly into your website, you are helping search engines generate rich snippets, which are small pieces of information that will then appear in search results.</p>
<p>Implementing Structured Data on your website does involve HTML code, however third-party services like schema.org, as well as Google’s Structured Data Helper, make it easier for marketers.</p>
<h2>Invest in Technical SEO</h2>
<p>An effective SEO strategy will cover both on-page SEO and technical SEO factors. Marketers are getting better at the on-page, content side of SEO, according to a <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/most-common-technical-seo-mistakes/217027/">SEMrush study</a>, many websites still have significant technical issues. This is a problem for web owners as search engines are continuously crawling and indexing websites and technical issues make this much harder for them.</p>
<p>There’s no denying that websites are becoming more complex, and technical aspects are becoming more important. Some of the technical aspects that you should focus on to improve your SEO in 2019 are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Site Speed:</strong>Users want quick answers and a seamless experience online, so <a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/marketing-resources/experience-design/mobile-page-speed-load-time/">Google has long rewarded sites that load quickly</a>. Going forward, the most successful sites will become simpler and faster in order to boost their SEO performance.</li>
<li><strong>JavaScript:</strong>Search engines prefer websites that are driven by JavaScript. As such, websites are likely to become more heavily JavaScript-driven going forward and SEO specialists should become familiar with this type of programming.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>AMP</strong>: Google needs to serve sites that load fast, particularly for mobile users. Accelerated Mobile Pages significantly help boost results for mobile searchers and are likely to become more popular this year.</li>
<li><strong>Responsive Design</strong>: Responsive design ensures that the user experience (UX) is optimised for all devices, so ensuring your website is responsive is imperative an SEO strategy in the mobile-first era.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Continue to Optimise On-Page <strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>On-page optimisation significantly impacts a website’s position in the SERPs, even more than generating backlinks from other sites. However, the trap that many site owners fall into, is doing on-page SEO as a one-off when they set up a page and then forgetting about it. The most successful SEO specialists are doing <a href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/on-page-seo/">on-page optimisation</a> continuously, evaluating their on-page strategies regularly in accordance with Google’s ever-changing algorithms.</p>
<p>Some of the key things to consider when optimising your website are ensuring the on-page content answers common user questions, developing an internal site search feature that provides highly relevant results, using a chatbot to answer common questions and ensuring users can easily find physical locations. In addition, taking steps to shorten the conversion process on your can help you to generate more online leads from your SEO efforts.</p>
<p>The Lead Agency is a <a href="/">B2B Marketing Agency</a> specialising in digital strategies such as <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B Lead Generation</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/">B2B Email Marketing</a> and<a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-adwords/"> B2B adwords</a>. For more information on how we can help boost your SEO results, get in touch with us today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/seo-trends-to-give-digital-marketers-an-edge-in-2019/">SEO Trends to Give Digital Marketers an Edge in 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internal Linking: How To</title>
		<link>/internal-linking-how-to/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 01:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As defined by Moz, Internal Links are hyperlinks that point to the same domain as the domain that the link exists on. They are useful for your website for three main reasons: They help users navigate your site and establish a site hierarchy for content They spread ‘link juice’ around websites They increase a user’s [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/internal-linking-how-to/">Internal Linking: How To</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As defined by Moz, <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/internal-link">Internal Links</a> are hyperlinks that point to the same domain as the domain that the link exists on.</p>
<p>They are useful for your website for three main reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>They help users navigate your site and establish a site hierarchy for content</li>
<li>They spread ‘<a href="https://www.woorank.com/en/edu/seo-guides/link-juice">link juice</a>’ around websites</li>
<li>They increase a user’s time on page by directing them to other relevant content</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>How are Internal Links Relevant?</strong></h2>
<p>As well as being integral to your website structure, internal links are also good for your SEO strategy as Google uses internal links (as well as other factors) to help rank your content. Google crawls websites by following links using a bot called Google Bot. When the bot arrives at the homepage of a website, it starts to render the page and follows the links to work out the relationship between the various pages, posts and other content.</p>
<p>This search engine itself has confirmed this method, saying ‘Google must constantly search for new pages and add them to its list of known pages. Some pages are known because Google has already crawled them before. Other pages are discovered <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/70897?hl=en">when Google follows a link from a known page to a new page</a>.’</p>
<p>Using the right internal linking strategy can boost your SEO, as internal links give Google an idea of the structure of your website. The more links you have to a certain page, the more significant that page becomes in the eyes of Google and as such, ranks higher on the Search Engine Results Pages (SERPs).</p>
<h2><strong>What are the Benefits of Internal Link Building?</strong></h2>
<p>Internal link building is an integral part of any comprehensive SEO strategy, for the following reasons.</p>
<h3><strong>Navigation</strong></h3>
<p>Internal linking makes it easier for web users to navigate through your website and enables you to present them with additional useful information on the topic at hand. It also enables you to present other information (usually at the end of the page) that web users maybe interested in (e.g. locations of stores, or other product / service offerings).</p>
<h3><strong>Spreading Link Equity</strong></h3>
<p>Every link carries equity, also known as ‘link juice’. Link juice is a term that is used to express the value that is being passed through to pages via hyperlinks. Link juice is made up of a number of elements, which includes; value, trustworthiness, topic relevance and authority of a page. Links that pass equity or juice are one of the many signals that search engines use to evaluate and determine the page’s rankings.</p>
<h3><strong>Increase ‘Time on Page’</strong></h3>
<p>The longer the reader spends on your webpage the better, as a longer ‘Time on Page’ can indicate to search engines that your quality is relevant and engaging to the user. Having internal links directing them to other relevant pages can help readers stay engaged and wanting to explore more on your website.</p>
<h2><strong>How to Insert a Link</strong></h2>
<p>Inserting internal links into your pages and posts is very simple. The following provides a step by step ‘How to’ to ensure you can’t go wrong.</p>
<p><strong>Step 1:</strong> Log in to WordPress and navigate to the page or post that you want to add internal links to. You should see the following page.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6689" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Step1-450x304.png" alt="" width="450" height="304" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Step1-450x304.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Step1-768x519.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Step1.png 789w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p><strong>Step 2:</strong> Highlight the text you want to link to.</p>
<p><strong>Step 3:</strong> Click on the hyperlink button from the toolbar that looks like this:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6690" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Hyperlink.png" alt="Hyperlink" width="132" height="141" /></p>
<p><strong>Step 4:</strong> Once you’ve clicked on the icon, something like the below will pop up and you can paste the URL in the textbox. Once you’ve done this press enter or the blue arrow. And there’s your internal link.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6691" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/URL-450x96.png" alt="URL" width="450" height="96" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/URL-450x96.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/URL-768x164.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/URL.png 941w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p><strong>Step 5:</strong> Don’t forget to press publish when you’ve finished otherwise the internal link won’t save.</p>
<h2><strong>Remove or Edit An Internal Link</strong></h2>
<p>If you want to unlink something, simply click on the anchor text and the below ‘unlink’ option will come up. All you have to do is click on it and the link will go away;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6692" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Unlink.png" alt="" width="112" height="142" /></p>
<p>If you want to edit the current URL click the pencil icon (see below)</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6693" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Editing-URL-450x99.png" alt="Edit URL" width="450" height="99" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Editing-URL-450x99.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Editing-URL.png 639w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Anchor Text</strong></h2>
<p>Choosing the right anchor text is arguably, the most important part of your internal link strategy.</p>
<p>Anchor text is the clickable text that visitors can see in your content (usually it is highlighted, underlined or in bold). See example below:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6694" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Anchor-Text-450x407.png" alt="Anchor Text" width="450" height="407" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Anchor-Text-450x407.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Anchor-Text.png 747w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>When you are inserting internal links, its important that your anchor text is relevant to the landing page that it’s linked to. These anchor texts should be the keywords.</p>
<p>In the above example, this would be ‘B2B Content Marketing Strategy’ and ‘B2B Marketing Consultants’.</p>
<p>In most cases, don’t use one word for the anchor text. If you are unsure of the right keywords to use, conduct simple keyword research to identify the most relevant terms for your business.</p>
<h2><strong>8 Common Mistakes with Internal Linking</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Remember to make sure that the internal link that you’re using isn’t broken, otherwise there will be nowhere for the ‘link juice’ to flow to</li>
<li>Try to not have too many of the same anchor texts on the same page directing you to the same landing page (one or two should be fine per page/post)</li>
<li>You don’t have to link the keyword every time it appears in the document; you can leave some as they are</li>
<li>Make sure that if you are adding in an anchor text that it makes sense in the sentence</li>
<li>Make sure that the anchor text that you’ve used relates to the keywords on the landing page that it’s connected to</li>
<li>Don’t link the same page to multiple different keywords; 3 at most is best practice, unless the keywords are all extremely relevant and make sense in the context of the article</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Internal links are meant to benefit the reader, so that they can find more resources about a particular topic. As such, it’s important to ensure your internal links connect the user to pages and posts that are related and useful for the visitor.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Only link when it’s absolutely necessary, don’t link for the sake of linking, as it could be seen as ‘spammy’, which can work against your SEO efforts.</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6695" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Think-before-you-link-450x329.png" alt="Think before you link" width="450" height="329" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Think-before-you-link-450x329.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Think-before-you-link-768x561.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Think-before-you-link.png 872w" sizes="(max-width: 450px) 100vw, 450px" /></p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we specialise in <a href="/">B2B Marketing</a>. If your business needs help with <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B Digital Marketing</a>, or <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">B2B SEO</a>, don’t hesitate to get in touch.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/internal-linking-how-to/">Internal Linking: How To</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Optimise Your B2B Local SEO Strategy</title>
		<link>/how-to-optimise-your-b2b-local-seo-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 23:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Local Search Engine Optimisation, or local SEO, is a type of SEO that focuses on optimising a website so that it is found in local search results. As 46% of all searches on Google are seeking local information, local search is a vital component of any comprehensive Search Engine Optimisation campaign. The premise behind is the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-b2b-local-seo-strategy/">How to Optimise Your B2B Local SEO Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Local Search Engine Optimisation, or <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/local-seo/">local SEO</a>, is a type of SEO that focuses on optimising a website so that it is found in local search results. As <a href="https://seoexpertbrad.com/local-seo-stats/">46% of all searches </a>on Google are seeking local information, local search is a vital component of any comprehensive Search Engine Optimisation campaign.</p>
<p>The premise behind is the same as regular SEO. As such, optimising a page for local SEO involves the same elements as a regular SEO campaign; content, on-page optimisation, and link building, but with a focus on localised intent.</p>
<p>The big search engines, Google and Bing are continuously working to update their algorithms to ensure they are delivering the most relevant results to match the user’s search intent. In many cases, the most relevant results are local. In fact, a recent Hubspot study found that <u>46% of all Google searches are local</u>, which indicates that almost half of the time, users are looking for a local solution. As such, it’s becoming more important to optimise your website for local search.</p>
<p>Many B2B companies are put off by the term ‘local SEO’ as they often operate across the country or have branches in multiple cities. However, local SEO can optimise all the locations that your business has to attract leads and customers in that location.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://seoexpertbrad.com/local-seo-stats/">92% of searchers</a> will pick businesses on the first page of local search results</p></blockquote>
<p>Ensuring your strategy is right, or at least better than your competitors’ strategy, is essential to your success on the SERPs.</p>
<p>The first step to a winning <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/local-seo/">B2B local SEO</a> campaign is simple, and costs nothing: set up a Google My Business Account.</p>
<h2>Google My Business for Local SEO<strong><br />
</strong></h2>
<p>Despite the <a href="https://www.chatmeter.com/blog/growth-of-near-me-searches-shows-importance-of-local-seo/">massive increase in local search</a>, particularly on Google, 56% of local retailers haven’t yet claimed their Google My Business listing.</p>
<p>Claiming and optimising your Google My Business listing is the foundation of local SEO. If you are one of the 56% of businesses that haven’t claimed their listing, you’re missing out on valuable opportunities for generating leads.</p>
<h3>What is Google My Business?</h3>
<p>Google My Business is an online directory listing that connects your business directly with customers across Google, whether they’re looking for you on Search, Maps or Google+. The below screenshot shows an example of how your business may appear on the search results page with a Google My Business listing.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6684" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM.png" alt="" width="1914" height="1126" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM.png 1914w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM-450x265.png 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM-768x452.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Screen-Shot-2019-06-05-at-2.39.37-PM-1024x602.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1914px) 100vw, 1914px" /></p>
<h3>Why Use Google My Business?</h3>
<p>With a Google My Business account, your customers can find your company immediately, anywhere, on any device, and it doesn’t cost you a cent.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Be Found On Google:</strong> With such a prominent position in the search results, your business can’t afford not to set up Google My Business. If your business has multiple stores or locations, you can make use of the ‘Multiple Service Areas’ functionality, which means upon searching, your customer can find your closest location to them. This is particularly effective for mobile searchers.</li>
<li><strong>Showcase Your Business:</strong> Google My Business offers a fantastic opportunity for showcasing your <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">brand personality and values</a>. Customise your profile with a value proposition, photos, virtual tours, videos and other media to create a real point of difference from your competitors.</li>
<li><strong>Make the Most of Social Proof:</strong> Customers can review your products or services on Google My Business by giving a star rating scale and leaving a comment. Positive reviews can help your business build trust and credibility in your brand.</li>
</ul>
<p>Don’t miss out on this free marketing opportunity, claim your <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en_au/business/">Google My Business</a> listing today – and stay ahead of the 44% of your peers who still don’t have one.</p>
<h2>Other Vital Elements of Local SEO</h2>
<p>While creating a Google My Business account is an excellent starting point for a local SEO strategy, there are many more things that you can do to ensure your website is fully optimised for local search.</p>
<p>As mentioned above, local SEO isn’t hugely different from organic SEO, it still centres around keywords, content, links, on-page SEO and reviews. However, when you are optimising for local search, these strategies should have more of a local focus to ensure your business is found when people are performing these searches in the area surrounding your business. It is vital to get these elements right in order to outrank your local competitors in the SERPs.</p>
<h3>Local SEO Keyword Research<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Keyword research for local SEO is not much different from traditional <a href="https://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo/keyword-research">keyword research</a>. However, <a href="https://searchengineland.com/local-search-mobile-268208">local searches are most often performed on a mobile device</a>, such as a smartphone, Amazon Echo, or Google Home, which have voice search capabilities. <a href="/is-your-seo-strategy-ready-for-voice-search/">Voice search is shaping SEO</a> going forward and it has been predicted that by 2020 <a href="https://www.campaignlive.co.uk/article/just-say-it-future-search-voice-personal-digital-assistants/1392459">50% of all searches will be voice searches</a>. Ensuring your website is optimised for voice search is one of the ways to boost your local SEO.</p>
<p>This means, trying to optimise for conversational voice search terms like “find a financial advisor near me”. Most voice searches will be more question-focused, so when you are conducting keyword research, try to look for these terms. In addition to the Google Keyword Planner, SEMrush’s topic research tool, Keyword.io, and AnswerThePublic are great for identifying the questions people are searching for, and their search volume. Given the increase in this type of search, you should be able to find some questions that are relevant to your business, with a reasonably high search volume.</p>
<h3>Content for Local SEO <strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Locally focused content is extremely important for a local SEO strategy. As with any content that you publish, showing a depth of knowledge on the topics that you cover is essential. However, while traditional SEO best practice is to <a href="https://www.sweor.com/seocontentlength">write long-form content</a>, this won’t necessarily get results for local SEO. Local SEO is more about matching your content to the user intent behind the query, rather than getting a high word count for the query. This means applying the keyword research that you have done to find out exactly what your local customers are searching for, and then writing content around these terms that addresses and answers their queries effectively.</p>
<p>Another tip for optimising your content for local is to ensure your headlines and metadata focus on local keywords and phrases. The snippet of your web page that Google shows in the search results should let Google, and the searcher, recognise your business as a local provider.</p>
<h3>Links for Local SEO<strong><br />
</strong></h3>
<p>Firstly, it’s important to follow <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/35769?hl=en">Google’s Webmaster Guidelines</a> when considering any linking strategy, as you don’t want your link acquisition efforts to result in a penalty from Google. Any links that violate Google’s guidelines will be detected eventually, which will significantly affect your search rankings.</p>
<p>Once you know what Google likes and doesn’t like in terms of linking, you can start to define your local linking strategy. For local SEO, linking is slightly different than for organic SEO. There are various link categories that make up a quality local SEO strategy, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Citation / NAP Sites:</strong> NAP stands for Name, Address and Phone number. These details are critical for businesses that want to rank in local search results, as search engines like Google take this data into account when determining which companies to show for geo-targeted searches. There are certain citation sites where you can submit your URL and NAP details to in order to increase local search presence.</li>
<li><strong>Local Directory Websites:</strong> Focus on adding your business to local directory sites to increase relevant links to your page and give your business more chance of appearing on local search results.</li>
<li><strong>Industry-Related Local Sites:</strong> Consider other local sites that might have link opportunities, such as newspapers, schools, universities and government associations. These sites can help significantly increase the value of your local link profile.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Content for Local SEO</h3>
<p>For local SEO, it’s best practice to create a webpage for each relevant town, county, or region. By focusing a page specifically on each area that you serve, you can really boost your local search optimisation. Ensure each page speaks to the unique characteristics of the location while keeping it relevant to your business. It can also be useful to add case studies of businesses that you’ve worked within the local area to add credibility and demonstrate how your business has contributed to the community.</p>
<h3>Reviews for Local SEO</h3>
<p><a href="https://moz.com/blog/2018-local-search-ranking-factors-survey">The 2018 Local Search Ranking Factors report by Moz</a> identified online reviews as one of the top 3 most important ranking factors in local search. In fact, having review stars in Google’s search engine results pages <a href="http://localclienttakeover.com/review-stars-serps/">can improve your click-through rate by up to 35%</a>. Customers trust and value online reviews, and treat them as they would a word of mouth recommendation from a friend or family member. They want to see recent reviews of your business that are long enough to provide specific details about the products or services that they received. As such, businesses should try to encourage their satisfied customers to leave detailed reviews on platforms that are relevant to them.</p>
<p>Google is the most important source of reviews for local SEO, which can be set up through Google My Business. In addition, depending on the industry you operate in, you may also want to consider generating reviews on Citysearch, Tripadvisor, Foursquare, Facebook, Yahoo Local or Yelp.</p>
<p>The <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">marketing consultants</a> at the Lead Agency have considerable experience in developing <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/local-seo/">Local SEO campaigns</a> that generate more leads and better quality leads for our clients. Get in touch with us to find out how we can help your business today.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget to check out the other industries that we operate in; <a href="/education-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/" data-line-height="xl">Insurance Marketing</a> | <a href="/it-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Manufacturing Marketing</a> | <a href="/technology-marketing/" data-line-height="xl">Technology Marketing</a></p>
<div class="blog-share text-center"></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-optimise-your-b2b-local-seo-strategy/">How to Optimise Your B2B Local SEO Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Secret to Finding the Right Keywords for your SEO Strategy</title>
		<link>/the-secret-to-finding-the-right-keywords-for-your-seo-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 23:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Search engine optimisation is a crucial component of your organisation’s B2B digital marketing strategy. Integrating the right keywords across your online domains is at the heart of maximising your visibility, but how can you determine which ones will be the most effective? In 2017, it was found that those in the top position on Google [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-secret-to-finding-the-right-keywords-for-your-seo-strategy/">The Secret to Finding the Right Keywords for your SEO Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search engine optimisation is a crucial component of your organisation’s B2B digital marketing strategy. Integrating the right keywords across your online domains is at the heart of maximising your visibility, but how can you determine which ones will be the most effective?</p>
<blockquote><p><em>In 2017, it was found that those in the top position on Google search had an </em><a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/2018/04/keyword-research-trends/"><em>average click through rate</em></a><em> of 21%, whereas second and third generated 10% and 7.5% respectively.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Search engine optimisation is highly relevant to those operating in the B2B sector, with their target market typically facing far more <a href="https://marketing-insider.eu/b2b-market-characteristics/">complex buyer decisions</a> than other consumers. This is often due to the scale and cost of their purchases as well as the extensive technical considerations that must be taken into account during their customer journey.</p>
<p>For this reason, it’s crucial that you’re able to effectively and directly reach your B2B audience to boost awareness and reassure them that you can meet their distinct needs.</p>
<p>By identifying the most appropriate keywords for your business and integrating them into your content you have the opportunity to optimise your search ranking and, as a result of this, enhance reach.</p>
<h2><strong>The Process of Keyword Research</strong></h2>
<p>When identifying the best keywords for your business, there’re a number of useful tools that can help to streamline the process.</p>
<p>Start by narrowing down a list of terms that are highly relevant to your business and its offering, these can often be found on your website. Once your list has been refined, the identified terms can be entered into <a href="https://www.semrush.com/">SEMRUSH</a>. This tool helps you track which keywords your website is currently ranking well for, and which don’t offer sufficient value.</p>
<p>Another beneficial domain to use when conducting keyword research is <a href="https://ads.google.com/intl/en_au/home/">Google Ads</a>’ Keyword Tool. This tool allows you to enter multiple keyword phrase suggestions and then provides you with a list of the keywords that are of the highest relevance. These results can be arranged in terms of average monthly searches, showing which keywords consumers are most commonly using.</p>
<p>When using Google Ads’ Keyword Tool, you’re able to compare the monetary value of each keyword as well as their level of competitiveness. It’s essential to take this into consideration when making your keyword choices, as opposed to purely focusing on the amount of monthly views each keyword receives.</p>
<p>Typically, keywords that have a higher cost per click are more sought after by those placing advertisements. By identifying these terms your business has the opportunity to leverage well-ranking keywords, enhancing your SEO and increasing your position in competitive search results.</p>
<p>Whether you use SEMRUSH and then enter the keywords found into Google Ads, or just search exclusively on one of these domains, such tools can offer your business immense value when researching keywords.</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong> </strong></p>
<h2><strong>Our Top Tips for Choosing the Right Keywords</strong></h2>
<h4><strong>1. Know your Customer</strong></h4>
<p>It’s important to gain a sound understanding of your target audience and their behaviour. You need to determine the language they’re likely to use when searching for your type of offering on Google, so that you can include these unique terms in your content.</p>
<p>Essentially, it all comes down to clearly defining commonalities in the way your target audience thinks and acts. Conducting thorough research of your market can assist in doing this, as can tools such as SEMRUSH and Google Ads.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4><strong>2. Examine your Competitors</strong></h4>
<p><em>What are other businesses in your industry doing?</em></p>
<p>When determining which keywords would be best for your organisation, <a href="https://writtent.com/blog/7-secrets-to-finding-the-best-keywords/#comments">looking to your competition</a> can offer valuable insights. By doing this, you can identify what’s working for them and decide whether there are any opportunities for you to optimise your keyword usage in a similar way.</p>
<p>A great starting point is making a list of your key competitors and visiting their websites to discover the keywords that they’re targeting. This research can help to broaden your own ideas, and assists in building an extensive list of effective keywords relevant to your sector.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4><strong>3. Leverage Long-Tail Keywords</strong></h4>
<p>Long-tail keywords are short phrases that include three to five terms. As they’re generally less competitive than shorter keywords, they can prove to be highly effective when trying to increase your search engine ranking.</p>
<p>Long-tail keywords are typically less sought after, meaning that they offer a cost effective and low risk solution to boosting your search engine optimisation.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Long tail SEO accounts for 70% of searches” – </em><a href="https://www.commonplaces.com/blog/5-tips-on-choosing-the-right-keywords/"><em>Common Places Interactive</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>When consumers use long-tail keywords, it’s likely that they have a good idea of what exactly they’re looking for. So even though the search volume is generally lower than that of one or two keywords, you’re able to attract highly targeted traffic with serious purchase intention.</p>
<h2><strong>Want to find out more?</strong></h2>
<p>For more information about keyword research, or to speak to an experienced marketing professional, please do not hesitate to <a href="/contact-us/">get in contact</a> with the Lead Agency today. We’re experts in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a>, and can help your business improve the effectiveness of your current <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategy</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-secret-to-finding-the-right-keywords-for-your-seo-strategy/">The Secret to Finding the Right Keywords for your SEO Strategy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Black Hat Vs White Hat SEO &#8211; How to Optimise Your Online Visibility</title>
		<link>/black-hat-vs-white-hat-seo-how-to-optimise-your-online-visibility/</link>
					<comments>/black-hat-vs-white-hat-seo-how-to-optimise-your-online-visibility/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=5958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Search Engine Optimisation – is your current approach improving or hindering your business’ online visibility? Chances are that your organisation is now operating in an extensive and highly competitive marketplace and, if consumers can’t find your business online, you risk potential customers deciding to look elsewhere. As such, to achieve success and increase traffic flow [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/black-hat-vs-white-hat-seo-how-to-optimise-your-online-visibility/">Black Hat Vs White Hat SEO &#8211; How to Optimise Your Online Visibility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search Engine Optimisation – is your current approach improving or hindering your business’ online visibility?</p>
<p>Chances are that your organisation is now operating in an extensive and highly competitive marketplace and, if consumers can’t find your business online, you risk potential customers deciding to look elsewhere. As such, to achieve success and increase traffic flow on digital platforms, maximising your online visibility is essential.</p>
<p>In a bid to enhance accessibility online, organisations are now actively working to maximise their search result ranking.</p>
<p>You may have an incredible offering but, if your desired customers are unable to find you, how will they ever know?</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“The top five results account for <a href="https://searchenginewatch.com/2016/01/21/seo-basics-22-essentials-you-need-for-optimizing-your-site/">67.60% of all clicks</a>” </em></p></blockquote>
<p><em>So, how can your business optimise search engine visibility?</em></p>
<p>There’s a distinct range of strategies that are commonly used by organisations aiming to improve their online accessibility, each with varying degrees of effectiveness.</p>
<p>Some of the typical approaches instigated by businesses can be categorised as either a white or black hat tactic. There is a clearly defined division between the strategies applied in each scenario and, essentially, they’re polar opposites.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>WHITE HAT VS BLACK HAT SEO</h2>
<h4>White Hat SEO</h4>
<p>Those who fall into the White Hat category are approaching Search Engine Optimisation in what is typically recognised as the ethical, correct way.</p>
<p>White Hat tactics have a human focus and an emphasis on creating quality content that is <a href="https://unamo.com/university/what-is-the-difference-between-white-hat-seo-and-black-hat-seo">highly relevant</a> to your webpage.</p>
<p>When implementing strategies to improve their visibility, these businesses are acting within the guidelines and, importantly, playing by Google’s rules.</p>
<p>A White Hat approach involves adjusting online content to meet the ever-changing preferences of Google’s search engine algorithm, rather than looking for loopholes.</p>
<p>For this reason, the strategies applied have the potential to be highly advantageous when aiming for long-term optimisation. Each time Google introduces an update of their search engine algorithm, there is a focus on identifying and penalising Black Hat tactics. When this happens, if your business is operating within guidelines there’s less of a chance that your search ranking will be dramatically impacted and disadvantaged.</p>
<p>That being said, it’s still within your best interest to adjust your current strategies accordingly, ensuring you meet new expectations and truly maximise the visibility of your business.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Black Hat SEO</h4>
<p>Businesses who implement a Black Hat SEO strategy are operating on the opposite end of the spectrum. They aim to find ways around Google’s algorithm, violating guidelines in a way that will boost their position in search engine results.</p>
<p>The tactics used are typically bot focused, looking to manipulate and essentially “trick” the algorithm by identifying weaknesses as opposed to creating quality, relevant content.</p>
<p>This approach has a very apparent aspect of risk, with the strategies being implemented typically <a href="https://optinmonster.com/white-hat-vs-black-hat-seo/">detected eventually</a>. Therefore, even though such tactics may see results in the short-term, once a new algorithm addressing the issue is introduced, your business is likely to plummet in search engine rankings.</p>
<p>It’s vital to think about the long-term development of your SEO when defining a strategy, as opposed to purely focusing on “quick wins” where you risk being substantially penalised in future.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>WHAT KIND OF STRATEGIES DOES EACH HAT INVOLVE?</h2>
<h4>White Hat SEO</h4>
<p>To maximise your online search results ranking without violating Google’s guidelines, what kind of tactics would your business need to implement?</p>
<p>A great starting point is to ensure that the content you’re sharing online is original, <a href="https://www.crazyegg.com/blog/seo/black-hat-vs-white-hat-seo/">valuable</a> to your target audience and accurate. This is essential as White Hat tactics typically have a human focus, improving your ranking by creating a comprehensive and functional website. By building a quality digital platform, you’re naturally helping to improve your website’s relevance by complying with Google’s algorithm.</p>
<p>It’s vital to partake in appropriate research and determine which keywords your business should include on different webpages. In doing so, you’ll be able to make the conscious effort to include particular language and, as a result of this, improve the overall relevance of your webpage &#8211; boosting your search engine results ranking. However, it’s crucial to ensure that your webpages aren’t overly crowded with keywords; this will be negatively received by Google’s algorithm.</p>
<p>How else can your business improve your websites relevance online? You could try using <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/white-vs-black-hat-seo-what-is-the-difference/183088/#close">backlinks</a>, a tactic that can prove to be highly beneficial when used correctly. The effective use of backlinks relies on related webpages linking back to yours. As such, the algorithm used by Google recognises that others have identified your content as valuable, therefore, increasing your overall relevance.</p>
<p>When your webpage makes reference to and creates a link between your own content, this is known as an internal link. This particular tactic also assists in boosting your relevance and, similarly to the use of keywords, is generally ineffective when overused. In short, don’t go overboard!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Black Hat SEO</h4>
<p>When it comes to long-term Search Engine Optimisation, it will likely benefit your business to steer clear of Black Hat tactics and stick to Google’s guidelines.</p>
<p>So, what kind of strategies is your business best to avoid?</p>
<p>Similarly to using an excessive amount of keywords on your webpage, including irrelevant content or keywords can be harmful to your search ranking. It all comes back to Google’s algorithm favouring your page if the content is perceived as valuable. Even though it may be tempting to include certain popular keywords or phrases to boost your ranking, it’s likely these will be picked up and your long-term SEO will suffer.</p>
<p>What if you could show consumers one thing, and optimise your relevance by showing search engine technology another? Well, you can. It’s called cloaking and, being illegal; it’s a practice we definitely wouldn’t recommend. Those using this technique online mislead the Google algorithm and, as a result of this, boost their webpages’ ranking.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Overtime, we’ve seen sites try to maximise their “search footprint” without adding clear, unique value.” &#8211; <a href="https://searchengineland.com/google-to-launch-new-doorway-page-penalty-algorithm-216974">Google&#8217;s Brian White</a> </em></p></blockquote>
<p>Another common Black Hat technique is the use of Doorway Pages. This involves a number of similar domains being created with the purpose of linking back to a particular page, thus, increasing its relevance. In combating such practice, Google has introduced an updated search algorithm to identify and penalise websites creating doorway pages.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Interested in improving your B2B Search Engine Optimisation?</h2>
<p>At The Lead Agency, our team specialises in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">digital marketing</a> and <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-seo/">b2b seo services</a>. Get in contact with us today for guidance in maximising your online visibility through White Hate techniques that will continue to succeed through Google’s algorithm updates.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget to check out our other industries; <a href="/education-marketing/">Education Marketing</a> | <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">Financial Services Marketing</a> | <a href="/industrial-marketing/">Industrial Marketing</a> | <a href="/insurance-marketing-2/">Insurance Marketing</a> |<a href="/it-marketing/"> IT Marketing</a> | <a href="/law-firm-marketing/">Law Firm Marketing</a> | <a href="/manufacturing-marketing/">Manufacturing Marketing</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/black-hat-vs-white-hat-seo-how-to-optimise-your-online-visibility/">Black Hat Vs White Hat SEO &#8211; How to Optimise Your Online Visibility</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/black-hat-vs-white-hat-seo-how-to-optimise-your-online-visibility/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
