<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Financial Services Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<atom:link href="/financial-services-marketing-blogs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>B2B Marketing Agency &#124; Digital Lead Generation campaigns and company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 07:19:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-AU</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-TLA-ico-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Financial Services Marketing Archives &ndash; The Lead Agency</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Financial Services Marketing Trends &#038; How to Prepare for Them</title>
		<link>/financial-services-marketing-trends-how-to-prepare-for-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 01:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Services Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The financial services sector is incredibly competitive, so when it comes to differentiating your business and attracting valuable prospects, marketing is crucial. “71% of financial services organisations plan to increase their digital marketing spend in the year to come.” Along with helping you build a strong B2B brand, developing a comprehensive marketing strategy can assist [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/financial-services-marketing-trends-how-to-prepare-for-them/">Financial Services Marketing Trends &#038; How to Prepare for Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The financial services sector is incredibly competitive, so when it comes to differentiating your business and attracting valuable prospects, marketing is crucial.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://www.cmo.com/features/articles/2017/3/10/financial-services-marketing-stats-mbs-tlp.html#gs.43c192"><em>71% of financial services organisations</em></a><em> plan to increase their digital marketing spend in the year to come.”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Along with helping you build a strong <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/b2b-branding/">B2B brand</a>, developing a comprehensive marketing strategy can assist your company in effectively positioning yourself as an industry leader.</p>
<p>If you want to truly optimise your <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial service company’s</a> investment in marketing, it’s essential that you stay up-to-date on the latest trends. However, this certainly doesn’t mean jumping on board with every tactic that’s recommended to you. Instead, you need to understand the changing business landscape and leverage your knowledge to construct highly relevant, targeted strategies. Whether this involves looking at what your competitors are doing, reading reliable industry sources or collecting and analysing data, such information is vital. This will assist your <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial services business</a> in establishing a sound marketing strategy for now, while also aiding in your ability to proactively plan for future endeavours.</p>
<h2>The Growing Prominence of Digital Technologies</h2>
<p>Digital capabilities are becoming an increasingly important component of many company’s business strategies, and for businesses providing financial services, this is not different. In a recent survey, <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/industry/financial-services/digital-transformation-in-financial-services.html">90% of respondents</a> said they believe that the <a href="https://www.thedubs.com/5-hard-truths-about-financial-services-and-digital-marketing/">financial industry is being disrupted</a> by the evolution of digital technologies. However, less than half of those surveyed feel as though they’re adequately prepared to meet the demands of these new digital pressures.</p>
<p><em>So, what does this mean for your business?</em></p>
<p>In most scenarios, this change will equate to one of two things, depending on how your financial services business reacts.</p>
<h4>Scenario #1</h4>
<p>The first is that you’ll be unresponsive and, consequently, end up being left behind in the rush. As your competitors evolve and adjust their processes to improve efficiencies and satisfy the ever-changing needs of consumers, you’ll remain relatively stagnate. If at some point you decide to start adopting digital technologies, your team will likely still be a step behind everyone else. While your competitors are already planning for the future and developing proactive strategies, you might find yourself stuck playing catch-up.</p>
<h4>Scenario #2</h4>
<p>Alternatively, let’s say you make integrating digital technologies a priority. Once having effectively incorporated them into your company, you can start thinking about what’s next. With strong foundational systems in place, you’ll be able to dedicate more time towards building innovative, proactive plans for future endeavours. This can, in turn, help you improve your responsiveness to new advances, all the while remaining competitive in an incredibly volatile market.</p>
<p>The digital era is already here, so if you’re yet to adapt, the time to act is now. With reliable systems in place that leverage digital technologies you can improve processes, enhance the customer experience and boost engagement.</p>
<h2>Improving the Customer Experience is Becoming Increasingly Important</h2>
<p>Your target audience isn’t always going to be familiar with the technicalities of your offering. It’s for this reason that, when comparing different financial commodities, consumers will often have difficulty differentiating between divergent products.</p>
<p>Thus, it’s crucial that your financial services company establishes a unique point-of-difference, conveying to prospects why your offering is the ideal solution for their needs. By focusing strongly on <a href="https://econsultancy.com/2019-financial-services-trends-fsi/">improving the customer experience</a> and adding new, unexpected value to the purchasing process you can do just that.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“</em><a href="https://thefinancialbrand.com/82143/financial-digital-marketing-trends-2020/"><em>79% of consumers</em></a><em> say the experience a company provides is as important as its products or services.”</em></p></blockquote>
<h4><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7520" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Leveraging-Data.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Leveraging-Data.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Leveraging-Data-450x185.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Leveraging-Data-768x316.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></h4>
<h4>Leveraging Data to Enrich The Customer Experience</h4>
<p>Interested in improving the customer experience, but not sure where to begin?</p>
<p>Collecting and analysing data is a great starting point, giving you valuable insights into how your financial services business is performing and where adjustments to your current processes are required. Data can provide your <a href="/b2b-marketing-strategies/">B2B marketing strategies</a> with clear, researched direction, all the while helping you optimise your campaigns.</p>
<p>By defining and examining the stages that consumer’s progress through when making a purchase, you can pinpoint certain areas where individuals disengage. Once you’re aware of these, you can develop tactics to target and address barriers in the customer journey and, ultimately, reignite prospects’ interest in your brand.</p>
<p>Personalisation is key in modern marketing campaigns, but if you don’t know your target audience, your efforts to improve their experience with your company could be completely misguided.</p>
<p>This is where the effective use of data becomes all the more important.</p>
<p>The information you discover by analysing data can be applied to build comprehensive customer personas. These distinct groups you’ve identified can then be targeted using personalisation tactics, allowing you to tailor the buyer journey to their differing needs and priorities.</p>
<p>By developing a thoughtful, value-driven customer experience, financial services organisations can improve their ability to attract new leads, drive conversions and boost customer retention.</p>
<p>At the Lead Agency, we’re experts in <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/">B2B digital marketing</a>, <a href="/lead-generation/">B2B lead generation</a>, <a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-digital-content-marketing/">B2B content marketing</a> and more. For more information about <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial services marketing</a>, or to start preparing your business for <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends, get in touch with our team today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/financial-services-marketing-trends-how-to-prepare-for-them/">Financial Services Marketing Trends &#038; How to Prepare for Them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Generate Referrals In Financial Services</title>
		<link>/how-to-generate-referrals-in-financial-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim McNeil]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 01:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Services Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While it falls under the umbrella of ‘B2B Marketing,’ financial services marketing is different from other forms of B2B Marketing. An effective B2B financial services marketing strategy will breakdown the complicated products and services that are offered by financial services firms into digestible pieces of information that are easy for the user to understand. With [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-generate-referrals-in-financial-services/">How to Generate Referrals In Financial Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While it falls under the umbrella of ‘B2B Marketing,’ financial services marketing is different from other forms of B2B Marketing. An effective B2B <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial services marketing</a> strategy will breakdown the complicated products and services that are offered by financial services firms into digestible pieces of information that are easy for the user to understand.</p>
<p>With financial services marketing, it is also particularly important to ensure your marketing strategies will help you retain customers. When you effectively retain customers and continue to exceed their expectations and add value to their business, they are more likely to recommend your services to a peer. This is an extremely effective marketing tactic for financial services firms as <a href="http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/insights/news/2013/under-the-influence-consumer-trust-in-advertising.html">people are four times more likely to buy when referred by a friend. </a></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>Why Referral Marketing Is so Effective</strong></h2>
<p><a href="http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/insights/news/2013/under-the-influence-consumer-trust-in-advertising.html">84% of consumers say they either completely or somewhat trust recommendations from family, colleagues, and friends about products – making these recommendations the information source ranked highest for trustworthiness</a>.</p>
<p>Referrals, or business introductions, are key to generating leads for financial services businesses. Getting these referrals, however, isn’t always easy. While asking for referrals comes naturally to some in the financial industry, others don’t find it so easy. Sometimes, it’s simply the case that the thought of asking a client, friend or colleague for a referral hasn’t even occurred to them.</p>
<h2><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7528" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Generate-Referrals.jpg" alt="" width="850" height="500" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Generate-Referrals.jpg 850w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Generate-Referrals-450x265.jpg 450w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Generate-Referrals-768x452.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /></h2>
<h2><strong>How to Generate Referrals</strong></h2>
<p>Introductions can come from a number of different sources. In most cases, people who trust your ability to provide the financial services that you specialise in will be happy to refer your name.</p>
<p>The following are some of the simplest ways to generate referrals that can be incorporated into your existing daily business routine.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mention Referrals Early in the Business Conversation: </strong>When you start working with a new client and are discussing what your business is about and how you work, it can be a good time to tell them how important referrals are to your business. If you mention right at the start that you’d appreciate the opportunity to be introduced to other businesses, they are more likely to do it once you’ve done a great job for them.</li>
<li><strong>Follow Up on Positive Feedback: </strong>If you receive an email or phone call from a particularly happy customer praising your work, you can simply respond by thanking them for their feedback and asking if they’d happen to know of others who could benefit from your business’ services.</li>
<li><strong>Set A Referral Goal: </strong>If you’ve been considering a referral scheme but don’t have the motivation to get started, it can be helpful to set a referral goal. For example, aim to get two referrals each week. Make sure you record all your referrals and who they are from so that you can follow up and thank them if you are successful.</li>
<li><strong>Be Specific:</strong> It’s important to tell your client or peer exactly what you are looking for when you ask for a referral. If you’re looking for clients of a certain size or if you specialise in a specific niche, then make sure that you mention it. It’s important to tell the person you are asking exactly <a href="https://thrivehive.com/how-to-identify-your-target-audience/">who your target audience is</a> so that you don’t waste time following up on referrals that are not relevant to your business.</li>
<li><strong>Ensure You Provide Exceptional Service: </strong>You won’t be successful in generating referrals unless you are offering something that is of superior value to your customer. You have to ensure the quality of your service is above and beyond so that your client is confident in referring you.</li>
<li><strong>Develop a Referral System: </strong>Reciprocity is key to referrals. If you can give a referral to one of your clients, they will be more likely to refer you in return. In addition, if you can help your clients by referring them to someone else, they will be even happier with the value that you provide their business, which will boost your reputation.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Create a Customer Loyalty Program: </strong>Loyal customers are more likely to become brand evangelists and are more likely to refer other clients to your business. By developing and maintaining a customer loyalty program that incentivises customers to keep coming back, they are more likely to tell others to do the same.</li>
<li><strong>Network: </strong>Try to make the most out of every networking opportunity that you come across. It can be useful to plan out what you will say about your business in advance and make sure that you speak to at least three people at each event. When you speak to someone who trusts you and what your business provides, they may enquire about your services themselves, or pass on your details to someone else that they know who may be interested.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are many factors to be considered when, and if, you ask for referrals for your financial services business. The above are just ideas that may help you. For more information on generating referrals, or for help with your wider <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial services marketing strategy</a>, get in touch with the <a href="/">B2B marketing</a> specialists at the Lead Agency.</p>
<p>Want to proactively plan for future success? Start developing your business&#8217; strategy for next year with our blog on <a href="/b2b-marketing-2020-trends/">B2B marketing 2020</a> trends.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/how-to-generate-referrals-in-financial-services/">How to Generate Referrals In Financial Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Ways to Optimise Marketing in the Financial Industry</title>
		<link>/5-ways-to-optimise-marketing-in-the-financial-industry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emily Vale]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Services Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=6053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>“The Financial Services Industry has been extremely slow in modernising their marketing in step with changing consumer behaviour” – Marketo The financial industry is continually evolving and, as such, it’s essential that your business is responsive to these changes. A detrimental aspect of your organisational strategy, of which many working in finance often overlook, is [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-ways-to-optimise-marketing-in-the-financial-industry/">5 Ways to Optimise Marketing in the Financial Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>“The Financial Services Industry has been extremely slow in modernising their marketing in step with changing consumer behaviour” – </em><em><a href="https://blog.marketo.com/2013/07/how-digital-marketing-is-reshaping-financial-services.html">Marketo</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>The financial industry is continually evolving and, as such, it’s essential that your business is responsive to these changes. A detrimental aspect of your organisational strategy, of which many working in finance often overlook, is marketing.</p>
<p>Developing a strong <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial services marketing</a> approach can assist you in attracting valuable new leads to your business, while also retaining current clients. Understanding your customers’ distinct needs and wants is at the heart of effectively targeting them and, essentially, can help you achieve a competitive advantage.</p>
<p>When determining the best B2B marketing tactic for your business, it’s crucial to develop a comprehensive understanding of the modern financial industry.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>1. Build Long-Term Relationships</strong></h2>
<p>As a financial business, your interactions and ongoing development of rapport with clients are of significant importance. Focusing on the individual customer is central in achieving this and relationship marketing is key.</p>
<p>When you truly understand your target markets’ unique expectations you’re able to establish meaningful relationships, ensure that you’re meeting their distinct needs, deliver exceptional value and maximise their loyalty.</p>
<p>Building long-term relationships with your customers encourages return business, which is typically far more cost-effective for organisations than attracting new clients.</p>
<p>If particularly satisfied with your service customers may also choose to share their great experience with others, generating positive word-of-mouth and directing new customers your way.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>2. Find a Strategic Position</strong></h2>
<p>How can you differentiate your financial business from others?</p>
<p>In the financial industry, it’s important to build a strong brand that is clearly communicated with your target market. You need to be constantly looking for opportunities to truly stand out from your competition and create memorable, relevant content.</p>
<p>A great starting point is to research your market and competitors in the financial industry, using the information found to identify current or potential issues and how your business could solve them. In doing this, you can develop a unique value proposition and strategically position yourself in the industry.</p>
<p>It’s then essential to convey a clear and consistent image of your financial business to customers, leaving a lasting image of why your offering will meet their needs like no other.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>3. Simplify Processes</strong><strong> </strong></h2>
<p>Finances can be confusing. A crucial aspect of your marketing as a business in the financial industry is to develop clear, simplified processes for consumers and to communicate these clearly with them.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Remove steps, minimise forms, add confidence builders and ensure progress is clearly signposted for the prospective customer to </em><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/steveolenski/2015/02/18/5-lessons-learned-in-marketing-from-the-financial-industry/#720f41d07666"><em>minimise drop-out</em></a><em>”</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Making your target markets’ experience a little less daunting could be as simple as creating an easily accessible and navigable website. When consumers reach your online domain, they’re not as likely to experience confusion and be deterred from continuing their customer journey.</p>
<p>Simplifying processes removes various potential barriers for consumers and, essentially, facilitates your ability to generate more valuable new leads and truly nurture them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>4. Know Your Customers</strong></h2>
<p>Marketing in the financial industry is particularly unique when compared to other forms of business-to-business marketing. As such, it’s of considerable importance that you do your research and figure out exactly who your target customer is so that you can market to their distinct needs.</p>
<p>An individuals’ management of their finances is arguably <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kimberlywhitler/2018/04/17/marketing-in-the-financial-services-industry/#17cfaaea1673">far more personal</a> than the purchase of most tangible offerings. Consumers are therefore likely to take greater precautions, and these can create additional barriers in their customer journey.</p>
<p>It’s essential to ensure the content you’re creating is highly tailored, relevant and applicable to your target market to truly engage their business. To achieve this, it’s crucial to have a comprehensive understanding of their specific expectations and needs in the financial industry.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>5. Be Proactive</strong></h2>
<blockquote><p><em>“45 per cent of financial service report their marketing is conducted on an “ad hoc” basis” – </em><em><a href="https://www.globalbankingandfinance.com/5-marketing-strategies-for-financial-industries/">Global Banking and Finance</a></em></p></blockquote>
<p>How often does your financial business assess whether your current B2B marketing strategies are still performing well, or if there are new opportunities you could get on board with?</p>
<p>To conduct marketing on an “ad hoc” basis is to only do so when necessary. If your organisation is interested in gaining exceptional results from your marketing efforts it’s essential to be proactive and, instead, update your strategic approach regularly.</p>
<p>By continually monitoring the effectiveness of your marketing, you’ll be able to identify potential areas of improvement and truly optimise your investment. This gives your business the opportunity to remain relevant in the current industry and, essentially, gain a competitive edge by staying ahead of the game.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Interested in developing a strong <a href="/b2b-marketing-services/">B2B marketing strategy</a>? At the Lead Agency, we can help. For professional assistance in <a href="/financial-services-marketing/">financial services marketing</a>, contact our expert team today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/5-ways-to-optimise-marketing-in-the-financial-industry/">5 Ways to Optimise Marketing in the Financial Industry</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</title>
		<link>/six-steps-account-based-marketing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrew Silcox]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[B2B Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Financial Services Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Search Engine Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So, you’ve heard of Account Based Marketing and want to know what all the fuss is about? Well, you’ve come to right place. In this article, we’re going to outline what Account Based Marketing is and how you can use it in your business. Account Based Marketing was initially developed to solve the B2B problem [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/six-steps-account-based-marketing/">The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, you’ve heard of Account Based Marketing and want to know what all the fuss is about? Well, you’ve come to right place. In this article, we’re going to outline what Account Based Marketing is and how you can use it in your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing was initially developed to solve the B2B problem of multiple decision makers being involved in a purchase. Rarely is there ever just one sole decision maker in a business deciding what product to buy &#8211; there can be anywhere up to a dozen decision makers in any one account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing can offer a lot to B2B enterprises looking to improve their ROI. According to research from the</span><a href="https://au.marketo.com/account-based-marketing/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Altera Group</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, “97% [of B2B businesses] had a somewhat higher or much higher ROI than other marketing initiatives.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whereas traditional lead generation is akin to fishing with a net, ABM is the equivalent of fishing with a spear. Rather than general broadcasts, you are focused on winning over key accounts. Adjusting to the demands can be difficult at first, but ABM tends to have better results, especially for B2B marketers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, how do you know who to contact? How do you personalise interactions with each decision maker? Read on for a step-by-step method to unlocking complex B2B accounts!</span></p>
<h2><b>How Does Account Based Marketing Differ From The Traditional Sales Pipeline Approach?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing may seem a little alien to those used to employing a sales pipeline. Metrics such as the number of qualified leads, prospects and other such demarcations don’t easily fit the Account-Based Marketing model.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the biggest differences is that Account Based Marketing is about creating quality relationships with a few key influencers and decision makers, as opposed to playing a numbers game hoping to attract significant numbers of qualified leads. You will also find that, given the low volume of accounts, you will not be able to use traditional funnel metrics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The longer sales cycles will impact what types of metrics you should focus on. Given your objective is to build stronger relationships over time, engagement becomes an increasingly important metric to use.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing means that sales and marketing have to work closely together to generate real results. Demonstrating value then becomes increasingly important.</span></p>
<h2><b>What Are The Benefits of Account Based Marketing?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account-Based Marketing doesn’t mean you have to start from scratch with your existing marketing. So long as your have your executive on board, have a good team of people and  are able to align your sales and marketing, you will find that this type of marketing will slot in nicely with your existing marketing strategies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Big businesses are run by individuals, if you can harness the power of scaled personalisation, you will find that you will be able to develop one-to-one communication quite easily.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the benefits of employing Account Based Marketing is a higher Return On Investment (ROI), better relationships with existing clients, and better alignment between your sales and marketing departments.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4618 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/findingyouraccount.jpg" alt="Find Your Account" width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h2><b>Step 1. Find Your Account</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Create a list of target accounts and then organise them according to a tiered structure. Once you have your list, you want establish how much of a percentage of your time you wish to dedicate to each tier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You may wish to have three tiers set up:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first tier contains those accounts that you believe are worth investing more time in researching, developing personalised touchpoint and investing in long-term. Tactics may include heavy targeting by sales and significant support. (20-50)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second tier might be accounts you see merit in, but are not willing to spend a significant amount time in pursuing. You may choose to use tactics that are less time intensive, such as direct mail and phone calls. (200-500)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The third tier will be accounts that are in your general periphery but not your focus. General marketing automation and limited personalisation would apply to this group. (2000-5000)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Establishing your list of accounts is a fine balance between art and science. Use any data you have access to to establish the viability of prospects and whom you should priortise.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 2. Map Out Who The Decision Makers Are</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you have your list of accounts it’s time to get started building some generalised personas to represent different members of the teams. Yet again, prioritise these accounts according to key stakeholders, and lower influence team members.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now comes the nitty-gritty of researching each target account and mapping out their staff individually. Attach your persona profiles to each contact and start building a comprehensive database. Tools for developing this could be LinkedIn, or even going through a data vendor.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 3. Research The Account</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now comes the time to get research done on the accounts as whole. You will need to find out the following:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who their target market is?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their mission, vision and values?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their culture and agenda?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The work dynamic within the organisation?</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are there any existing connections to the account?</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This research can come from conversations, surveys, stalking their website and social media or even just general market data.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4618 size-large" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/createcontent.jpg" alt="Relevant Content " width="800" height="380" /></p>
<h2><b>Step 4. Create Relevant Content</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Creating content that is going to resonate with your different accounts is the next step. We don’t suggest you create specific content for each account but have a wide range of content that varies in its level of personalisation depending on the importance of the account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the higher end of this spectrum is content specifically for one account, at the lower end is generic broad content and in between might be content targeted towards certain industries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Changing the title, feature picture and headline may be all that is needed to personalise content. If you have the time and see value in a particular prospect, you may wish to spend time labouring over some more specific content.</span></p>
<h2><b>Step 5. Decide On Your Tactics For Interaction</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is where all your hard work and research can finally be put to use. Now you have your accounts, and you know who you are targeting within each account, you can begin to reach out to your prospects.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Account Based Marketing interactions are unique in that you are applying inbound two-way communication and sharing of relevant content to an outbound marketing strategy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some tactics you may wish to employ may include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Hosting Events </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Create, or simply host, business networking events. These events allow your sales team to get direct access to those accounts they are targeting.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Direct Mail </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; In a digital world, physical mail is more likely to cut through the clutter. Creating personalised direct mail campaigns to target priority accounts is a great way to open doors.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="/b2b-digital-marketing/b2b-email-marketing/"><b>Email Marketing </b></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; You may have general eNewsletters accounts can subscribe to, however, if you want to build two-way communication, consider avoiding smart looking templates and using more text-based personal emails.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Digital Advertising </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; Use retargeting, personalised search and social media paid advertising to get to your audience. LinkedIn, for example, allows you to target your posts exclusively to certain demographics.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Free Webinars </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Host relevant and interesting webinars to get the attention of account-holders. By creating personalised invitations to events you are also able to make a good impression.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Step 6. Progress Your Strategy</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now the campaign is up and running, consider what your game plan is going to be. Rather than traditional tactics of broadcasting to a wide net and hoping some stick, you need to be very specific in your planning. Have a marketing flow chart prepared with the list of the different channels and tactics you plan to employ for each account.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are two things you need to consider when building your strategy. The first is how long you plan to run your campaign for and how often you plan to post. The second is creating a strategy employing a diverse range of integrated channels.</span></p>
<h2><b>Summary</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are interested in ABM marketing and looking for assistance employing it for your B2B business, please contact <a href="/">The Lead Agency</a>. Our expert <a href="/b2b-marketing-consultants/">B2B Marketing Consultants</a> are generating leads and prospects for your business and building strong, resilient ties with them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more information about the impact Account Based Marketing is having on <a href="/">B2B marketing</a>, try reading this article on</span><a href="/account-based-marketing-revolutionising-b2b/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">How Account Based Marketing Is Revolutionising B2B</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<noscript class="ninja-forms-noscript-message">
    Notice: JavaScript is required for this content.</noscript><style>

        /* PLUGIN WIDE STYLES */
    
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container.textarea-container .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    height:100px!important;
                    }
    </style><style>

        /* FORM STYLES */
    
        #nf-form-2_1-cont {
                                    background-color:#e74c3c;
                                            padding:10px;
                                                    box-shadow: -webkit-box-shadow: 4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);
-moz-box-shadow:    4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);
box-shadow:         4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);                    }
        #nf-form-2_1-cont .nf-form-title h3 {
                                    color:#f8c9c3;
                                            font-size:30px;
                                            margin:10px 0px;
                                                    text-align: center                    }
    </style><style>

        /* FIELDS STYLES */
    
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap {
                                    color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-5_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-10_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-10_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-6_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    border-width:0px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap {
                                    width:100%;
                                            display:block;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-label label {
                                    width:100%;
                                            display:block;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field {
                                    background-color:#31415c;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                                            width:100%;
                                            font-size:18px;
                                            padding:10px;
                    }
        .nf-form-content .nf-field-container #nf-field-8_1-wrap .nf-field-element .ninja-forms-field:hover {
                                    background-color:#162542;
                                            color:#ffffff;
                    }
    </style><div id="nf-form-2_1-cont" class="nf-form-cont" aria-live="polite" aria-labelledby="nf-form-title-2_1" aria-describedby="nf-form-errors-2_1" role="form">

    <div class="nf-loading-spinner"></div>

</div>
        <!-- TODO: Move to Template File. -->
        <script>var formDisplay=1;var nfForms=nfForms||[];var form=[];form.id='2_1';form.settings={"objectType":"Form Setting","editActive":true,"title":"Contact The Lead Agency","key":"","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","default_label_pos":"hidden","conditions":[],"show_title":1,"clear_complete":"1","hide_complete":"1","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","add_submit":"1","logged_in":"","not_logged_in_msg":"","sub_limit_number":"","sub_limit_msg":"","calculations":[],"formContentData":[{"order":1,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["name"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":2,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["contact_number_1491218320211"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":3,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["email"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":4,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["i_need_help_with_1549425070059"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":5,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["recaptcha_1602543056346"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":6,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["hidden_1571292741941"],"width":"100"}]},{"order":7,"cells":[{"order":0,"fields":["speak_to_a_b2b_expert_1508319997306"],"width":"100"}]}],"container_styles_background-color":"#e74c3c","container_styles_border":"","container_styles_border-style":"","container_styles_border-color":"","container_styles_color":"","container_styles_height":"","container_styles_width":"","container_styles_font-size":"","container_styles_margin":"","container_styles_padding":"10px","container_styles_display":"","container_styles_float":"","container_styles_show_advanced_css":1,"container_styles_advanced":"box-shadow: -webkit-box-shadow: 4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);\n-moz-box-shadow:    4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);\nbox-shadow:         4px 4px 0px 0px rgba(150, 150, 150, 0.4);","title_styles_background-color":"","title_styles_border":"","title_styles_border-style":"","title_styles_border-color":"","title_styles_color":"#f8c9c3","title_styles_height":"","title_styles_width":"","title_styles_font-size":"30px","title_styles_margin":"10px 0px","title_styles_padding":"","title_styles_display":"","title_styles_float":"","title_styles_show_advanced_css":1,"title_styles_advanced":"text-align: center","row_styles_background-color":"","row_styles_border":"","row_styles_border-style":"","row_styles_border-color":"","row_styles_color":"","row_styles_height":"","row_styles_width":"","row_styles_font-size":"","row_styles_margin":"","row_styles_padding":"","row_styles_display":"","row_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","row_styles_advanced":"","row-odd_styles_background-color":"","row-odd_styles_border":"","row-odd_styles_border-style":"","row-odd_styles_border-color":"","row-odd_styles_color":"","row-odd_styles_height":"","row-odd_styles_width":"","row-odd_styles_font-size":"","row-odd_styles_margin":"","row-odd_styles_padding":"","row-odd_styles_display":"","row-odd_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","row-odd_styles_advanced":"","success-msg_styles_background-color":"","success-msg_styles_border":"","success-msg_styles_border-style":"","success-msg_styles_border-color":"","success-msg_styles_color":"","success-msg_styles_height":"","success-msg_styles_width":"","success-msg_styles_font-size":"","success-msg_styles_margin":"","success-msg_styles_padding":"","success-msg_styles_display":"","success-msg_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","success-msg_styles_advanced":"","error_msg_styles_background-color":"","error_msg_styles_border":"","error_msg_styles_border-style":"","error_msg_styles_border-color":"","error_msg_styles_color":"","error_msg_styles_height":"","error_msg_styles_width":"","error_msg_styles_font-size":"","error_msg_styles_margin":"","error_msg_styles_padding":"","error_msg_styles_display":"","error_msg_styles_show_advanced_css":"0","error_msg_styles_advanced":"","changeEmailErrorMsg":"Please enter a valid email address!","confirmFieldErrorMsg":"These fields must match!","fieldNumberNumMinError":"Number Min Error","fieldNumberNumMaxError":"Number Max Error","fieldNumberIncrementBy":"Please increment by ","formErrorsCorrectErrors":"Please correct errors before submitting this form.","validateRequiredField":"This is a required field.","honeypotHoneypotError":"Honeypot Error","fieldsMarkedRequired":"Fields marked with an <span class=\"ninja-forms-req-symbol\">*<\/span> are required","currency":"","unique_field_error":"A form with this value has already been submitted.","allow_public_link":0,"embed_form":"","drawerDisabled":false,"ninjaForms":"Ninja Forms","changeDateErrorMsg":"Please enter a valid date!","fieldTextareaRTEInsertLink":"Insert Link","fieldTextareaRTEInsertMedia":"Insert Media","fieldTextareaRTESelectAFile":"Select a file","formHoneypot":"If you are a human seeing this field, please leave it empty.","fileUploadOldCodeFileUploadInProgress":"File Upload in Progress.","fileUploadOldCodeFileUpload":"FILE UPLOAD","currencySymbol":"&#36;","thousands_sep":",","decimal_point":".","siteLocale":"en_AU","dateFormat":"m\/d\/Y","startOfWeek":"1","of":"of","previousMonth":"Previous Month","nextMonth":"Next Month","months":["January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"],"monthsShort":["Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],"weekdays":["Sunday","Monday","Tuesday","Wednesday","Thursday","Friday","Saturday"],"weekdaysShort":["Sun","Mon","Tue","Wed","Thu","Fri","Sat"],"weekdaysMin":["Su","Mo","Tu","We","Th","Fr","Sa"],"currency_symbol":"","beforeForm":"","beforeFields":"","afterFields":"","afterForm":""};form.fields=[{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":1,"label":"Name","key":"name","type":"textbox","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Name","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":"","disable_input":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","disable_browser_autocomplete":"","mask":"","custom_mask":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"#ffffff","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"#ffffff","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"#ffffff","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3466","custom_name_attribute":"","personally_identifiable":"","value":"","id":"5_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["textbox","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":2,"label":"Contact Number","key":"contact_number_1491218320211","type":"textbox","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Contact Number","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":"","disable_input":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","disable_browser_autocomplete":"","mask":"","custom_mask":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"0px","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3470","custom_name_attribute":"","personally_identifiable":"","value":"","id":"10_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["textbox","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":3,"label":"Email","key":"email","type":"email","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"placeholder":"Email","default":"","wrapper_class":"","element_class":"","container_class":"","admin_label":"","help_text":"","desc_text":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"","element_styles_border":"0px","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3473","custom_name_attribute":"email","personally_identifiable":1,"value":"","id":"6_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"email","element_templates":["email","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":4,"label":"I need help with...","type":"textarea","key":"i_need_help_with_1549425070059","label_pos":"hidden","required":1,"default":"","placeholder":"I need help with...","container_class":"","element_class":"","input_limit":"","input_limit_type":"characters","input_limit_msg":"Character(s) left","manual_key":false,"admin_label":"","help_text":"","textarea_rte":"","disable_rte_mobile":"","textarea_media":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"cellcid":"c3476","drawerDisabled":false,"value":"","id":"71_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","parentType":"textarea","element_templates":["textarea","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":5,"label":"Recaptcha","type":"recaptcha","container_class":"","element_class":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"size":"visible","key":"recaptcha_1602543056346","cellcid":"c3731","id":"80_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["recaptcha","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap","site_key":"6LdootYZAAAAAEwDzfbB_4BI4UK8B2U9F1bmQcbQ","theme":"dark","lang":"en"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":6,"label":"Hidden","type":"hidden","key":"hidden_1571292741941","default":"{wp:post_title}","admin_label":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_width":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_border":"","label_styles_width":"","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_border":"","element_styles_width":"","element_styles_font-size":"","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"cellcid":"c3479","drawerDisabled":false,"id":"72_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"hidden","element_templates":["hidden","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap-no-label"},{"objectType":"Field","objectDomain":"fields","editActive":false,"order":7,"label":"SPEAK TO A B2B EXPERT","key":"speak_to_a_b2b_expert_1508319997306","type":"submit","created_at":"2016-08-24 16:39:20","processing_label":"Processing","container_class":"","element_class":"","wrap_styles_background-color":"","wrap_styles_border":"","wrap_styles_border-style":"","wrap_styles_border-color":"","wrap_styles_color":"","wrap_styles_height":"","wrap_styles_width":"100%","wrap_styles_font-size":"","wrap_styles_margin":"","wrap_styles_padding":"","wrap_styles_display":"block","wrap_styles_float":"","wrap_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"wrap_styles_advanced":"","label_styles_background-color":"","label_styles_border":"","label_styles_border-style":"","label_styles_border-color":"","label_styles_color":"","label_styles_height":"","label_styles_width":"100%","label_styles_font-size":"","label_styles_margin":"","label_styles_padding":"","label_styles_display":"block","label_styles_float":"","label_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"label_styles_advanced":"","element_styles_background-color":"#31415c","element_styles_border":"","element_styles_border-style":"","element_styles_border-color":"","element_styles_color":"#ffffff","element_styles_height":"","element_styles_width":"100%","element_styles_font-size":"18px","element_styles_margin":"","element_styles_padding":"10px","element_styles_display":"","element_styles_float":"","element_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"element_styles_advanced":"","submit_element_hover_styles_background-color":"#162542","submit_element_hover_styles_border":"","submit_element_hover_styles_border-style":"","submit_element_hover_styles_border-color":"","submit_element_hover_styles_color":"#ffffff","submit_element_hover_styles_height":"","submit_element_hover_styles_width":"","submit_element_hover_styles_font-size":"","submit_element_hover_styles_margin":"","submit_element_hover_styles_padding":"","submit_element_hover_styles_display":"","submit_element_hover_styles_float":"","submit_element_hover_styles_show_advanced_css":0,"submit_element_hover_styles_advanced":"","cellcid":"c3482","drawerDisabled":false,"id":"8_1","beforeField":"","afterField":"","value":"","label_pos":"hidden","parentType":"textbox","element_templates":["submit","button","input"],"old_classname":"","wrap_template":"wrap-no-label"}];nfForms.push(form);</script>
                <script id="nf-tmpl-cell" type="text/template">
            <nf-fields></nf-fields>
        </script>

        <script id="nf-tmpl-row" type="text/template">
            <nf-cells></nf-cells>
        </script>

        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/six-steps-account-based-marketing/">The 6 Steps of Account Based Marketing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">The Lead Agency</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
